<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Home - Living at 300Main Downtown Winnipeg - apartments-in-downtown</title>
	<subtitle>We all love 300Main</subtitle>
	<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/apartments-in-downtown/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2019-11-21T21:41:11+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/apartments-in-downtown/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Bigger is Greener: The Environmental Benefits of High-Density Housing</title>
		<published>2019-11-21T21:41:11+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-11-21T21:41:11+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/bigger-is-greener-the-environmental-benefits-of-high-density-housing/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/bigger-is-greener-the-environmental-benefits-of-high-density-housing/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Canadians are increasingly &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.macleans.ca&#x2F;news&#x2F;canada&#x2F;census-2016-a-picture-of-a-bigger-more-urban-canada&#x2F;&quot;&gt;living in cities&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;canadapopulation.org&#x2F;winnipeg-population&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Winnipeg is no exception&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It can sometimes be hard for communities with fast-growing populations to keep up with the infrastructure needs for new residents. That’s why many cities are gravitating towards more high-density housing as part of their “&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.smartcitiesdive.com&#x2F;ex&#x2F;sustainablecitiescollective&#x2F;urban-density-and-sustainability&#x2F;241696&#x2F;&quot;&gt;smart growth&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;” strategies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is High-Density Housing?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
High-density housing simply is housing that packs more people per geographic unit. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;300 Main&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a 40-storey apartment building that will be home to several hundred city dwellers. Communities that are urbanizing sometimes encourage developers to add higher-density complexes to their downtown areas. There are many advantages to these tall multiplexes.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_6065&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;1024&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-6065&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;Final_C2-1024x775.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Apartment Buildings, Apartments in Winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;775&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; 3D Rendering of 300 Main[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Higher-density neighbourhoods have a strong sense of community and connectedness because people are just in closer contact with each other. High-density housing usually entails high-rise buildings such as 300 Main. Higher population density is essential for &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.huffingtonpost.ca&#x2F;ypnexthome&#x2F;high-density-housing-gta_b_17208346.html&quot;&gt;developing busy, vivacious neighbourhoods&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with lots of features. It allows for beautiful public spaces like downtown Winnipeg to make life convenient, enjoyable and, most importantly, green!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sustainable Design&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
As cities &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;canada.constructconnect.com&#x2F;dcn&#x2F;news&#x2F;economic&#x2F;2019&#x2F;04&#x2F;canadas-major-cities-ride-slipstream-surging-population-growth&quot;&gt;boom in population&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and invest to meet the needs of their new citizens, sustainability has also become a major focus. High-rise apartments are one of the easiest ways to make a community more sustainable. They have a smaller footprint than that of many smaller buildings.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_6069&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;680&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-6069&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;apartment-architectural-design-architecture-bridge-1152849-3-680x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Apartment Buildings, Apartments in Winnipeg, Chicago, High Rise Buildings in Chicago, High Rise Apartments in Chicago&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt; Chicago, United States by Cameron Casey from Pexels[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If neighbourhoods want to continue to grow, all they need to do is look up! Building up, or even on top of, is &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.citylab.com&#x2F;equity&#x2F;2012&#x2F;01&#x2F;why-most-environmental-building-building-weve-already-built&#x2F;1016&#x2F;&quot;&gt;more environmentally-friendly&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; than conventional demolished-site redevelopment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Size Matters (For Energy)&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Denser neighbourhoods that include apartment blocks or condos also use less energy. Residences that are stacked or bunched should &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ottawacitizen.com&#x2F;life&#x2F;homes&#x2F;modern-housing-why-highrises-are-good-for-the-environment&quot;&gt;use less energy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. For example, an apartment suite in 300 Main is more efficient to heat and cool than a detached suburban house. So even on cold winter nights (which us Winnipeggers know sometimes start in October), if every apartment suite were to turn their heat up, they’d be using less energy than the equivalent number of houses. Higher-density neighbourhoods also &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cbsnews.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;trying-to-reduce-your-carbon-footprint-dont-fall-for-these-myths&#x2F;&quot;&gt;create fewer harmful emissions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. As &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.citylab.com&#x2F;life&#x2F;2012&#x2F;04&#x2F;why-bigger-cities-are-greener&#x2F;863&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Richard Florida at CityLab&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; says, “When it comes to greenness, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;martinprosperity.org&#x2F;insights&#x2F;insight&#x2F;cities-and-co2-bigger-is-better&quot;&gt;size matters&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.”
&lt;h3&gt;Encourages more Walking, Cycling and Use of Public Transportation&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Though downtown areas can seem busy, there are major benefits to living and working downtown. Dense downtown neighbourhoods help residents drive less and walk more, without giving up their lifestyles. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.fastcompany.com&#x2F;40492045&#x2F;living-in-a-dense-city-makes-citizens-healthier&quot;&gt;Research&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has shown that lower density promotes sedentary behavior. If your home is far away from the grocery store and your office, you’re going to spend more time in a car and less time being active.
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;getting-around-winnipeg-without-a-car-yes-its-possible&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High-density housing encourages walking and cycling &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cbsnews.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;trying-to-reduce-your-carbon-footprint-dont-fall-for-these-myths&#x2F;&quot;&gt;because everything is closer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; together! Transit is also promoted by high-density housing, as transit connections become more common when neighborhood density increases. Many city dwellers find it more convenient to jump on a transit bus and be at work in a stress-free jiffy, rather than drive to work, deal with traffic, and find parking. Talk about a headache!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individuals who live in suburban areas can also benefit from people taking transit to work. Fewer cars on the road equal fewer harmful emissions, like carbon dioxide.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What’s Big, Green, and Sustainable?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
High-density housing is a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theguardian.com&#x2F;environment&#x2F;georgemonbiot&#x2F;2011&#x2F;jun&#x2F;30&#x2F;sustainable-cities-urban-planning&quot;&gt;sustainable choice&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for growing cities. Tall buildings are more than just towers of concrete and steel; they’re a fundamental part of successful urbanization. They offer a greener, less wasteful, and more energy-efficient way of life.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_6072&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;954&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-6072&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;vehicles-on-road-between-high-rise-buildings-1525612-954x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Apartment Buildings, Apartments in Winnipeg, New York, New York Apartment Buildings&quot; width=&quot;954&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt; New York, United States by Craig Adderley from Pexels[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Developing your Timeless Style</title>
		<published>2019-11-15T22:09:44+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-11-15T22:09:44+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/developing-your-timeless-style/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/developing-your-timeless-style/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every time I hear the word “timeless” in relation to fashion or home décor, I feel so much hope. This piece of furniture or pair of shoes will last, will indeed be timeless.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my living room stands a small, mustard-yellow, mid-century sofa. Was this style of sofa fashionable in the 1950s? Absolutely. Is it fashionable today? Certainly. Will it be fashionable in twenty years? I dare say so. Having those three definite answers in mind helped me decide to buy that piece of furniture. Asking if it was timeless helped even more when my subconscious decided I would enjoy this sofa for the next twenty years.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-6036&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;inside-weather-Ijk3UP9uRhk-unsplash-2-1024x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Timeless decor, home decor, apartment decor, classic decor, modern decor, redecorating, furniture, buying, apartment style&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some things might be considered fundamentals of timeless fashion, but what’s timeless for each of us might be different. What we decide to call &lt;em&gt;lasting&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;classic&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; depends on our ideas of current and vintage trends. It comes from our backgrounds, preferences, and our feelings.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might call my yellow sofa timeless, but it might not be something you want to see in your living room every day for the next twenty years. I know why the tweed Chanel suit is considered beautiful and timeless, but it’s just not for me. When it comes to home décor, the same rules apply; each piece of furniture should suit your vision and your lifestyle.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of such a talky introduction was only to get us thinking about and appreciating the things we own. In a fast-paced world full of issues such as climate change, plastic and fast-fashion production, we ought to pay attention to the quality and durability of our clothes and furniture. Building a wardrobe and home centered on timeless pieces will make a positive difference to both your life and the environment. Let’s look at the process of searching for décor that will last.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Stay away from clichés&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
A home that evokes sighs of admiration with its timeless style wasn&#x27;t decorated in a week. Everything that deserves attention, anything that will last, takes time, love and effort to find. I’m not trying to judge Costco or IKEA. However, I tend to believe in other, more sophisticated and exciting ways of discovering your home essentials.
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-6038&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;ikea-building-1797405-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Timeless decor, home decor, apartment decor, classic decor, modern decor, redecorating, furniture, buying, apartment style, ikea&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current trends, which tell us to live more organically and embrace slow-fashion and slow-living, affect our ideas about the right way to shop. There are many ways to avoid mass-produced pieces of furniture to find something that will add character to your place that you’ll treasure and enjoy using.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Visit flea markets and antique stores, like &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;antiquesandfunk.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Antiques &amp;amp; Funk&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;thejohnstonterminal.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Johnston Terminal Antique Mall&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Honestly, what compares to the thrill of finding a chair in Louis XIV style, or a set of old chandeliers to make each dinner and party you host sparkle?&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;thejohnstonterminal.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-6040 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;Johnston-Terminal-1024x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Timeless decor, home decor, apartment decor, classic decor, modern decor, redecorating, furniture, buying, apartment style, antique store, johnston terminal&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;576&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Try local furniture boutiques. When people hear the word “boutique,” they tend to imagine high-end pieces with high-end prices. But you’d be surprised by the quality you can find at affordable prices My yellow couch, for example, cost just under $600, and the quality and the style are tremendous!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Frequent local marketplaces that feature artists and makers. These markets, like &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alleywaysmarket.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Alleyways Market&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;thirdandbirdevents.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Third + Bird&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, can be found throughout the year in Winnipeg. Many artists will have examples at their booths that can be pre-ordered or purchased on the spot. I’ve found beautiful wooden side tables, kitchen items made from olive wood, and handmade woven baskets that are great for décor and storage.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;thirdandbirdevents.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-6042&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;https___cdn.evbuc_.com_images_78161255_101463824605_1_original.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;third + bird&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Go treasure hunting at thrift stores and second-hand places. Sure, sometimes you’ll leave empty-handed, but you might also leave with pieces that will suit your style and serve you loyally. Search thrift stores for small details like a magazine stand, books, candelabras or even seasonal decorations. You’ll find unique pieces while doing your part for the environment by reusing, recycling, and restyling.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. Add culture to your place&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
My great-grandmother was &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Ruska_Roma&quot;&gt;Ruska Roma&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Learning this explained a lot about my preferences. Every time I promised myself that I would keep my house minimalistic, and style it simply with bohemian pieces, I would find something a colourful carpet, golden candle holder, or velvet pillow I couldn’t resist.
&lt;p&gt;Don’t let a fear of being different blind you. Don’t force yourself to follow trends and clichés if you feel no connection to it. I’m not saying to surround yourself with only appropriate cultural pieces. You don’t want your home to be a museum; you want it to be your home that reflects who you are and feels comfortable and warm. Add culture by mixing in art pieces (maybe something you picked up while travelling) with modern furniture for a timeless look.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-6045&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;ana-juma-bX-N-0sz8gg-unsplash-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Timeless decor, home decor, apartment decor, classic decor, modern decor, redecorating, furniture, buying, apartment style, antique store, bohemian&quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a room where the main pieces, like the sofa, chairs, and table, are simple, but the room feels full of character. Look closer, and you will notice more than basic furniture. Is that a rug from India? Are there French impressionist paintings? Photographs? Are there handmade vases from Poland? Discover what your culture is about and sprinkle it throughout your home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Let the basics be timeless&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
I’ve said it before, and I’ll say it again: everyone has their own interpretation of what makes something timeless. However, there are some standard rules for choosing timeless pieces.
&lt;p&gt;Allow bigger pieces such as sofas, dining tables, kitchen cabinets, and your bed to be timeless. The same rules that apply in fashion apply to interior design: keep your essential wardrobe and basic furniture functional and timeless. Then, add trendy or cultural notes to it seasonally.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-6046&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;samantha-gades-BlIhVfXbi9s-unsplash-1024x684.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Timeless decor, home decor, apartment decor, classic decor, modern decor, redecorating, furniture, buying, apartment style&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;684&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Timeless furniture makes a functional base but doesn&#x27;t have to be boring. Research the epoch you find the most delightful or interesting and be inspired by its designs. Pay attention to descriptions such as “retro”, “mid-century” and “contemporary”; you might even keep an eye out for “Victorian” if you like a bit of pomp. Use these pieces fearlessly as your basics.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If cultural or trendy decorative details suit your personality, then timeless furniture is your neutral base. The more timeless and essential your main furniture is, the longer it will stay with you. You merely won&#x27;t get tired of its appearance and presence.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advice that helped me: start a mood board (physical or just on Pinterest) and do your research. Collect ideas for timeless (but not dull and boring!) interior design pieces. Then, enjoy the slow thrill of the furniture hunt at antique stores, little unknown shops. Search Instagram for artists and handcrafters; you might find unique dish sets, side tables, pillows and baskets. When you’re finished, your home will be more than just a shelter. It will be full of useful, uncommon pieces that have a story behind them; pieces that serve you and express your individuality. And that’s truly timeless.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your favourite places for finding unique, lasting pieces of furniture? Leave your tips in the comments!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>No Nail Holes: Decorating Your New Apartment</title>
		<published>2019-09-10T21:29:09+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-09-10T21:29:09+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/no-nail-holes-decorating-your-new-apartment/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/no-nail-holes-decorating-your-new-apartment/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;To your right: an empty wall. To your left—another one. You’re surrounded by large, blank walls. The walls of your new apartment are the bones of the space that you have decided works best for you. Now that you’ve moved in, they need some attention to personalize your new home and make it truly yours.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to sound corny, but those empty walls are a canvas—a beautiful, clean canvas that gives you an opportunity to express yourself. But you want to do it without putting holes in them. To get you started, here are three tips on how to showcase your personality when decorating your new apartment—without risking your security deposit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;small-space-design-ideas&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Wall Pops&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
According to Winnipeg interior designer Kelly Porath, of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.blueroseinteriors.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Blue Rose Interiors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wallpops.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Wall Pops&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are very on-trend. Removable decals that are relatively &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wallpops.com&#x2F;how-to-hang-peel-and-stick-wallpaper&quot;&gt;easy to install and remove&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Wall Pops are definitely not the wallpaper of old. Whether you’re inspired by simplicity or drawn to the big and bold, there are plenty of options to highlight and define your space.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-pin-do=&quot;embedPin&quot; data-pin-width=&quot;large&quot; data-pin-terse=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.pinterest.com&#x2F;pin&#x2F;636485359817214732&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Textiles&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
More than just window dressings, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;society6.com&#x2F;tapestries&quot;&gt;textiles&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; can add colour, design and texture to any space. Consider blankets and woven pieces that mean something to you or speak to your personality. Whether they were handmade by a family member or discovered while shopping at a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;mulveymarket.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;local market&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, textiles can add warmth and character.
&lt;h3&gt;Command products by 3M&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Command hooks and strips allow you to hang everything from your favourite art work and photos to travel memorabilia. These nifty products are designed to work on a variety of surfaces and come in different sizes. Follow the product specifications and be careful to choose the right strength strip or hook for your art. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.command.com&#x2F;3M&#x2F;en_US&#x2F;command&#x2F;how-to-use&#x2F;all-other-hooks&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Detailed instructions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on how to use them are available online.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-pin-do=&quot;embedPin&quot; data-pin-width=&quot;medium&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.pinterest.com&#x2F;pin&#x2F;333899759859867789&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Resources&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
For more information, check out these resources:
&lt;ul&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wallpops.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Wallpops.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; offers peel-and-stick wall decals, wallpaper, and floor tiles&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;society6.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Society6.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is an international marketplace and community for artists&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.command.com&#x2F;3M&#x2F;en_CA&#x2F;command-ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Command.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has products for hanging everything, including art, purses and brooms&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Home decor retailers such as &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wayfair.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;wayfair.ca&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and HomeSense have great bargains&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Home improvement stores like Home Depot, Loews and Canadian Tire have décor and storage items&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
Thank you to Kelly Porath of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.blueroseinteriors.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Blue Rose Interiors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for sharing her tips and tricks with us. Kelly’s final words of advice: “Make your art count.”
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What would your advice be to someone decorating a new apartment?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&quot;&#x2F;&#x2F;assets.pinterest.com&#x2F;js&#x2F;pinit.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
