<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Home - Living at 300Main Downtown Winnipeg - 300-main</title>
	<subtitle>We all love 300Main</subtitle>
	<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/category/300-main/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-03-03T19:02:46+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/category/300-main/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Benefits of Living in a Central Location</title>
		<published>2022-03-03T19:02:46+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-03T19:02:46+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/benefits-of-living-in-a-central-location/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/benefits-of-living-in-a-central-location/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7473,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;office-worker-active-and-healthy-lifestyle-in-urb-2021-09-02-07-21-01-utc-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7473&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people believe that downtown living is about rigid, concrete walls and tall buildings. But what many don&#x27;t realize are the benefits of living in a central area - from exceptional dining options to entertainment venues.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all its perks on offer, you&#x27;ll find yourself immersed in the culture, easy access to green areas, and all the convenience of living by retail and services. This article will explain why being near these things can be amazing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location, location, location&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downtown living is a great way to be in the center of everything and to enjoy all the stores and restaurants available in the area. Life is way more convenient when you can walk to the grocery store, drug mart, dry cleaner, and many other services.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7470,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;manicure-care-procedure-woman-in-a-nail-salon-rec-2021-08-26-17-33-25-utc-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7470&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, imagine living above a fitness facility like GoodLife, two restaurants, and a beauty salon. Sounds incredible, right?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new development in Downtown Winnipeg, 300 Main, has a dining and entertaining experience never seen in residential buildings in Winnipeg. Convenient and luxurious, the building&#x27;s primary goal is to simplify the lifestyle of residents.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7467,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;melbourne-cocktails-2021-08-29-11-21-46-utc-1-1024x768.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7467&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you planning a romantic date? Look no further! Earl&#x27;s restaurant at 300 Main is a perfect option. Choose between an elegant dining room with breathtaking decor or enjoy drinks in the charming lounge, and your date will be indeed impressed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those mornings that you just want to relax and recharge, you can enjoy a fabulous brunch at OEB Breakfast followed by a beauty session at Ninety-Five Beauty, all of it at the same address.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upscale Living&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the ground, cities are vibrant and lively. But from up high, you can see all their gears working in perfect balance, like one big clockwork machine!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skyscrapers like 300 Main provide that much-needed comfort whenever necessary and, of course, the perfect glimpse of Winnipeg—with a city view that never disappoints.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7468,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;woman-talking-on-the-phone-and-looking-at-window-2021-08-26-18-19-36-utc-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7468&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From your apartment&#x27;s balcony, you can see the architectural icon Human Rights Museum, The Forks - where families enjoy the warmer and colder times - and, of course, celebrate the gorgeous yet peaceful sunset time framing the beautiful red river.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sense that there is so much more out in this world than what meets the eyes can be found at 300 Main, located in a central location, where you can enjoy the best starry sky view while having fun with your friends at the Forty tenant lounge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be car-free&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, it&#x27;s easy to complain about the traffic in a big city like Winnipeg. But living in a central area means never having any problems with getting around since everything, including dining options, is within walking distance from your home base. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7469,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;rental-bycicles-terminal-mockup-2021-09-03-04-16-08-utc-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7469&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living Downtown also means that you can benefit from biking, walking, or public transportation. And it&#x27;s not just for the environment. It provides an efficient alternative to driving, whether it can help alleviate concerns about parking or digging your car out in wintertime while saving money on gas prices! Let&#x27;s not forget that biking and walking also promote healthy living by getting some daily body movement.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host with the most&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who live Downtown often forget how much their residences appeal to friends and family members who want quick access into the city. Rather than lamenting another trip out into sleepy suburbs, your friends and family will be waiting with excited anticipation for your next visit!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7472,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;dinner-with-friends-group-of-young-people-enjoyin-2021-10-21-03-07-24-utc-1024x614.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7472&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city is your oyster. You have endless opportunities to show them your favorite dining places and the new corners of the beautiful city you love, from scenic parks like the Forks and amazing views from 300 Main into world-famous museums or sporting events!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life Downtown lets people live a comfortable life without ever getting bored because there&#x27;s always something going on around every corner of the neighborhood.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access Parks and Community gardens&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does a desirable living look like? One possibility is green areas and parks that contrast sharply with many people&#x27;s image for city life. Winnipeg, Manitoba&#x27;s most populated metropolitan area, offers a great example: we have more than enough space to enjoy nature while still being close by.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7471,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;walking-in-the-park-2021-08-27-10-10-05-utc-1024x684.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7471&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winnipeg is a city of green spaces. Approximately 7% of 47,570 ha of the entire city area is parkland. In 2021 Winnipeggers enjoyed 30 new trails in parks for skiing, walking, and fat-biking, 13 dog parks, and 49 community gardens.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&#x27;s more, it&#x27;s not simply the presence of a park or two but an entire system with open fields for sports and tree-covered benches to lounge upon. There are swings and monkey bars available so you can enjoy your time outside in style!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Perks of Heated Parking</title>
		<published>2019-10-04T18:32:58+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-10-04T18:32:58+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/perks-of-heated-parking/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/perks-of-heated-parking/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Heated underground parking might seem like a luxury, but in Winnipeg it’s downright life-changing. I hate to even say the dreaded w word yet, but there are many perks to underground heated parking—especially during Winnipeg’s harsh winters! Here are some of the best reasons to look for parking underground.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;No More Morning Duties&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
If you are like me and value your sleep, a giant perk of heated underground parking is that you save major time in the morning. Instead of waking up twenty minutes earlier to bundle up, trudge outside, and work up a sweat clearing inches of snow and ice off your car, only to then wait another miserable ten minutes for your car to warm up, you can be in bed hitting your snooze button for the third time. With heated underground parking, you don’t have to spend half of your day preparing your car for departure, you just hop in and go!
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_5887&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;819&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-5887&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;10&#x2F;ian-keefe-kJ74b4gK-Wc-unsplash-819x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Heated Parking, Parkade, Underground Parkade, Winnipeg Square Parkade, 300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, snowy road, winter street&quot; width=&quot;819&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt; Photo by Ian Keefe from Unsplash[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll also have somewhere to plug in your car, guaranteeing it will start on those extra toe-numbing days that always come around in January. A warm underground parking spot will also protect your wheels from the elements, so it won’t be 100% dependent on being plugged in.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Keeping Your Car Clean&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Winnipeg roads are the epitome of dirty—especially on groggy winter days when it’s almost impossible not to drive into a pothole full of brown slush. Sometimes, you just want to make your car all spiffy but fear the mix of the leftover water and Winnipeg’s frigid days. But if you’re headed back to your cozy, underground heated parking spot afterwards, you can scrub your car without a care in the world. Plus, underground parking ensures you’ll be taking fewer trips to the carwash by avoiding those extra splashes of dirt your car would receive parked on the street.
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-5890&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;10&#x2F;car-3266965_1920-1024x680.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Heated Parking, Parkade, Underground Parkade, Winnipeg Square Parkade, 300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, snowy road, winter street, slushy winter, muddy car&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;680&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Keeping Your Car Safe&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Your car is less likely to be dinged or damaged by passing cars when it’s parked safely underground. And if you do have the misfortune of receiving a ding from a car door or a smashed bumper, most underground parking lots have security cameras. So if the offending driver didn’t leave a note, you might be able to find out how it happened. Underground parking also helps protects you from those always ill-timed street parking break-ins.
&lt;h3&gt;No More Parking Tickets&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
“Be right back, I need to go move my car!”
&lt;p&gt;Sound familiar? Underground parking also saves you from getting a parking ticket (or three). Many underground parking lots have you pick up a ticket when you enter and pay for your time when you leave. So no rushing to move your car each hour, or leaving your dinner date to go plug more quarters into the meter. If you have the option of including parking in your rent, that’s even more convenient!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: none; overflow: hidden;&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;plugins&#x2F;post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FWinnipegMomOnline%2Fposts%2F1878140362231098&amp;amp;width=500&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;632&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Save Big on Time and Energy&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Downtown Winnipeg is known for having limited parking on their streets, especially during the 9 to 5 on workdays. Parking underground may seem like a luxury, but it will save you time and energy every time you don’t need to circle the block looking for somewhere to park.</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Downtown Living with Susan Ainley</title>
		<published>2019-07-10T14:37:02+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-07-10T14:37:02+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/downtown-living-with-susan-ainley/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/downtown-living-with-susan-ainley/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;embed&#x2F;_WtGqd79km4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We invited Susan Ainley (also known as &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;broken_down_chevy&#x2F;&quot;&gt;@broken_down_chevy on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) to come and tell us a story of her experience living in downtown Winnipeg! She talked about how long she&#x27;s been living in downtown, why she chose to rent, and the things she enjoy most living in downtown.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We love hearing personal stories of  downtown living. Do you have your own that you want to share with us?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>300 Main, Where the Future of Winnipeg Wants to Be</title>
		<published>2019-06-20T10:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-06-20T10:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/300-main-where-the-future-of-winnipeg-wants-to-be/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/300-main-where-the-future-of-winnipeg-wants-to-be/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Not only is downtown Winnipeg—home of arguably the best restaurants, historical architecture, and free live entertainment in the city—the future of Winnipeg and its economy, soon it will be home to the people that will help create that future!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve lived all over Winnipeg with over 30 moves, and I&#x27;ve experienced most of the lifestyles our city has to offer. Quite honestly, downtown is the only neighbourhood that really captures the magic of Winnipeg while sidestepping any of the inconveniences, and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;300 Main&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; snagged the perfect spot.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Winnipeg: Chicago of the North!&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
By now we’re all familiar with Winnipeg’s claim to fame but unfortunately, people are starting to wonder if that’s still relevant. I&#x27;m here to tell you why that reputation is more relevant than ever, and why you want to be at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;300 Main&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the building to kick it all off!
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: none; margin: 10px 0 0 0; overflow: hidden;&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;plugins&#x2F;post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2F300MainWinnipeg%2Fposts%2F1415526985256497&amp;amp;width=500&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;611&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;Chicago is a little bit ahead of us architecturally, aren’t they? The good news is, Winnipeg’s architects seem eager to catch up—and quick. The city’s center is rapidly expanding, and Winnipeggers are determined to show their southern sister that the cold doesn’t slow us down!
&lt;p&gt;You just can&#x27;t beat the convenience of living at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;300 Main&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, right at the underground mall that connects all the way down to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;portageplace.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Portage Place&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; via the skywalk system. You’ll never have to bear that true north wind, from your apartment door to your seat for the game at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bellmtsplace.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;BellMTS Place&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Just steps away, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cityplacewinnipeg.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;City Place&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is full of food, convenience stores, a liquor mart, and an indoor farmers market; it even connects to Winnipeg&#x27;s famous &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.sharkclub.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Shark Club&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for an affordable lunch special and maybe the occasional hand of cards between laundry flips.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if the skywalk system to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;portageplace.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Portage Place Mall&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; isn’t long enough, almost every main bus route in the city connects within a block from your front door. With all of Winnipeg&#x27;s top lounges and patios as your neighbors, you&#x27;ll never miss happy hour (or pay for parking) again!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;True North Strong &amp;amp; Your Neighbor&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
I noticed that in Chicago, the people who work downtown live in luxury high-rises nearby. As a tourist, I felt that it created a very safe environment and an exciting downtown nightlife. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.truenorthsquare.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;True North Square&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; will add yet another element to downtown’s exciting energy.
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: none; margin: 10px 0 0 0; overflow: hidden;&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;plugins&#x2F;post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Ftruenorthsquare%2Fposts%2F982376771934575&amp;amp;width=500&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;688&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;Think of it as a (new) central park for Winnipeg. Set to be 2 acres, with retail, restaurants, and a stage for live entertainment, no matter what you like doing, or who you&#x27;ll be there with, there will be something for everyone!
&lt;h3&gt;The sky’s the limit&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
But there&#x27;s one last reason why I and many others are particularly excited about &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;300 Main&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;; it&#x27;s really going to shake things up for our city! Coming in at 42 stories, it&#x27;ll be Winnipeg&#x27;s tallest building and I’m sure the city will soar just as high.
&lt;p&gt;With construction of Winnipeg’s most anticipated accommodations underway at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;300 Main&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, downtown is where the future of the city is literally being built. I believe that &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;300 Main&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is bringing culture and condos together, and I can’t wait to see what the future looks like in downtown Winnipeg.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Six Reasons Why Renting is the Smart Move for Millennials</title>
		<published>2019-03-28T11:00:20+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-03-28T11:00:20+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/six-reasons-why-renting-is-the-smart-move-for-millennials/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/six-reasons-why-renting-is-the-smart-move-for-millennials/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are few decisions in life as important as your first home. And with the housing market rising, everyone seems to have advice about this decision. Millennials who are moving to bigger cities feel the pressure to get into the market. They’re told that buying is the smart move, and renting is just throwing away money. But is it? I took a look at the numbers and found six reasons why renting for Millennials is sometimes the best option.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;“You build equity when you buy a house”&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
This statement is&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;affordanything.com&#x2F;is-renting-better-than-buying-should-i-rent-or-buy&#x2F;&quot;&gt; frequently used as an argument against renting&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The tenant rents for years and the landlord makes a profit, when the tenant could be using that money to save for a down payment or paying off a mortgage. On a basic level this is true, but it overstates the idea of gaining &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.investopedia.com&#x2F;terms&#x2F;e&#x2F;equity.asp&quot;&gt;equity&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from owning a property. Most 30-year mortgages build very little equity over the first 20 years, and only start building equity in the last decade. Most of your mortgage payment in the first two-thirds of time that you own a property is going towards insurance, taxes, and the organization that gave you the mortgage. Unless you’re very sure you are going to live in this house for the next 30 years, you’ll build minimal equity.
&lt;p&gt;House values also tend to increase with inflation. There have been very few periods in the last 100 years when house prices have risen beyond inflation, and when they did, they eventually declined when the “bubble burst.” When a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.investopedia.com&#x2F;terms&#x2F;h&#x2F;housing_bubble.asp&quot;&gt;housing bubble&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; bursts, the market value of your home quickly declines—but your mortgage debt doesn’t. Unless you get lucky and buy the right property at the exact right time in the right location, the chance of your house value rising by significantly more than the rate of inflation is minimal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Being tied to a place for an allotted time&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Millennials are lucky to have started our careers at a time dominated by technology. Many people have the freedom to work remotely from their computer. This freedom does not mesh well with a mortgage payment, which only sees equity growth in its later years. The economy is changing, and Millennials tend to go back to school or switch careers more often than baby boomers, but there’s little incentive for us to tie ourselves down to a 30-year mortgage until we know we’ll be staying in one place for a long time. Renting allows Millennials the freedom to spend money on travel, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.forbes.com&#x2F;sites&#x2F;petesaunders1&#x2F;2017&#x2F;01&#x2F;12&#x2F;where-educated-millennials-are-moving&#x2F;#f706ec0d3ccc&quot;&gt;starting a business&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, or paying off student debt, rather than having money tied down in a place where you aren’t sure you will want to live for the next three decades.
&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-3672 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;03&#x2F;thought-catalog-641073-unsplash-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Millenials, renting, buying a house, Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Winnipeg, Downtown Apartments, 300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;There are better ways to grow your wealth&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Not only are the gains of equity from buying a house in some ways overstated, but if investment is your goal, there are more profitable ways to go about it. Renting can save you a lot of money on your yearly spending, and that money can be used to invest in stocks, ETF’s, Index Mutual funds, RRSP’s and other investment strategies that have a higher overall gain. As mentioned above, house prices tend to increase alongside inflation. Adjusting for that, a house in 1897 cost the same as a house in 1997. As for investing, The Financial Planning Standards Council &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.tangerine.ca&#x2F;forwardthinking&#x2F;investing&#x2F;what-is-a-realistic-rate-of-return-on-an-investment-portfolio&quot;&gt;states that&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, “Return assumptions for a balanced portfolio range from 4.55%…to 6.05%.” Therefore, investing in stocks and bonds with the cash you’ve saved from renting is a more profitable option. The money you gain over years can be used to buy a home in a city that you know you’ll stay in.
&lt;h3&gt;Peace of mind&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
The &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.investopedia.com&#x2F;financial-edge&#x2F;1112&#x2F;reasons-renting-is-better-than-buying.aspx&quot;&gt;lack of stress about maintenance or repair fees is a major perk of renting&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as well, as the landlord or building manager responsible for these. This removes a major source of worry from your life as a renter, since you don’t have to think about replacing the furnace or the pipes if they break or hiring someone to check problems in your house. I know many homeowners who are frustrated with the amount of work they have to do just to maintain their living space. Renovations and repairs can be a huge drain, both financially and of your time. Renting allows you to spend your free time enjoying your home, not just keeping it in order.
&lt;p&gt;Another way renting removes stress is that you don’t have to worry about fluctuating markets and property taxes. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.gov.mb.ca&#x2F;cca&#x2F;rtb&#x2F;rentincreaseguideline&#x2F;calculate.html&quot;&gt;In Manitoba, the most rent can increase is 1% and 3% each year (with some exceptions)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which many renters can manage. Property taxes, on the other hand, can rise by more, and the value of your home can swing wildly without you having any ability to budget for it. Knowing how much you are paying at the beginning of every month is a big stress reliever for Millennials, who often freelance and work jobs that are more fluid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Amenities and extras&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Not a lot of people have a pool, a gym, a party room, or a tennis court in their house. But with a lot of newer condominiums, these are built in! These facilities are right in the building and make exercise and social gatherings easy and affordable, which is important in our society where we all seem to be so busy. These amenities would normally require Millennials to pay a membership to a gym or club, plus transportation costs. With many buildings having these amenities built in, it saves renters both money and time. Not to mention the cost of having these perks in your home as an owner would vastly outweigh what renters spend for building fees in a year!
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_3674&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;1024&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-3674&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;03&#x2F;humphrey-muleba-1119283-unsplash-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Amenities, Gym, 300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Winnipeg, Winnipeg Apartments&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; &#x2F;&gt; ? by Humphrey Muleba from Unsplash[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another benefit with renting a condo or apartment is that you are surrounded by a built-in community. Many of my good friends are people who rented beside me, went to the dog park at my building or who I just bumped into in my neighbourhood at some point. You’re surrounded by hundreds of neighbours in an apartment building, which can come in handy when you need someone to watch your dog for a day, borrow a drill for a project, or just want to get together with some new friends.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;It is the best option&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;business.financialpost.com&#x2F;personal-finance&#x2F;young-money&#x2F;student-debt-the-crippling-side-effect-of-education&quot;&gt;rising student debt&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cbc.ca&#x2F;news&#x2F;business&#x2F;house-prices-affordability-income-1.4966211&quot;&gt;tough housing market&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, many Millennials have no choice but to move back in with their parents after going to college or university. In these cases, for a young professional looking to live on their own, renting is a better option. The freedom of living on your own without the stress of the housing market allows Millennials to get closer to their dreams while saving up money and building a life.
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cnbc.com&#x2F;2018&#x2F;09&#x2F;05&#x2F;its-better-to-rent-than-to-buy-in-todays-housing-market.html&quot;&gt;new research&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from Florida Atlantic University and Florida International University Faculty, “Renting and reinvesting the savings from renting, on average, will outperform owning and building home equity, in terms of wealth creation,” which can allow younger people to live the life they want. Traveling, being in a city, having a safe home, and chasing your career: all of this is possible and more attainable while renting. Renting isn’t throwing away money; you get to live in a place with all the amenities of owning a home, without any of the costs of upkeep! Don’t let old advice keep you from living your dream.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have you chosen to rent? Are you a happy homeowner? Tell us why that choice was right for you in the comments!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Finding the One: Choosing an Apartment in Winnipeg</title>
		<published>2019-02-07T11:00:16+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-02-07T11:00:16+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/finding-the-one-choosing-an-apartment-in-winnipeg/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/finding-the-one-choosing-an-apartment-in-winnipeg/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finding a new space to call home is an undertaking that can require serious time and energy. But apartment hunting can also be fun and exhilarating! With a bit of planning, you can avoid a headache and find a home you’re ready to commit to—at least until the lease is up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Scope out the Neighbourhood&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
Your neighbourhood has an enormous influence on your life, and there are a few very important things to consider when picking your perfect downtown neighbourhood.
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you research what sort of neighbourhood you seek to best fit your lifestyle. For example, if you like being in the center of everything, consider streets in the core of downtown Winnipeg. Streets like Graham, Garry and some areas of Portage Avenue are a five-minute walk from popular bars, restaurants and Bell MTS Place.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for somewhere more cosmopolitan, right in the middle of a richly varied area—the Exchange District may be your perfect match! This vibrant neighbourhood boasts many of Winnipeg’s one-of-a-kind boutiques, coffee shops, bars and restaurants. Also, it’s near the Centennial Concert Hall and Winnipeg’s own China Town.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BtNESe3AwDL&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BtNESe3AwDL&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;A post shared by @andrewmahon&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot;font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-01-29T03:56:35+00:00&quot;&gt;Jan 28, 2019 at 7:56pm PST&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in a more laid-back neighbourhood that’s still close to entertainment, check out West Broadway. It’s known for being an unofficial boundary between the hustle bustle commercial parts of downtown and the residential areas, so you get the best of both worlds. Backing onto the Assiniboine River, it’s a picturesque area with elm tree canopies over streets and beautiful historic buildings.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do some extra exploring around the area to make sure it has your must-haves for a neighbourhood. Keep an eye out for nearby grocery stores, drugstores, and bus stops.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When walking around the streets outside a potential apartment, do you feel at home? Can you picture yourself showing your friends and family around the streets near the building? That’s a good sign.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Size Does Matter&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
When looking for somewhere to call home, you might start to feel like Goldilocks trying to find just the right size. Starting your apartment hunt with your basic space needs figured out will make a world of difference. Consider the following for determining the square feet of your future living space.
&lt;p&gt;Do you own a lot of larger-scale furniture that needs to be accommodated—such as a pool table, a piano or a bulky sectional sofa? How many bedrooms and bathrooms do you want? Are you the type to spend a ton of time in your bedroom, or do you need a spacious living room? Do you love to host parties and need seating for your entourage?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re moving from one place to another, you might want to look for something close to the same size. If you are moving into a larger place remember that you’ll have to shell out money to fill it with furniture—an empty apartment just doesn’t feel homey!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And don’t forget about storage: how much stuff do you need to store? When touring a place or even just looking at a listing on Kijiji, pay attention to the number and size of closets. Look for a bathroom closet, kitchen storage (like cupboards or a pantry) and a coat closet. A lack of storage space can go unnoticed until move-in day when you don’t know where you’re going to store your cleaning supplies or winter coats.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Nancy Drew that Apartment&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
There’s nothing worse than moving into an apartment and finding unpleasant surprises in the crooks and crannies, so put on that detective hat. When you view a potential apartment, look closely at ceilings, walls and floors for any cracks, stains or other damage. Check the appliances: open the refrigerator and the oven and try out the sink faucets. Look for signs of wear and tear; these may not be necessarily deal-breakers for you, but something to alert the landlord about so you don’t get dinged on your security deposit.
&lt;p&gt;Also, check the cellphone reception in every room! Cellphones are a huge part of our lives so make sure you walk around the apartment checking your service bars or sending a quick text or two.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scope out the Neighbours&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
If you pass someone living inside the apartment building you’re touring, say hello! Whether they say hello back, stop to chat or just walk right by will give you an idea of what your potential neighbours are like.
&lt;p&gt;The perfect neighbours only exist in Hallmark movies, but you do want to feel comfortable with the people around you. It depends on the type of person you are but having neighbours that you can at least smile at in the hallways might be important to you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Identify Must-Have Amenities&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
These are different for everyone, but here are three that we consider deal-breakers:
&lt;p&gt;A dishwasher: You can theoretically live without a dishwasher—but for the sake of your sanity and the environment, look for an apartment with one.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An elevator: Stairs may help you with your step counter on your FitBit, but on move-in day, when you’re trying to move your couch up three flights of stairs, you’ll be kicking yourself for renting the place!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laundry facilities: Take it from someone who is a serial renter: an on-site laundry room is the holy grail of apartment living. Having to lug all your dirty clothes back and forth from a laundromat is a pain. Do yourself a favour and put a laundry room on your list of non-negotiables.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Trust Your Instincts&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
We don&#x27;t call the places where we live home without a reason. If the price is right but something just feels wrong—even if you can’t pinpoint what—trust that feeling and keep searching. The right apartment should be your home base, your personal launchpad for taking on the day and where you can cozy up to recharge.
&lt;p&gt;Have some pro tips for scoring the perfect apartment? Share your wisdom with us in the comments!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Where to Walk Your Dog in Downtown Winnipeg: 5 Beautiful Places</title>
		<published>2019-01-31T11:00:54+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-01-31T11:00:54+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/where-to-walk-your-dog-in-downtown-winnipeg-5-beautiful-places/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/where-to-walk-your-dog-in-downtown-winnipeg-5-beautiful-places/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having a dog while living downtown is a great motivator to get outside, see other people, and experience small daily bits of fun. Walking your dog in the downtown helps you feel like you’re instantly part of a community of dog owners. Dogs are great companions; they’re your best friend, and keep you warm on a cold winter night. On a bad day, a doggie tail wiggle will definitely cheer you up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people say that having a dog is like having a child. I would say it’s like having a child that &lt;em&gt;never grows up&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. But as dog lovers know, they’re worth the work! Having a dog while living in an apartment can actually help you stay motivated to get outside. Dogs need exercise, and can develop health problems if they don’t get enough. No one wants their furry friend to get sick!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So no matter how snowy, cold, rainy, or hot it is outside, you put a leash on your excited dog and get yourself outside. Sometimes it’s eye-wateringly early and you’re dreaming about your warm bed, but Fido needs his walk. And as a bonus, you get to enjoy as much fresh air and physical activity as your pet! (Ever notice how fit some dog owners are?)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But here’s the problem: Your dog is all excited about going out to see the big world, but you have no idea where to go or what route to take this time. You’re in luck: here’s a list of 5 beautiful places and parks in Winnipeg within a 20-minute walk of 300 Main Street:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BrTa1dpAcvV&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BrTa1dpAcvV&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;A post shared by David Metcalfe (@davidmetclfe)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot;font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-12-12T22:06:15+00:00&quot;&gt;Dec 12, 2018 at 2:06pm PST&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.winnipeg.ca&#x2F;PublicWorks&#x2F;parksOpenSpace&#x2F;OffLeashDogParks&#x2F;DTDogPark.stm&quot;&gt;Bonnycastle Dog Park&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. The park is just a 12-minute walk from 300 Main Street. It’s located in the beautiful Assiniboine Avenue area, right across from the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.fortgarryhotel.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Fort Garry Hotel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I love spending summer days here, just walking around and seeing happy dog owners playing with their pets! The park even has a bottle-refill fountain that operates in the hot summer months. Bonnycastle Park was opened in February 2016 and has become very popular with downtown doggies. The off-leash park is fully fenced and has almost 13,000 square feet of playing area. Its design includes artificial turf that was specifically designed for dog parks. Take your dog to Bonnycastle dog park—I promise you both will enjoy it!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theforks.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt; The Forks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; You can’t let your dog go off-leash in this heritage area, but why not combine your dog walk with some entertainment for yourself? The Forks is just a 9-minute walk away from 300 Main Street. In the summertime, wander around with an ice cream in one hand and dog’s leash in the other while listening to buskers. In the wintertime, enjoy Christmas lights, watch people skate and absorb the joyful holiday vibes. Keep in mind that the Forks can get very crowded during festivals; unless your furry friend is very used to big crowds of people, you might want to avoid busy days.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;Bc6VNxqjs2x&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin: 8px 0 0 0; padding: 0 4px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #000; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none; word-wrap: break-word;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;Bc6VNxqjs2x&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;every time I visit this place I make a new friend&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;93mp&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt; Winnipeg&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (@93mp) on &lt;time style=&quot;font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-12-20T04:56:37+00:00&quot;&gt;Dec 19, 2017 at 8:56pm PST&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;downtownwinnipegbiz.com&#x2F;business&#x2F;central-park&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Central Park&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; This park is not an off-leash dog park, but pet owners love it anyway. After a 17-minute walk away from downtown, you can stroll in a peaceful place surrounded by historical architecture. The park is also a good place for a relaxing pause if you and your dog walked for a long time and need some rest. Bring a book and settle in on a bench to enjoy a relaxing day in the park.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipeg.ca&#x2F;ppd&#x2F;planning&#x2F;pdf_folder&#x2F;WaterfrontDriveExpectations.pdf&quot;&gt;Waterfront Drive&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; This is one of my favourite areas in Winnipeg because it combines historical and brand-new buildings with a wide sidewalk through the park. Taking a walk here feels like wandering through a picturesque forest. Dog owners, bikers, and joggers share the walking route at Waterfront Drive. The sidewalk is paved, wide, and well maintained, and runs right beside the mighty Red River. It’s a lovely place to have some quality time by yourself, with a good friend, or with your dog.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. The Legislative Grounds.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; The park around the monumental &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.gov.mb.ca&#x2F;legislature&#x2F;visiting&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;Manitoba Legislative Building&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is easily one of the best in Winnipeg for walking with your dog. The Legislative Grounds are a bit further from 300 Main, clocking in at 21 minutes at a walking pace, but it’s worth the extra effort. It’s peaceful right in the middle of the city, and it’s always full of dogs and their owners enjoying some time together. Personally, I believe the Legislative Grounds are so popular because it feels like time stands still there. As soon as you walk into the park and see the Legislative Building, you slow down, and a strong feeling of being part of history overcomes you. Seriously—just put a leash on your dog and go experience it for yourself. Just forget about your cell phone in your pocket, and lift your eyes to the ledges of the Manitoba Legislative Building. The details might surprise you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BrQCBAEDlO9&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin: 8px 0 0 0; padding: 0 4px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #000; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none; word-wrap: break-word;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BrQCBAEDlO9&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Mommy, look! The Golden Boy! I’m golden too right? ⚜️&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;loki_pomchi&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt; Loki&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (@loki_pomchi) on &lt;time style=&quot;font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-12-11T14:31:39+00:00&quot;&gt;Dec 11, 2018 at 6:31am PST&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
It might seem like a concrete jungle, but downtown Winnipeg is full of beautiful and safe park spaces for getting outside with your canine companion. Now you know all of my favorite parks and hidden gems for dog walking—share &lt;em&gt;your&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; favourites in the comments</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Merry Christmas from 300 Main</title>
		<published>2018-12-20T11:00:26+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-12-20T11:00:26+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/merry-christmas-from-300-main/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/merry-christmas-from-300-main/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;[embed]https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;xCs4HR9Unw4[&#x2F;embed]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wishing you a safe holiday season with the ones you love. Have a Merry Christmas and a prosperous New Year!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-417&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;11&#x2F;300-Main-Logo-Blue150.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;300 Main Winnipeg Apartment Living&quot; width=&quot;96&quot; height=&quot;96&quot; &#x2F;&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>We see you Winnipeg.</title>
		<published>2018-10-21T04:08:37+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-10-21T04:08:37+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/we-see-you-winnipeg/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/we-see-you-winnipeg/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;[embed]https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;n8lLwdEn8U4[&#x2F;embed]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The crane is up and construction is now officially underway.   This short video is a quick time-lapse showing the construction of the crane that will be used to raise the new apartment tower at Main Street and Graham Avenue. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;&quot;&gt; We are extremely excited to be underway and look forward to the next steps in this adventure.  For more information or to follow this development visit: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&quot;&gt;300main.ca&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-417&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;11&#x2F;300-Main-Logo-Blue150.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;300 Main Winnipeg Apartment Living&quot; width=&quot;96&quot; height=&quot;96&quot; &#x2F;&gt;</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
