<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Home - Living at 300Main Downtown Winnipeg - apartment</title>
	<subtitle>We all love 300Main</subtitle>
	<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/category/apartment/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-05-13T20:35:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/category/apartment/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Designing the Perfect Bedroom</title>
		<published>2022-05-13T20:35:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-13T20:35:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/designing-the-perfect-bedroom/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/designing-the-perfect-bedroom/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our bedroom is one of the most important spaces in the home. It is our retreat, where we relax and recharge. Being one of the focal points of our homes, many of us strive to create the &#x27;perfect&#x27; bedroom. But when it comes to designing our bedrooms, it can be hard to know where to start. What do you need, what should you think of, are you forgetting anything, what is considered &quot;the best&quot; bedroom set up anyways?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7931,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;bedroom2-1024x672.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7931&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no exact formula for the best bedroom when designing the perfect bedroom because each space, personality, and lifestyle is different, and you have to do your best with what you can do. When living in a rental property, it may seem like it isn&#x27;t much you can do if you are limited by not being able to paint or change too much. You can turn any space into the perfect bedroom with a few key tips, no matter your bedroom situation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Colors &amp;amp; Textures&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the overall aesthetic design of your bedroom, you want to consider your colors and textures first. If you are planning to paint, make sure you choose your colors carefully and consider the color scheme of one of the next major features in the room, like your bedding or rug.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7932,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;bedroom3-1024x672.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7932&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to go with&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.homedepot.com&#x2F;b&#x2F;Paint-Ideas&#x2F;Popular&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt; colors that complement each other&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; without being overbearing. If you already have a common color throughout the room, you might want to choose one that compliments the things you already have. You want to go with colors that are the more neutral, darker, or lighter tones than the colors you will be working with; this compliments your bright colors without using the same ones and being too much.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For textures, you want to be mindful that you are adding the right ones, but you want to avoid having too many. Textures include things like your rug, pillows, blankets, and patterns. These are all things that have and create their texture, and you want to make sure you choose the same or complementary and not add too many.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7929,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;pexels-vlada-karpovich-5357416-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7929&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you aren&#x27;t painting, having white walls in your bedroom is a great way to trick the eye into feeling like the space is bigger than it is. If you have a smaller space, it might be better to go with white to make the space feel larger, whereas, in a small room, the wrong or too many colors can make the space feel cramped.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Having the right Frame in Mind&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing you want to consider is your&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.structube.com&#x2F;en_ca&#x2F;furniture&#x2F;bedroom?page=1&amp;amp;sort-by=position-asc&amp;amp;category_id%5Bfilter%5D=Beds%2C503&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt; bed frame&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. If you will be getting a new bed frame, it is essential to think about the space and what you need when choosing one. One thing you can never have enough of in a bedroom is storage space.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7928,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;bedroom12-1024x672.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7928&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt; So if you are low on available closet space or don&#x27;t have room for dressers, then this could be a great solution for you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pick the Best Nightstand&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having the right bedside table makes all the difference. Not only is it going to be a great accent of style in your room, but it is &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.eq3.com&#x2F;ca&#x2F;en&#x2F;category&#x2F;bedroom&#x2F;storage&#x2F;nightstands&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;one piece of furniture that we all need&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, no matter what kind of space you are working with. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7925,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;pexels-pnw-production-8251682-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7925&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When picking the perfect nightstand, you want to consider the overall style and tone of your room. You want to pick something that goes with the theme, looks good, and holds whatever you need.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Less Is More&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the perfect bedroom, one thing you don&#x27;t want to do is overthink or overcrowd it. The bedroom is the perfect room to use minimalism. The less furniture, accessories, and clutter you have lying around your room, the better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7924,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;bedroom6-1024x672.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7924&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the way things are today, our bedrooms are starting to turn into the space where we spend the most time and maybe even get the most work done, so that may not always be an option. If you do have to have things like a desk, electronics, and your collectibles in your room, you can still use the less is more approach. Display things like trinkets and collections on floating shelves rather than taking up surface space on your dresser, desk, and side tables.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Room Dividers&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have to have an office space in your bedroom, it is not only a useful design trick that both helps cut the visual clutter but also the mental clutter. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.ikea.com&#x2F;ca&#x2F;en&#x2F;p&#x2F;risoer-room-divider-white-black-70182191&#x2F;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;A room divider&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a helpful trick to help you focus by eliminating other distractions in your room while working on your desk without getting distracted with laundry, tv, and bed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7923,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;bedroom1-1024x672.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7923&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Room dividers are a great design tool that you can utilize when designing your room. Often used to create a separate space in a room, these come in handy when you have no choice but to have your office in your bedroom.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choosing the right room divider helps create a separate space and hide the clutter of your &quot;office.&quot; They are also a great aesthetic feature that you can use to complement or control the room&#x27;s theme.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Accents and Furnishing&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are going to be &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;decorating-your-apartment-avoid-these-mistakes&#x2F;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;accessorizing and furnishing&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; your bedroom, you want to make sure you do it thoughtfully. Consider what you need, what the room has already, and work off of that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you don&#x27;t have a lot of space to work with or are limited in what you can do when it comes to painting and wall hangings, there are still many ways you can accessorize some personality into the room.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7926,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;pexels-max-vakhtbovych-6782567-1024x686.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7926&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right accessories can be the answer when it comes to storage problems. If you need a bit more storage space, pieces of furniture like trunks, ottomans, or even the right baskets not only look great but add just the right amount of space for those things like extra blankets or things you want to keep in your room but not necessarily in everyday view.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designing the perfect bedroom to your taste is easy to do in any space; you just need to keep in mind what you are working with, what you need out of the room, and how best to inject your personal flair into it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7927,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;bedroom7-1024x672.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7927&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to keep your bedroom a retreat and not overthink what goes into it. Be mindful of what you need, your colors, the theme, and how you want to feel when you look at your room and start designing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Landing that Loft After Love: Starting Over After a Divorce</title>
		<published>2021-07-02T19:57:56+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-02T19:57:56+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/landing-that-loft-after-love-starting-over-after-a-divorce/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/landing-that-loft-after-love-starting-over-after-a-divorce/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, divorce wasn’t exactly in your life plan. I think it’s safe to say it’s not in most of ours. But it happens. Then suddenly, your life is in upheaval and your vision for the future needs to change. It’s stressful and kind of scary. And it sucks. But, it can also be an exciting opportunity to establish the new and improved, independent you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mondo checkbox on that to-do list is finding your new home. It’s a pretty daunting task. For most of us, being at home makes us feel comfortable and safe. If you don’t have that refuge to return to, or it’s full of reminders of your past life, well, it can make a tough time even harder. But it &lt;em&gt;is &lt;&#x2F;em&gt;possible, and even manageable. &lt;em&gt;You’ve got this.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that if I can do it, you can too. It won’t be easy, but you’ll be back on your feet in no time. Remember though, every situation is unique. Assess your circumstances and then tackle those hurdles as only you can!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you do anything else, you’ve got to answer this all important question:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What’s your budget?&amp;nbsp;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A budget is &lt;em&gt;integral&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to starting things off right.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re going from living with a spouse and splitting the expenses to living on your own, you’re going to need to reassess your finances. Depending on your situation, this may drastically affect your standard of living (harsh, but true).&amp;nbsp;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Break down your monthly income and your current expenses. Which are non-negotiable? Which can be reduced? And when in doubt, round up! If you always count on socking away a little extra, the surplus will help to cover any unexpected expenses that crop up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a ballpark figure, about 30% of your monthly income is going toward rent. Depending on your earnings and your housing needs, that number might be even higher. In the quest for your new address, be sure to consider what utilities and amenities are included - a higher monthly payment might be worth it if it covers your electric bill and gym membership too!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve run the numbers and you’re going to be hard pressed to make ends meet, &lt;em&gt;don’t panic&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. There is social support in place for this situation you may qualify for. Those in Manitoba can find out more through the 2-1-1 phone line or website.&amp;nbsp;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you know how much you’re prepared to spend, it’s time to hit the bricks (or the search engine).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:6801,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2021&#x2F;06&#x2F;Divorce1-1024x693.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-6801&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finding a place&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like with any important decision: take your time!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another way of saying &lt;strong&gt;don’t take the first thing that comes along&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re anything like me, you’re eager to get out of this limbo and on with your life! But it’s worth it to look around and weigh your options (especially remembering some ‌places I considered - yikes!).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only do you want a place that fits your budget, you want something that fits your lifestyle. Somewhere you can reclaim that safe and comfortable environment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the short term, I recommend renting as opposed to buying for two main reasons:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:list {&quot;ordered&quot;:true,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;1&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexibility&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp; - Right now your future is uncertain. A lease gives you the option to adjust your plans as circumstances evolve. Plus, it’s easier to find something that fits your budget.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Convenience - &lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;You have enough to deal with without worrying about replacing appliances or building and yard maintenance! Instead, you can plunk yourself in a central location with easy access to whatever amenities you need.&amp;nbsp;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:list --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My downtown apartment was the perfect haven, with easy access to transit, restaurants, parks and entertainment. It had everything I needed to let me hunker down and put myself back together again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you’re searching the streets for vacancy signs, try not to worry about landing something&amp;nbsp; before the month closes. If possible, shack up with a friend or even your Mom for a few weeks while you get your house in order (literally and figuratively). This gets you out of your old place into a transitory state. You’ll be more motivated to find a pad of your own &lt;em&gt;and&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; it gets you out of your old place.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can check into short-term leases. If you need a place to recoup for a month or two before you sign a long-term lease, these can provide temporary asylum.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The local Rental Guide, classifieds, internet searches and prowling the pavement are all great ways to get a beat on lucrative places for rent. Check them out and see what your options are.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your new home is where you’re going to begin the next chapter of your life, it’s okay to take a bit of time to figure out something that fits you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ok, so you’ve found a place. Now what?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:list --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Out with the old in with the you!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:list --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best things about divorce? Getting to choose your own aesthetic. Now’s your chance to design your space in a way that reflects &lt;em&gt;you&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purge the items that don’t fit anymore - both emotionally and physically. Throw the wedding pictures in storage, and swap that too big, memory ridden furniture for something that fits your space and your style. Whether you’re trawling department stores or thrift shops, it’s refreshing to pick out some new pieces you love.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:list --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan for Plants!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:list --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are happier with plants around. It’s almost like we do better with other living things nearby! (We do, that’s science.) I don’t pretend to understand &lt;em&gt;why &lt;&#x2F;em&gt;exactly having plants makes you feel better, but they reduce stress and improve your mood just by being there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you’re not a plant person, you have options. Have you considered a spider plant? Even I managed not to kill that. Or, check out these out articles to find your fit:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;finding-your-houseplant-match&#x2F;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;-Finding your houseplant match&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;which-plants-grow-best-in-your-apartment-making-your-apartment-greener&#x2F;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;-Make your apartment greener&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:list --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potentially pets&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:list --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:6802,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2021&#x2F;06&#x2F;pets1-1024x688.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-6802&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it’s already you and your furry friend against the world, you’re set. But if not, you may want to take up cat-sitting, because like plants, we’re happier with animals around. You might even look into fostering or adopting a pet of your own!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caring for and having the company of animals can be rewarding and fulfilling. But think carefully before adopting a pet - it’s a big commitment. If your life is already in turmoil, heaping more responsibility onto your plate may not be the best idea. It adds extra complexity such as ensuring your new abode is pet friendly, and paying additional damage deposits.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, having an animal around is super therapeutic because, well, they’re often cuddly and adorable. Plus the previously mentioned scientifically backed benefits of other living things! You’ve got options though - there are lots of programs in need of good foster homes for animals while they wait for adoption, or you can volunteer your time at the shelters themselves.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, definitely crash your friend’s next trip to the dog park!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:list --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get to know your neighbourhood&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:list --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re in a new place with all kinds of new things to discover! It can be a little intimidating, and you may still be mourning the loss of your favorite coffee shop, but getting out and about in your neighbourhood has multiple benefits.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, it’s important that you actually get up and leave your place occasionally, even if you don’t want to. Being outside is &lt;em&gt;another &lt;&#x2F;em&gt;of those scientifically backed well-being things. Plus, how else are you going to find the local restaurant with the best patio?? (Besides on the internet - you need to go check it out!)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting familiar with your new surroundings is a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; step toward quelling that out-of-place feeling. You’ll start recognizing the local baristas and it will ‌become more and more like home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember: Everything is going to be OK&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:6803,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2021&#x2F;06&#x2F;Divorce2-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-6803&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might take a while, but over time things will begin to feel normal again. In the meantime, it’s okay &lt;em&gt;not &lt;&#x2F;em&gt;to be okay. Lean on your friends and family, talk to a therapist, dispose of that pair of your ex’s underwear you found, preferably in a needlessly spectacular and ruthless fashion. Do what you need to do to get through this.&amp;nbsp;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Divorce is cruddy, but it’s also the start of something new. Things won’t ever be the same, but there are plenty of reasons you don’t want them to be. By taking the time to prepare and find a place that provides what you need, you’ll have a new home base and foundation off which to launch. Having the comfort of a home that embodies &lt;em&gt;you&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; will provide the safety and structure you need to heal and start the next leg of your journey.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Why My Apartment is My Happy Place</title>
		<published>2020-02-07T22:58:36+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-02-07T22:58:36+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/why-my-apartment-is-my-happy-place/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/why-my-apartment-is-my-happy-place/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;What My Apartment Means to Me&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;My apartment is my sanctuary&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;—my &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;little piece of space that’s &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;all &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;my own. Between a career, a social life, community involvement, side projects, &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;and &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;whatever else it throws at you, life can be both exhilarating and debilitating. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;My apartment is where I can &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;step away from it all and relax. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;And when I’m &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;recharged and ready to take on the world again&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;, my apartment is right in the middle of where I want to be&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;I’ve chosen to live in an apartment almost &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;as long as&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; I’ve lived in Winnipeg. It fits my lifestyle&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;: &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;I get to come home to a secured, maintained property (two fewer things &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;I&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; have to worry about!)&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;,&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; which means I have more time to spend hanging out with friends, trying out new recipes&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;, or &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;just bumming around in my &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;pyjamas&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;. After living downtown for a few years and then &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;(&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;foolishly&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; thinking a place at the edge of the city would be nice, I was only too happy to move back into the center of everything.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;without-a-doubt-ill-keep-choosing-apartment-living&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Why I Want to Live Downtown&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Downtown &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;has&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; everything I’m looking for in a&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; location&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;, with a huge variety of businesses and services within &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;easy &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;walking distance. I’m elated to be in the middle of the city with so many fantastic things&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; at my fingertips&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;. Here are my top 5 downtown highlight&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;s!&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;why-i-choose-to-live-downtown&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;1. Fantastic food
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Winnipeg has a fantastic food scene and I’ll all about it. From fresh &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bronuts.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;gourmet doughnuts&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;, to &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thetallestpoppy.com&#x2F;menu&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;chicken and waffles&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;, to stellar &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;phohoang.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Vietnamese&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;, if there is a particular cuisine you’re craving or you’re &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;just &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;looking to grab a good cup of joe, &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;there’s something &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;nearby to fulfil&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;l &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; your foodie desires.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;2. The vistas
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;One of my favourite things about my apartment is that it’s in a gorgeous location. To be &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;in the midst of&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; a busy city and surrounded by public parks and beautiful historical buildings is a dream. I love green space&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;,&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; so in the summer there&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;’s &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;nothing better than being able to walk a few blocks and spend the afternoon reading a book in the grass and &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;the &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;sunshine. Plus, there are some breathtaking views! I suggest a good wander around The Exchange for the architecture&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;, &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;or &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;timing it so you’re &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;on one of the many bridges overlooking the river at sunset.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;downtown-living-with-susan-ainley&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;3. There is &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;always &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;something going on
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Areas like &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;t&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;he &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;exchangedistrict.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Exchange&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; District&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;, &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theforks.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;T&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;he Forks&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; and &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.osbornevillage.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Osborne Village&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; are some of the most popular spots in Winnipeg&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;. Downtown is close to all of them, giving you&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; all kinds of opportunities for adventure. There are always interesting activities to take part in, like swing dancing, weekly markets, and music festivals. I really enjoy that I can just wander over to the unique shops, restaurants and venues &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;that surround Winnipeg’s downtown.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;4. It’s easy to be spontaneous
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;When you’re downtown, &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;music, film, theatre, art, &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;and &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;history&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; are&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; practically at your doorstep. It’s much easier to be spontaneous when going out doesn’t involve a lot of meticulous planning. The fact that I can indulge in some live music or an afternoon at the &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wag.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;WAG&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; when I feel like it means I’m much m&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;ore likely &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;to&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; do so.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;making-downtown-your-first-home-in-winnipeg&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;5. Public transportation
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;As a non-driver, I really appreciate that when I need to get somewhere, there are plenty of transit options. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;After living&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; on the outskirts of the city for a few years, &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;I know that the &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;difference this makes is &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;immeasurable&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;(&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;H&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;ave you ever tried to bus out of Charleswood after 10&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;pm? It’s nearly impossible.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; Since I’m already starting in a central location, wherever I need to go, I’m already halfway there!&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;getting-around-winnipeg-without-a-car-yes-its-possible&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Why an Apartment is the Right Choice &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;f&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;or Me&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Like so many people, I’m all about convenience. I’m a busy person so anything that makes my life a little easier is a win. An apartment provides this in 4 way&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;s.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;rent-vs-buy-which-is-right-for-you&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;1. All-in-one&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;My apartment building has everything I nee&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;d.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; Fitness and laundry facilities on site means I save the cost of a gym membership fee and don’t need to regularly drag my things down to a laundromat.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;2. Maintenance free&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Buildings are a lot of maintenance!&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;I appreciate that the apartment complex has a dedicated caretaker who keeps everything clean and running smoothly. Someone needs to cut the grass, water the flowers and make sure the electricity stays on. I’m glad these things are being taken care of and I’m equally glad I’m not the one who &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;has to&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; do them.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;3. Neighbours&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Your apartment building is like its own little community. Whether you’re the kind to stop and chat or not (I’m not) it’s nice other&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; to know other&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; people are close by (read: at a respectful distance).&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wont-you-be-my-neighbour&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;4. Peace of mind&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;It’s a huge weight off of my shoulders to know that if something needs to be repaired&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;—whether &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;it’s a broken tap, an appliance on the fritz or something big like the hot water heater or the roof—&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;it will be taken care of. It’s comforting that the doors to the building are secure and that there are security cameras on site. Knowing that I have a safe and &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;functioning place to come back to makes apartment&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; living nearly&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;stress&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;-&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;free.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;My apartment is the perfect combination of comfort and convenience&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;I can’t imagine a better place to live my life. If you’re looking for a low&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;-&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;stress, high&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;-&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;convenience option that gives you more time to focus on the people and things that you love, I advocate for an apartment. There are a lot of options in &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;all &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;different price ranges, so find something that suits your needs. And I’ll yell &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;it &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;from my &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;perfectly situated&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; rooftop&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;: &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;there’s no better location than downtown!&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:331}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Soundproofing Your Apartment</title>
		<published>2020-02-03T18:21:09+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-02-03T18:21:09+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/soundproofing-your-apartment/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/soundproofing-your-apartment/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Whether it&#x27;s squea&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;ling garbage trucks, blaring speakers from the neighbors&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; or the general buzz of foot traffic outsid&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;e your window&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;,&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; t&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;he noise of apartment living can be draining. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;If you find that all the hubbub is making life at home maddening, you&#x27;re not alone. For many apartment dwellers, unwanted noise is a fact of life &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;that can seem&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; unavoidable.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; But there are a few things you can do to dampen the noise and &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;make your home &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;the&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; soothing oasis&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; you deserve&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:480}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Go Rug Shopping&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Because noise naturally reverberates off hard surfaces, y&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;our biggest enemy when it comes to amplifying sound &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;in&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; your apartment is your floors. Those hardwood floors were probably a real selling point when you first viewed the apartment, but now they&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;’re &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;your worst nightmare. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;I&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;f your floors &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;aren’t &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;carpeted&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;,&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; I suggest you accessorize with plush rugs&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Ikea has many &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.ikea.com&#x2F;ca&#x2F;en&#x2F;cat&#x2F;rugs-10653&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;affordable options&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;, &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;and&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; places like &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.designmanitoba.com&#x2F;store&#x2F;c72&#x2F;Rugs&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Design Manitoba&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; might have something a bit more special. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;A&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;dd a&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; thick &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.homedepot.ca&#x2F;product&#x2F;safavieh-dura-grey-6-ft-x-6-ft-square-non-slip-surface-rug-pad&#x2F;1001131211&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;rug pad&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; underneath to match&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; and quiet things down even further&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-6209&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2020&#x2F;02&#x2F;jean-philippe-delberghe-UcatgzYuh0U-unsplash-2-732x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;soundproofing your apartment,, apartment living, downtown winnipeg apartments, apartment lifestyle, apartment hacks, area rugs, apartment rugs&quot; width=&quot;732&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Weatherproof Your Front Door &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:480}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;If hallway traffic is your problem, this is a great solution. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Place &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;high-quality%20weather-stripping&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;high-quality weather-stripping&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; between the door and &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;the &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;door frame to create a seal when the door of closed. I recommend &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;a &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;rubber &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;weather-strip rather than a foam or vinyl. Rubber is more cost effective &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;and will last &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;longer. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:480}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Hang Curtains &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:480}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;To soundproof your windows, use cellular shades or &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.amazon.ca&#x2F;Soundproof-Thermal-Insulated-Blackout-Curtain&#x2F;dp&#x2F;B01LW1BF82&#x2F;ref=sr_1_5?keywords=sound+blocking+curtains&amp;amp;qid=1579828769&amp;amp;sr=8-5&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;curtains&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;The fabric will help&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; to dampen outside noise. While shades are fashionable, they are often transparent &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;to &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;allow light to enter the room&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;—which means they won’t block much noise, either&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-6211&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2020&#x2F;02&#x2F;justin-schuler-pY58mAGvGJo-unsplash-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;soundproofing your apartment,, apartment living, downtown winnipeg apartments, apartment lifestyle, apartment hacks, window curtains&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Divide Your Space: &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:480}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;If you have a wide&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;-&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;open loft space, try breaking up the room by hanging a curtain and creating two rooms out of one. It not only adds privacy to your space but absorbs the sound waves&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;—decreasing annoying &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;noises!&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Reduce Reflected Noise&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:480}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Noise reflects off hard surfaces like wall and ceilings&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;, adding&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; to the overall noise level inside a room.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Lowering your ceiling is a great way to reduce reflected noise. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;An easy way to do this is to install &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;standard soundproofing panels. You can buy &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.amazon.ca&#x2F;s?k=foam+panels&amp;amp;ref=nb_sb_noss_2&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;foam panels&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; in all colours on &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;A&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;mazon for as low as $&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;14&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;. If you’re afraid &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;foam panels will ruin the aesthetic of your room, bed canopies and hanging textiles&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; can&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;absorb sound&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;, too&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:480}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Muffle Neighbour Noise&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:480}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;B&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;eef up thin walls&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;to muffle &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;noise from the apartment next door. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Large bookcases—a whole wall of them, if you can swing it—are a great way to do this. The shelf itself will block noise&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;, and bulky books make &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;wonderful sound insulation. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;I&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;f you are comfortable doing so, ask your &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;neighbors&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;to do the same!&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-6212&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2020&#x2F;02&#x2F;kelly-sikkema-89FNXRnHMEE-unsplash-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;soundproofing your apartment,, apartment living, downtown winnipeg apartments, apartment lifestyle, apartment hacks, book cases, book shelf&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Mask &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Nocturnal&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;Nuisances &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:480}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;If your biggest complaint is nighttime noise, a&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bestbuy.ca&#x2F;en-ca&#x2F;product&#x2F;lectrofan-lectrofan-noise-fan-machine-asm1007-white-asm1007&#x2F;10406699&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;white noise machine&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; is a simple fix. By playing a non-&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;distracting&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; form of noise, white noise machines divert your ears by masking disruptive noise source&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;s. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;You can buy white noise machines at many price points, so they fit most budgets.  &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:480}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;As Usual, Plants Save the Day&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:480}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;On a smaller scale, plants &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;can &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;absorb&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; and&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt; deflect noise. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;If you want to use &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;plants to reduce noise, don’t be afraid to &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;buy &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;a few more than you first planned. Look for a variety of plants&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; in a variety &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;of heights and sizes.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;More plants &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;mean&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; more &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;surface area to help reduce noise&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Ferns, baby’s tears, peace lilies, rubber plants, money trees and fiddle leaf figs can all help reduce noise.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;finding-your-houseplant-match&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;b&gt;Did we miss your favourite soundproofing DIY? Let us know in the comments below!&lt;&#x2F;b&gt; &lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Without A Doubt, I&#x27;ll Keep Choosing Apartment Living</title>
		<published>2020-01-24T22:34:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-01-24T22:34:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/without-a-doubt-ill-keep-choosing-apartment-living/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/without-a-doubt-ill-keep-choosing-apartment-living/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;The streets of downtown Winnipeg are sprinkled with apartment complexes, of all shapes and sizes; each one housing hundreds of apartment dwellers with their own story to tell &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;about&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; w&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;hy they chose apartment living.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233117&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;134233118&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;335559731&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:480}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Many people become apartment dwellers for the first time during their university years&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;, &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;and I&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;’m &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;no exception. Choosing apartment living was sort of a no-brainer&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; for me&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;, especially living in a downtown residence&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;—it ticked all the boxes for me&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;When I first began my apartment living journey, I was a wide-eyed twenty-something student &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;without a&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; full-time job &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;or &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;any &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;major responsibilities&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;. A&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;partment living fit perfectly with my lifestyle&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;A&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;s the years passed and&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; the leases &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;came &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;to an end&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;,&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;I always &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;found &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;myself living in an apartment downtown instead of venturing off somewhere else or &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;rent-vs-buy-which-is-right-for-you&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;taking the financial plunge &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;into house ownership&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233117&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;134233118&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;335559731&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:480}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Fits My Lifestyle &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233117&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;134233118&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:480}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;One of the main reasons I chose apartment living is because I get bored super easily. I like to change up my lifestyle as often as possible and apartment living gives me that opportunity. Within downtown&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; Winnipeg&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;, there are so many &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;different areas &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;and streets that satisfy my ever-lasting need to switch-it-up. There is no better feeling than knowing &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;that &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;when my lease is up&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;,&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; I have the luxury of picking up and relocating. Truly liberating! &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;why-i-choose-to-live-downtown&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Prime Location&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233117&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;134233118&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:480}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;One of the many reasons people like me appreciate apartment living is where they&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;’re located&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;! &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;D&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;on’t get me wrong&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;: &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;there are plenty of &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;diverse &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;neighborhoods in various parts of Winnipeg that &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;houses inhabit&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;,&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; but there is nothing quite like apartment living&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; downtown&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;. Living in a downtown high-rise&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;,&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;you’re &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;smack in the middle of everything happening in the city! &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Most of Winnipeg’s talk-of-the-town &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;events&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;events&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; happen in the city’s core&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;. You&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;’re &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;also near &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;coffee-shops-in-downtown-winnipeg&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;the best coffee shops&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;, mouth-watering &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;eateries&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;, and one-of-a-kind &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;hidden-fashion-boutiques-downtown-and-in-the-exchange&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;boutiques&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;If&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; you &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;feel &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;like venturing into other parts of town, there&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;’s &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;a transit stop &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;on nearly every block&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;so you can go &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;wherever your heart desires. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;coffee-shops-in-downtown-winnipeg&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Easy on the Wallet &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233117&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;134233118&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:480}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Being a new university graduate, my budget has a budget—&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;so a &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;major bonus &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;of&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; living in an apartment is that it is quite &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;six-reasons-why-renting-is-the-smart-move-for-millennials&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;easy on the wallet&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;. If something goes wrong with my sink tap or dishwasher, a maintenance team will come in a jiffy &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;to&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; fix it&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;,&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; without any additional &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;cash leaving my pocket&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;six-reasons-why-renting-is-the-smart-move-for-millennials&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Social Aspect &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233117&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;134233118&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:480}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Another &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;thing that really &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;draws&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; me to apartment living, over and over again, is the &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;new-to-networking-start-with-your-neighbours&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;social aspect&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;. I find there is always a sense of community among people living in apartments. This may not be the case for every apartment block&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;,&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; but I’ve met some cool people in &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;the &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;elevator and had some great chats while waiting for my laundry. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;new-to-networking-start-with-your-neighbours&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Additional Bonuses  &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233117&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;134233118&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:480}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Houses have perks of their own&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;, but apartments &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;such as &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;300 Main come with additional pleasures&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; you just can’t get in a house&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;, such as a residential gym, &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;a &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;pool&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;,&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; a&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;nd &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;heated &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;underground parking!&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;300-main-where-the-future-of-winnipeg-wants-to-be&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;The Bottom Line &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233117&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;134233118&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:480}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;My friends can’t wait&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; to save enough to make a&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; down payment on a house in the suburbs&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;,&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; and for a lot of us&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;,&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; we were told that &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;owning &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;your own &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;home &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;is the &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;definition &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;of &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;“&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;making it.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;”&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; To that, I &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;say&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;, &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;“&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;To &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;each their own&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;!”&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;To me, “making it” means &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;being able to explore every inch of &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;what Winnipeg’s &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;downtown&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt; as to offer&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=&quot;none&quot;&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;why-i-loved-apartment-living&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tell us below&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;W&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;hy &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;did &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;you &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;choose &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;apartment living? &lt;&#x2F;b&gt; &lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How to Decorate your Small Space for the Holidays</title>
		<published>2019-11-29T22:05:40+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-11-29T22:05:40+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/how-to-decorate-your-small-space-for-the-holidays/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/how-to-decorate-your-small-space-for-the-holidays/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Holiday decorating is one of the best parts of winter, and living in a tiny apartment shouldn’t mean you have to miss out! Decorating for the holidays in a small space can be tricky, so we’re here to help with a collection of festive ideas.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christmas Tree Chaos&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miniature Tree&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
It may be small, but a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.amazon.ca&#x2F;s?bbn=6647219011&amp;amp;rh=n%3A2206275011%2Cn%3A%212206276011%2Cn%3A2224027011%2Cn%3A2224031011%2Cn%3A13848649011%2Cn%3A6647219011%2Cp_n_size_browse-bin%3A6819137011&amp;amp;dc&amp;amp;fst=as%3Aoff&amp;amp;qid=1574642410&amp;amp;rnid=6819135011&amp;amp;ref=lp_6647219011_nr_p_n_size_browse-bin_1&quot;&gt;miniature Christmas tree&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; can still pack a stylish punch. A tiny tree is one of the easiest and most common decorations for small spaces. I decorate my miniature tree with an over-the-top tree topper, festive ornaments, and twinkling fairy lights. I also like to sweeten it up with a few candy canes. Even though it’s tiny, I love how my Christmas tree lights up the room with its larger-than-life presence.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-6093&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;toa-heftiba-9FT_mSlYAjQ-unsplash-683x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;683&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Half of a Christmas Tree
&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;I admit this one requires an open mind. When I first heard about half Christmas trees, I thought whoever came up with the idea was insane. But, after a few sleepless nights up thinking about it (it &lt;em&gt;really&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; bothered me), I realized its brilliance!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuck this slim, festive fellow in a corner for all the fun of a full-size Christmas tree for half the space. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.amazon.ca&#x2F;TANGKULA-Artificial-Christmas-Half-Shape-Decoration&#x2F;dp&#x2F;B081MYBNG7&#x2F;ref=sr_1_16?keywords=half+christmas+tree&amp;amp;qid=1574640178&amp;amp;sr=8-16&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.walmart.ca&#x2F;en&#x2F;ip&#x2F;Home-Heritage-7-Ft-Pre-Lit-Artificial-Half-Christmas-Tree-with-Folding-Stand&#x2F;PRD1TCPD0VT30L5&quot;&gt;Walmart&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; sell cheap but high-quality half Christmas trees.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Christmas Tree Doesn’t Need to be Pine
&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;When you imagine a Christmas tree, you’re automatically going to picture a lush, green pine tree. But I’m here to advocate for all the other types of plant that can be just as festive!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-6090&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;photo-of-decorations-on-the-wall-732917-671x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;671&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for more greenery or just don’t want to go out and buy a tree, consider giving one of your houseplants a chance to shine this holiday season. I like to decorate the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.shelmerdine.com&#x2F;product&#x2F;fiddle-leaf-fig-tree&#x2F;&quot;&gt;fiddle leaf fig tree&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in my bedroom with bulbs, holly and candy canes. It’s quirky and brings so much character to the room.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Festive Fairy Light Tree
&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.amazon.ca&#x2F;Kohree-Changing-Decorative-Stroller-DecorTree&#x2F;dp&#x2F;B01HO0RVCI&#x2F;ref=sr_1_7?keywords=fairy+lights&amp;amp;qid=1574642608&amp;amp;s=hi&amp;amp;sr=1-7&quot;&gt;Fairy lights&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; have so many uses; you can string them up or get creative! When I was first settling into my downtown apartment and wasn’t sure if I wanted to invest in a tree, I created one myself. Pair your fairy lights with garland and pin them up on your wall in the shape of a pine tree (or a fiddle leaf fig tree!), and you’ve got yourself a DIY Christmas tree. Be creative: you can attach bulbs or even candy canes to it, just like a real tree.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trick can also be used as a decoration hack for those who celebrate other holidays. Creating a Star of David with the lights on your wall is just as simple and beautiful!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Mantel Makeover&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
I’m pretty lucky; my apartment has a brick fireplace with a beautiful oak mantel. If you have a fireplace, decorating the mantel is an easy way to display small decorations without taking up floor space.
&lt;p&gt;Since I like to keep the rest of my living room fairly simple for Holiday decorating, I make the mantle my centerpiece. I prefer traditional Christmas colours, so I decorate my mantel with deep greens by pinning a flocked pine wreath above the fireplace and draping garland across the mantle. I then strategically place crimson-red holly within the garland and finish the look by pinning up a few red stockings. The stockings also draw my guests’ eyes down to the burning fire underneath, completing the cozy look I’m going for.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Utilizing Holiday Cards&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
I don’t know about you, but as soon as December 1st hits I’m bombarded with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.etsy.com&#x2F;ca&#x2F;search?q=christmas+card&amp;amp;locationQuery=6183235&quot;&gt;holiday cards&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from family, friends and co-workers. Don’t get me wrong, I love them, but at first I was confused about what to do with all of them. Eventually, inspiration struck and I started selecting a few with the most festive illustrations to display on my mantel behind my garland. Not only do they make cheerful decorations, they also remind me of my loved ones.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Deck the Halls—Literally!&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Mistletoe
&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;Mistletoe is a winter classic that doesn’t take up any space at all. All you need is a doorway, such as in a hallway, to let the festive smooches begin!
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paper Snowflakes&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
I love decorating my space with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instructables.com&#x2F;id&#x2F;How-to-Make-6-Pointed-Paper-Snowflakes&#x2F;&quot;&gt;paper snowflakes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. They make me feel so nostalgic about being a kid and spending all winter snipping them out with safety scissors. As an adult, they’re an inexpensive decoration that brings the romance of snow into your home – without the chill.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally like stringing paper snowflakes up on the ceiling, letting them drape down to bring a touch of magic to an entranceway. Try hanging them by a window where they can catch the every-changing winter light.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Create a Holiday Scent&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
So, your place looks festive…but does it smell festive? &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.charlestonandharlow.com&#x2F;collections&#x2F;fall-holiday&quot;&gt;Scented candles&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are the easiest way to bring a merry aroma to your apartment. Cinnamon, gingerbread, fire and pine are a few of my favourite scented candle fragrances; all these are super easy to find in your favourite candle shop! Coal and Canary even sells a cute &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.coalandcanary.com&#x2F;product-page&#x2F;holiday-collection-box-set&quot;&gt;Holiday Collection Box Set&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;center&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;B5RGZdpBM9-&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;B5RGZdpBM9-&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.w3.org&#x2F;2000&#x2F;svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.w3.org&#x2F;1999&#x2F;xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;path&gt;&lt;&#x2F;g&gt;&lt;&#x2F;g&gt;&lt;&#x2F;g&gt;&lt;&#x2F;svg&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;B5RGZdpBM9-&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;A post shared by Coal and Canary Candle Company (@coalandcanary)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-11-24T23:48:42+00:00&quot;&gt;Nov 24, 2019 at 3:48pm PST&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&quot;&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re hosting a holiday party tonight or are looking for a more creative way to bring the smells of Christmas into your home, here’s my personal recipe for the perfect merry scent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add a few cinnamon sticks, four orange halves, one of cup fresh cranberries, and two rosemary springs to a large pot of water. Put a lid on the pot and let it simmer all day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that’s just a bit too much work for you (totally understandable), try &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.gimmesomeoven.com&#x2F;mulled-wine-recipe&#x2F;&quot;&gt;mulled wine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;! You can buy &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.liquormarts.ca&#x2F;product&#x2F;warm-n-cozy-mulled-wine&#x2F;750-ml&quot;&gt;premixed mulled wine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for a lazy, but still luxe, holiday evening.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Happy Holidays!&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Whether you prefer to keep it classic with a neutral aesthetic or like to deck your space out with clashing holiday décor, we hope these ideas will help you make your space merry, bright and festive.
&lt;p&gt;From the 300 Main family to yours, Happy Holidays!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did we miss one of your must-have holiday decorations? Let us know in the comments!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How to Deal with a Wall Colour You Hate</title>
		<published>2019-11-08T20:53:23+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-11-08T20:53:23+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/how-to-deal-with-a-wall-colour-you-hate/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/how-to-deal-with-a-wall-colour-you-hate/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had never been more excited than the days leading up to my move into my dorm room for my first year of university. I had spent months creating Pinterest boards and circling items in Ikea catalogs. As soon as I stepped into my new room, my bubbling excitement quickly fizzled into disgust: lime green walls assaulted my eyes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could feel my beautiful aesthetic daydreams being crushed. Unfortunately, my dormitory wouldn’t let me paint the walls, which is standard in a rental. However, I was determined not to let that hideous colour stop me from having the best dorm room in the hall. Here are my cheap and easy tips to save your style when you’re stuck with unpleasant paint!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tapestry is Your New Best Friend&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
As soon as you add a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;society6.com&#x2F;tapestries&#x2F;winnipeg&quot;&gt;tapestry&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (or your DIYed fabric) onto your wall, what lies underneath is your little secret. This is the easiest way to make an unfortunate wall colour disappear. Plus, you won’t lose your security deposit when it’s time to move.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_6019&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;700&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;society6.com&#x2F;product&#x2F;winnipeg-skyline-yyh_tapestry?sku=s6-8105496p42a55v412&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-6019&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;winnipeg-skyline-yyh-tapestries.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;wall painting, accent wall, tapestry, wallpaper, apartment decor, decorating, interior design, apartment style, boho-style apartment, boho-style wall, apartment living, renting an apartment, wall art, winnipeg skyline, tapestry&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Winnipeg Skyline Wall Tapestry by MarianVoicu on Etsy[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Peel-and-Stick Backsplash Tiles or Wallpaper&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
You can pick these up at the dollar store, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.homedepot.ca&#x2F;en&#x2F;home&#x2F;categories&#x2F;decor&#x2F;wallpaper-and-supplies&#x2F;wallpaper.html?q=*:relevance:categoryPathHierarchy:3%252Fhd-classes%252Fl1-decor%252Fl2-wallpaper%252Fl3-wallpaper:attributeidWallpApplication2016:Self-Adhesive%252FPeel%2Band%2BStick&quot;&gt;Home Depot&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wallpops.com&#x2F;nu1650-birch-tree-peel-and-stick-wallpaper&quot;&gt;online&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and they’re super easy to apply! You apply them right on top of the paint. When you’re ready to move or just need a change in backdrop, they peel right off.
&lt;h3&gt;Cover Every Inch in Art&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
I’m a self-professed clutter bug and love having lots of action on my walls. If that sounds like you, this is the perfect solution to your wall-based conflict! Divide your wall into sections and decorate it with collages of artwork, mirrors and larger décor&#x2F;paintings. Perhaps your style leans more towards weavings, like this &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.etsy.com&#x2F;ca&#x2F;listing&#x2F;677226640&#x2F;50-shades?ref=shop_home_active_1&amp;amp;frs=1&quot;&gt;cool piece from Winnipeg artist Rebecca Riel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_6012&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;768&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-6012&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;lena-malevitis-_Kn4EGbLqGo-unsplash-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;wall painting, accent wall, tapestry, wallpaper, apartment decor, decorating, interior design, apartment style, boho-style apartment, boho-style wall, apartment living, renting an apartment, wall art&quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt; ? by Lena Malevitis from Unsplash[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Use Complementary Colours&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
This ties in with covering the wall in art. It might seem difficult to compliment a colour you hate, but this tip can really add to your décor. For example, to deal with my lime green walls I added muted and neutral tones. I used black and white photographs, a darker green tapestry and a mocha-coloured mirror. Even though I was working with the colour of the wall, it worked with my style and drew more attention to it.
&lt;p&gt;For help finding colour inspiration, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.architecturelab.net&#x2F;&quot;&gt;www.architecturelab.net&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a great resource.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Reflect with a Mirror&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
A sculptural &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.picturesframesandmore.com&#x2F;mirrors&#x2F;page-id-166&#x2F;Decorative&#x2F;&quot;&gt;mirror&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a great, eye-pleasing way to direct attention away from the wall. For starters, mirrors are wonderful for &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.apartmenttherapy.com&#x2F;10-ways-to-use-mirrors-to-make-113181&quot;&gt;making rooms appear bigger&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and illuminating your space. They’re also great for directing attention! Your guests will be more prone to looking at themselves in the mirror than to notice what it’s hiding.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_6014&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;1024&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-6014&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;round-brown-framed-mirror-with-reflection-of-curtain-1587597-1024x749.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;wall painting, accent wall, tapestry, wallpaper, apartment decor, decorating, interior design, apartment style, boho-style apartment, boho-style wall, apartment living, renting an apartment, wall art&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;749&quot; &#x2F;&gt; ? by Erin Profaci from Pexels[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Make Another Wall the Focus&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
I found myself putting a lot of effort into the wall adjacent to the lime green fiasco. That way, when guests came into my room their attention was immediately drawn to the cool photos on the other wall. I also hung lights around the space.
&lt;h3&gt;Add Greenery&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Adding a couple &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.verdeywg.shop&#x2F;product&#x2F;ctenanthe-lubbersiana&#x2F;449?cp=true&amp;amp;sa=false&amp;amp;sbp=false&amp;amp;q=false&amp;amp;category_id=2&quot;&gt;tall potted plants&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; beside a wall is one of the easiest ways to direct attention away from the wall behind. Plants might even &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.forbes.com&#x2F;sites&#x2F;nomanazish&#x2F;2018&#x2F;02&#x2F;10&#x2F;think-you-dont-need-houseplants-science-says-different&#x2F;#25af3ef53595&quot;&gt;help you relax&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-6016&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;photo-of-swiss-cheese-plant-3125195-874x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;wall painting, accent wall, tapestry, wallpaper, apartment decor, decorating, interior design, apartment style, boho-style apartment, boho-style wall, apartment living, renting an apartment, potted plant&quot; width=&quot;874&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Consider a Cabinet&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
If you’ve been thinking about investing in &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.pier1.ca&#x2F;cremone-rubbed-black-72%22-tall-cabinet&#x2F;4121735.html?cgid=bookshelves-decorative-cabinets#nav=left&amp;amp;origin=gridswatch&quot;&gt;hefty cabinetry&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.structube.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;madras-bookcase-47-02-94?pid=18071&quot;&gt;bigger bookshelf&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, this is the time to bite the bullet and make a purchase.
&lt;p&gt;Having a not-so-great paint job is not the end of the world. Instead of looking at it as a hassle, try looking at it as motivation to be experimental and creative!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have any tips on how to decorate a wall colour that we did not cover? Let us know in the comments!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Thrifting for Your New Home (And What To Buy New)</title>
		<published>2019-10-31T20:25:07+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-10-31T20:25:07+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/thrifting-for-your-new-home-and-what-to-buy-new/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/thrifting-for-your-new-home-and-what-to-buy-new/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;konmari.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Marie Kondo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; craze sweeps the nation, everyone is decluttering their household belongings. There’s never been a better time to take advantage of the overflowing thrift stores to deck out your own space. Shopping secondhand is a win for your planet, your community, and your wallet. Now that sparks joy!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why Thrift?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environmental impact&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every thrifted item means one less new one produced, which is important because the production of each household item is costly to the environment. By choosing to thrift your household items, you’re helping divert used goods from landfills. Value Village alone diverts over 700 million pounds from landfills annually!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_5988&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;580&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;bozemanmagazine.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;2016&#x2F;04&#x2F;01&#x2F;26026_upholstery_in_the_maker_space&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-5988&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;10&#x2F;From-Bozeman-Magazine.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thrift store, thrifting, shopping for furniture, furniture shopping for your apartment, apartment living winnipeg, 300 Main downtown winnipeg apartments, furniture waste, furniture in landfills&quot; width=&quot;580&quot; height=&quot;386&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Photo from an article titled Upholstery in the Maker Space, Bozeman Magazine[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social impact&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thrift stores make it easier to know where your money is going. For instance, one of Winnipeg’s most popular thrift stores, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.valuevillage.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Value Village&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, donates a large portion of their proceeds back into the community.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal impact&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite item in my downtown apartment is a unique, red oak coffee table that I copped from &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;canadiangoodwill.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Goodwill&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for just $12! Amazed by my deal, I looked online—similar items sold for $150. Need I say more?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to Shop Secondhand Décor&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Friendly reminder that when you buy used, you’re technically sharing with the previous owners. Check fabric and upholstered pieces carefully before making your purchase. Always check for M.O.P.S: mildew, odors, pests and stains!
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shop prepared&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing the measurements of the room you want to decorate is key! There’s nothing worse than coming home with your dream rug only to realize it’s way too big for your space. Measure the room beforehand, write the measurements down, and bring a measuring tape with you when you go shopping. These simple precautions will save you so much hassle.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus on key pieces first, rather than browsing everything. It’s easy to get overwhelmed when thrifting. You might be on a mission for a coffee table but end up lost among dozens of decorative mirrors.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Look for potential, not perfection&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thrifted goods likely won’t look perfect when you purchase them, but that doesn’t mean they aren’t right for your space.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-5990&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;10&#x2F;alexandra-gorn-JIUjvqe2ZHg-unsplash-1024x684.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thrift store, thrifting, shopping for furniture, furniture shopping for your apartment, apartment living winnipeg, 300 Main downtown winnipeg apartments&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;684&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know your style&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combining a variety of decorating styles can be a cool, edgy look, but only when done carefully. Avoid decorating seasickness by carefully considering two questions: What’s your existing style, and what colour scheme are you going for?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re decorating a space that you’ll be spending a lot of time in. Make sure you like the items you bring into your space and that they reflect your personal style. You’re doing no one any good by decorating the space in fads and trends that you really don’t truly like. And having an assortment of colours and furniture can be a pretty, eccentric look, but there should always be an overall colour scheme to keep your room cohesive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What to Buy New&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mattress&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to mattress shopping, I have two words for you: bed bugs! A mattress is one of the most important things to buy after signing the lease to your new apartment. I think it goes without saying that buying a used mattress is a no-no. Bed bugs are great hitchhikers!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crib&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a baby is expensive, but a crib is not something you should want to skimp on. Buying a used crib is risky, because you don’t know what type of internal damage there might be.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pet furniture&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have no way of knowing what previous pets were up to on second-hand pet beds, crates, blankets or toys. To ensure your furry friend has a clean and safe place to sit or sleep, avoid buying pet items second-hand.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you prefer thrifting or buying new for your apartment? Tell us down below!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Furnishing Hearth and Home</title>
		<published>2019-10-25T17:57:22+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-10-25T17:57:22+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/furnishing-hearth-and-home/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/furnishing-hearth-and-home/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Does the idea of furniture shopping bring you feelings of glee—or dread? Even if it’s not your favourite thing, choose furniture carefully to ensure you have a happy, comfortable abode. There is no one style that will suit everyone, so let’s look at some things you should consider before you furnish your digs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Living Room&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
We’ll start in the living room or family room. You’ve got options when it comes to your furniture upholstery, such as leather, wood or fabric. What will work best for you depends on a few factors.
&lt;p&gt;Nice furnishings don’t always mix well with children or clawed pets. If you have small children or a feline who loves to scratch, you might want to save yourself some heartache and avoid expensive materials like leather.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-5964&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;10&#x2F;IMG_4018-1024x768.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;furniture shopping, apartment living, downtown winnipeg apartments, apartments in winnipeg, furniture shopping in Winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;768&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should also consider the temperature you tend to keep your home at. If you like thing on the warm side, be aware that leather can stick to bare skin. There’s nothing fun about the sting that follows peeling your body off leather furniture. On the other hand, leather is durable and comfy to sink into. For the vegans or vegetarians among you, leather is likely out, so you may want to consider &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.ikea.com&#x2F;ca&#x2F;en&#x2F;p&#x2F;vimle-sofa-with-chaise-farsta-dark-brown-s79206994&#x2F;&quot;&gt;artificial leather&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or a different type of upholstery.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wood can be nice for some furnishings, but you don’t want an entire couch made of it. (Imagine trying to take an afternoon nap on that.) Wood can stand up to Fluffy and her talons, though, so you might look for couches and chairs that pair wood frames with fabric coverings if you have a particularly-destructive cat. Wood gives a room a nice look and has great durability. I have cube-shaped, solid-wood end tables that I can stand on. They’re great for when my short frame needs to dust high places. Places like &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.biglowwoodcraft.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Biglow Woodcraft&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; make beautiful pieces right here in Winnipeg.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-5961&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;10&#x2F;angelo-pantazis-rXDAVb7tvA-unsplash-681x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;furniture shopping, apartment living, downtown winnipeg apartments, apartments in winnipeg, furniture shopping in Winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;681&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost is another factor when we decide what to buy. Leather and wood tend to be more expensive than fabric, so they might end up out of your price range. When considering cost, think about how long you intend to have that piece of furniture. Some people want to buy something and use it forever, and others like to change up their décor regularly. You may want to spend a bit less if you can’t see yourself liking the same desk or chair for years; you’ll want to replace it eventually.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-5966&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;10&#x2F;stephanie-harvey-PPA6wsuedeM-unsplash-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;furniture shopping, apartment living, downtown winnipeg apartments, apartments in winnipeg, furniture shopping in Winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The size of your space also plays a major role in your furniture shopping. You might love the idea of a gigantic sectional so all your friends can come over and watch Jets games, but a sectional won’t work in a tiny apartment. Instead, you might choose something like this &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thesefourwalls.ca&#x2F;sofas-sectionals&#x2F;axis-sofa&quot;&gt;plush-looking condo sofa&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. My home is small, so we’ve gotten good at picking up furniture that fits in our space. Some people look at Ikea with disdain, but it’s a great place to find &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.ikea.com&#x2F;ms&#x2F;en_JP&#x2F;rooms_ideas&#x2F;small_spaces&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;pieces designed for small spaces&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. We wanted a futon for our spare bedroom&#x2F;office, but the room doesn’t have space for a double-sized futon. Ikea came to our rescue with a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.ikea.com&#x2F;ca&#x2F;en&#x2F;p&#x2F;vallentuna-sleeper-module-with-backrests-hillared-light-blue-s49277488&#x2F;&quot;&gt;chair futon&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that folds out into a single bed. It’s also super comfy!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can look for other furniture that does double duty. We store cooking magazines inside an &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.urbanbarn.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;product&#x2F;fay-storage-ottoman--alexa-steel-212122.html?cgid=LIVING-SEATING-OTTOMANSBENCHES#sz=12&amp;amp;start=21&quot;&gt;ottoman that opens up to double as storage&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Floating shelves look good and provide storage for books and knick-knacks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Dining Experience&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Does your dining room table simply act as a repository for your mail and random objects? Or do you fancy yourself a chef and do a lot of entertaining? If you’re more the chef type, choose your table wisely. Will you have enough room for your friends and family to gather around?
&lt;p&gt;Look for a table that extends if you sometimes need to serve a larger group. Keep in mind that &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.designmanitoba.com&#x2F;store&#x2F;p2052&#x2F;Nexus_Extendable_table_by_Amisco.html&quot;&gt;extendable tables&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are not all equal. How easy is it to extend&#x2F;collapse? Do you have to store the extra leaf somewhere else? We bought a great table from &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.urbanbarn.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;home&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Urban Barn&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a few years ago. It extends so we can host a crowd, and one person can set up the extension without help. The extra leaf butterflies and folds down under the table, so we don’t have to store it anywhere else in our already-tight space. It’s a far cry from the tables of old that needed (at least) two people and an engineering degree to add or remove a huge leaf, which took up valuable storage space when not in use.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-5968&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;10&#x2F;IMG_6104-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;furniture shopping, apartment living, downtown winnipeg apartments, apartments in winnipeg, furniture shopping in Winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pay attention to your &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thebrick.com&#x2F;collections&#x2F;furniture-dining-room-chairs&quot;&gt;dining chairs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, too. Do people often linger at your table? If so, choose chairs that can be comfortable for a few hours. When we bought our table, we had the option of purchasing coordinating benches that would have seated 3 people each. They were beautiful, solid wood benches—and horribly uncomfortable. We found wood-framed chairs with leather upholstery instead, so our guests don’t need to visit the chiropractor after dining with us.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chairs also allow you to show off your personal style. You can choose chairs all in the same subdued hue or add a bit of flair and a pop of colour! We had 4 different colour options when we bought our dining chairs and couldn’t decide which we liked better. So we bought 2 of each colour! Our &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.apartmenttherapy.com&#x2F;mismatched-dining-chairs-262815&quot;&gt;mismatched chairs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; add a bit of whimsy to our slate grey table.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 500px; border: #eee 1px solid;&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.apartmenttherapy.com&#x2F;mismatched-dining-chairs-262815&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Technology Can Help You Decide&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
When looking for furniture, you can download a room design app to help you decide what you want! It’s fun to virtually plan out a room to see what it might look like and what will fit. With the right app, you can do more than use your imagination when you are trying to decide what works and doesn’t. Here’s an article that links to some &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.apartmenttherapy.com&#x2F;the-7-best-apps-for-room-design-amp-room-layout-244213&quot;&gt;popular room design apps you can try&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;I’d still recommend going to showrooms, since look and size are only part of the picture when it comes to choosing furniture. I’m always most concerned with comfort and practicality in my furniture, but you can choose to go entirely online for your furniture buying. Either way, take the time to do your research and think about what you truly need. Buying furniture is far more expensive than buying clothes and you’ll be living with your decisions for a long time. Don’t get stuck with buyer’s remorse when it comes to your furniture!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where is your favourite place to shop for furniture in Winnipeg? No judgement here, Ikea-lovers!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The Decorator’s Dilemma</title>
		<published>2019-10-18T20:01:04+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-10-18T20:01:04+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/the-decorators-dilemma/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/the-decorators-dilemma/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s always that one room⁠—you know the one. It could be a powder room, a bedroom, an office, a hallway, or just a weird corner. Regardless of its size or location, the one thing you know for sure is that it isn’t working for you. You want it to change. You’re just not sure what that means or where to begin.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, I’m not about to tell you what to do with it. I am by no means an expert; I have found myself in your predicament more than once. Typically, my fix was calling my sister and brother-in-law for guidance. I’ve called them for help for something as simple as a colour choice. (At least, I thought it was simple!)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t offer up their phone number, but I can tell you that getting an outside opinion is never a bad idea. But who should you call?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I called on Kelly Porath. Kelly is the force behind &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.blueroseinteriors.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Blue Rose Interiors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a Winnipeg-based interior design firm. You may know Kelly from her segments on CTV Morning Live with Terri Apostle. I presented her with a hypothetical situation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: none; overflow: hidden;&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;plugins&#x2F;post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FCTVMorningWPG%2Fposts%2F1692892317414267&amp;amp;width=500&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;512&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Situation&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
You have a great office space, but more often than not you find yourself working at your kitchen table. You have come to the conclusion that your office is simply not conducive to getting work done. It never gets direct sunlight and its decor doesn’t help. In fact, you think that it makes the room feel even smaller.
&lt;p&gt;You want that to change. After all, the idea of having a home office is one of the reasons you chose this apartment in the first place!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this scenario in mind, Kelly provided a few pointers to solve your office dilemma.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paint&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Dark colours absorb light and light ones reflect more light into the space.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Never pick your paint colours in the store.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Walk around the space, holding your paint sample.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Consider painting the entire room a single colour to unify the space, making it feel larger.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Use a neutral colour as a backdrop, and then use accent pieces to bring in colour.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-5928&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;10&#x2F;close-up-colors-focus-2647714-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Decor, Home decor, Apartment Decor, Room Decor, Office Decor, Apartment Hacks, Decorating, Wall Painting, Furniture&quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mirrors&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflective surfaces make a space feel larger. A mirror can make the walls feel as if they have moved out. Having said that, how you position a mirror is very important. Be aware of what the mirror will reflect and don’t install them too high. If hanging a mirror over a sofa, position the mirror so its bottom edge is 6 to 9 inches above the back of the couch. The mirror’s size should be proportional to the size of the room.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-5929&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;10&#x2F;apartment-bed-bedroom-271624-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Decor, Home decor, Apartment Decor, Room Decor, Office Decor, Apartment Hacks, Decorating, Wall Painting, Furniture&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lighting&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, people will not spend time in a dark room. They’ll instinctively move to a well-lit room instead. No surprise here; you’re living that reality now!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Begin by considering the ambient lighting⁠—the natural light entering the space, as well as any artificial lighting that may already exist. When decorating an office, consider task lighting. Task lighting is the light needed to perform a certain task, such as reading or working on a desktop.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, make sure to use a combination of table and floor lamps in order to balance the lighting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-5930&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;10&#x2F;chair-clean-contemporary-1571467-1024x684.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Decor, Home decor, Apartment Decor, Room Decor, Office Decor, Apartment Hacks, Decorating, Wall Painting, Furniture&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;684&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Furniture&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key to a well-styled room is to make sure that your furniture is proportionate to the size of the room. If you kept your favourite furnishings in your most recent move, ask yourself how well they fit your new home. Remember they were purchased to fit a different space. You may need to purchase new pieces that fit your new space.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, avoid “small item-itis.” Visual clutter makes a space feel smaller. Simplify, simplify, simplify.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Thank you, Kelly!&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Kelly provided some great tips to get you back into your hypothetical office. Many of her tips can be applied to any decorating situation!
&lt;p&gt;While browsing Kelly’s website, I came across this insightful line: “Your environment shapes your thoughts, feelings, and motivations.” That struck a chord with me and has made me appreciate even more the guidance that I have received over the years from my sister and brother-in law. It also really made me appreciate the value that a professional like Kelly brings to the table.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about Kelly and the Blue Rose Interiors story, visit blueroseinteriors.com or find Blue Rose Interiors on Facebook.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Perks of Heated Parking</title>
		<published>2019-10-04T18:32:58+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-10-04T18:32:58+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/perks-of-heated-parking/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/perks-of-heated-parking/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Heated underground parking might seem like a luxury, but in Winnipeg it’s downright life-changing. I hate to even say the dreaded w word yet, but there are many perks to underground heated parking—especially during Winnipeg’s harsh winters! Here are some of the best reasons to look for parking underground.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;No More Morning Duties&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
If you are like me and value your sleep, a giant perk of heated underground parking is that you save major time in the morning. Instead of waking up twenty minutes earlier to bundle up, trudge outside, and work up a sweat clearing inches of snow and ice off your car, only to then wait another miserable ten minutes for your car to warm up, you can be in bed hitting your snooze button for the third time. With heated underground parking, you don’t have to spend half of your day preparing your car for departure, you just hop in and go!
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_5887&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;819&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-5887&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;10&#x2F;ian-keefe-kJ74b4gK-Wc-unsplash-819x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Heated Parking, Parkade, Underground Parkade, Winnipeg Square Parkade, 300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, snowy road, winter street&quot; width=&quot;819&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt; Photo by Ian Keefe from Unsplash[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll also have somewhere to plug in your car, guaranteeing it will start on those extra toe-numbing days that always come around in January. A warm underground parking spot will also protect your wheels from the elements, so it won’t be 100% dependent on being plugged in.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Keeping Your Car Clean&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Winnipeg roads are the epitome of dirty—especially on groggy winter days when it’s almost impossible not to drive into a pothole full of brown slush. Sometimes, you just want to make your car all spiffy but fear the mix of the leftover water and Winnipeg’s frigid days. But if you’re headed back to your cozy, underground heated parking spot afterwards, you can scrub your car without a care in the world. Plus, underground parking ensures you’ll be taking fewer trips to the carwash by avoiding those extra splashes of dirt your car would receive parked on the street.
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-5890&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;10&#x2F;car-3266965_1920-1024x680.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Heated Parking, Parkade, Underground Parkade, Winnipeg Square Parkade, 300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, snowy road, winter street, slushy winter, muddy car&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;680&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Keeping Your Car Safe&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Your car is less likely to be dinged or damaged by passing cars when it’s parked safely underground. And if you do have the misfortune of receiving a ding from a car door or a smashed bumper, most underground parking lots have security cameras. So if the offending driver didn’t leave a note, you might be able to find out how it happened. Underground parking also helps protects you from those always ill-timed street parking break-ins.
&lt;h3&gt;No More Parking Tickets&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
“Be right back, I need to go move my car!”
&lt;p&gt;Sound familiar? Underground parking also saves you from getting a parking ticket (or three). Many underground parking lots have you pick up a ticket when you enter and pay for your time when you leave. So no rushing to move your car each hour, or leaving your dinner date to go plug more quarters into the meter. If you have the option of including parking in your rent, that’s even more convenient!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: none; overflow: hidden;&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;plugins&#x2F;post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FWinnipegMomOnline%2Fposts%2F1878140362231098&amp;amp;width=500&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;632&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Save Big on Time and Energy&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Downtown Winnipeg is known for having limited parking on their streets, especially during the 9 to 5 on workdays. Parking underground may seem like a luxury, but it will save you time and energy every time you don’t need to circle the block looking for somewhere to park.</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Why I Loved Apartment Living</title>
		<published>2019-08-30T16:29:12+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-08-30T16:29:12+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/why-i-loved-apartment-living/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/why-i-loved-apartment-living/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I spent almost 20 years living in apartments before moving into a house, and they were good years. I moved into my first apartment as a teenager with my parents to save money, but there were many reasons why I stuck with apartments for so long.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Location, location, location&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
I’ve lived in multiple cities and provinces, and my biggest reason for sticking with apartment living was always location and the convenience it brought. I’m not a driver, so I like to be in or near downtown areas where buses are plentiful and I can walk to lots of places. I spent years being able to walk to work in less than 20 minutes, and I loved it. Walking is cheap, lets you avoid rush-hour frustration, and is an easy way to get exercise outdoors. (And yes, I still walked to work in Winnipeg winters. The trick is bundling up properly, and I’ll take that over +30℃ weather any day.)
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;getting-around-winnipeg-without-a-car-yes-its-possible&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also nice to be able to walk to the grocery store, coffee shops, and restaurants. Going to a concert downtown? No problem. I strolled right past the line-ups of cars trying to leave the venue. I was often home before most cars had been able to move two blocks. And when I lived in Osborne Village, I had several friends who lived in the neighbourhood, so get-togethers were a cinch.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Not handy? No problem&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Another thing I loved about apartment living was not worrying about upkeep. I am the opposite of handy, so it helped that the most I ever had to do was reset a breaker. If something broke, such as the air conditioner or stove, I didn’t have to fix it or pay to replace it. I also never had to cut grass or shovel snow. I truly miss my shoveling-free days.
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;rent-vs-buy-which-is-right-for-you&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Community atmosphere&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
I also liked the safety and sense of community I felt in an apartment building. I didn’t always know my neighbours, but sometimes I made friends and it was nice to have people to say “hello” to on my way in or out. Being a single woman for many of those years, I always felt safer in a secure building with neighbours within earshot. Being alone at night in a house (particularly if it was a large house) always brought out the worst in my imagination.
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;new-to-networking-start-with-your-neighbours&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Nice and easy&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
I’ve done quite a lot of moving around, and apartments were ideal for that too. I never had to worry about selling a house or what the market was like when it came time to move. I just gave my necessary notice and was off.
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always liked having a smaller place, too. (Even my house is small.) I like not having to furnish lots of rooms, and more importantly, I hate having to clean a big place. I could clean any of my apartments in less than an hour, so I didn’t waste my precious time on dreaded housework.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The one downside&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
My only beef about some of my apartments (always the older buildings) was when I had no control over the heat in winter. Those apartments were always too warm for my liking. In my last apartment, butter would half-melt on the counter because it was so hot! For this reason, I recommend looking for a relatively new building where you can control your own thermostat.
&lt;h3&gt;Bottom line&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Overall, there’s so much to like about apartment living that I’m surprised more people don’t try it. They’re missing out! What’s your favourite aspect of apartment living?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Downtown Living with Susan Ainley</title>
		<published>2019-07-10T14:37:02+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-07-10T14:37:02+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/downtown-living-with-susan-ainley/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/downtown-living-with-susan-ainley/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;embed&#x2F;_WtGqd79km4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We invited Susan Ainley (also known as &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;broken_down_chevy&#x2F;&quot;&gt;@broken_down_chevy on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) to come and tell us a story of her experience living in downtown Winnipeg! She talked about how long she&#x27;s been living in downtown, why she chose to rent, and the things she enjoy most living in downtown.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We love hearing personal stories of  downtown living. Do you have your own that you want to share with us?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Make Working from Home Work for You</title>
		<published>2019-04-11T20:30:43+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-04-11T20:30:43+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/make-working-from-home-work-for-you/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/make-working-from-home-work-for-you/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you own your own business, you may need or want to work from home. This can be a great way to save yourself money and cut commuting time, but there are also potential pitfalls!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve used a home office for my writing and editing business since 2010, so I’m here to help with some tips about working from home and maintaining your sanity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Finding a space to work&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
The first thing you need to decide is where in your home you want to work. This can be tricky when space is tight. My first home office was in my downtown apartment. I only had one bedroom, so I couldn’t convert it to office space. I did have a large living room, so I set up my desk and office equipment on one side of it.
&lt;p&gt;Ensure your spot isn’t too enticing to encroach on. For example, if you have to work in your living room, setting up your desk near the front door might not work out. Your workspace could become a tempting spot to dump your coat, mail or keys when you walk in the door. Try to avoid creating your workspace in a high-traffic area, lest it become a repository for personal junk.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You also need to consider lighting for your workspace. This is especially important if you’re a creative type and are doing painting, sewing, etc., in your home. Look for a spot near a window for natural sunlight. It also feels good to be able to look up and see the world while you’re hard at work.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noise will be another factor when choosing where to work. Some of you may love background noise, such as the radio or other people talking and moving about. I hate it and don’t work well with noise, so I always look for a quiet spot.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, try to make your space enticing to you. In my current home, we have a second bedroom for my office—but I mostly use it for business storage. I prefer working in my open kitchen at my big wooden table. I like being able to see a lot of things when I look up. If I’m at my desk in my office, I see wall. I learned too late that I should have turned my desk facing into the room instead of putting it against the wall, flanked by two big bookcases, as I don’t like feeling hemmed in while working. The moral of the story is to ensure your workspace makes you happy before you nail a desk to the wall.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-4172 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;04&#x2F;vadim-sherbakov-277610-unsplash2-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Work from home, 300 Main Winnipeg Downtown Apartments, Home office, Renting&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Storage&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Having adequate storage for your business items can also be tough in a small space. You might need a big desk, filing cabinets or somewhere to keep your materials and paint. Having worked in many tight spaces, I love Ikea for their storage items because they are particularly skilled at offering goods meant for small spaces. You might have luck finding a smaller desk or storage items that can double as something else.
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always liked footstools that double as storage boxes. I can keep items hidden away and still have space to rest my weary feet at the end of the day. Shelving that hangs on walls is also helpful. It saves floor space and can provide a nice visual piece in your home if you load it up properly. Look for anywhere you can store things in or under to maximize your use of space.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask yourself if you can store more items electronically, rather than needing filing cabinets for everything. You might also have items you use infrequently and can store offsite or in harder to reach places in your home. I’m prone to towering piles of papers and books, so I need to take more of my own advice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tax considerations&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
This is the un-fun stuff, but you still need to pay attention. If you work for yourself from home, you can use part of your home expenses, such as rent and hydro, as business write-offs. There is a caveat though: CRA says the space must be used exclusively for your business. If it doubles as personal use, no dice. When I was in my apartment, I couldn’t write off part of my rent because my office was smack in the middle of my living room, which I also used for personal reasons. If you only have one bedroom, you might be in this same bind. Talk to your accountant to see what you can do about making your space eligible for home office deductions.
&lt;h3&gt;The whole work-life balance thing&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
The other problem to watch out for is the temptation to be working, or thinking about working, all the time. When your home and office are the same place, it can be difficult to pull yourself out of work mode. You can be sitting on your couch watching your favourite show, and something on your desk will catch your eye and try to lure you back to work. This is another reason picking the right work spot is critical. You don’t always want your work to be staring you in the face!
&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-4169 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;04&#x2F;adult-from-above-hair-983818-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Work from home, 300 Main Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might need to set specific boundaries for work hours to keep you from working day and night. For example, you could choose not to work or answer the phone on weekends or past 6 pm. As you spend more time working at home, you will realize what your trouble spots are, so you can create a plan to overcome them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could also face the opposite problem. When you should be working, your TV or the book you left lying out last night might try to lure you back to leisure. You might need to set specific hours and boundaries for play time and naps that don’t keep you from earning a living. (Reading is great, but starvation is bad!)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re an introvert like me, you might feel tempted to never leave your home because everything you need is right there. Don’t get sucked into this vortex. We all need to go out sometimes, even if it’s just for a walk by ourselves. Try to plan regular outings. Join a professional organization related to your work, a Toastmasters club, a book club or anything else that will get you out of the house and socializing on occasion. Being a complete hermit is never a good idea.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bottom line&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Working from home can be great. I love being able to sleep late and have a commute that’s about 10 steps long. I don’t have to get gussied up to go anywhere and I can decide what I want for lunch at lunch time. The dog and I can take a break and go for a stroll midday. I even have someone to talk to in person when my husband gets home from work. But that doesn’t mean working from home is a perfect solution.
&lt;p&gt;To set yourself up for success, create a good workspace and plan specific work and leisure times. Talking to others who work from home is also a great way to learn new tips and coping mechanisms, so try to cultivate relationships with other self-employed people. With a little careful planning, you can have a successful work-from-home life that brings you satisfaction!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you work from home? Share what you’ve learned about making it work in the comments!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Six Reasons Why Renting is the Smart Move for Millennials</title>
		<published>2019-03-28T11:00:20+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-03-28T11:00:20+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/six-reasons-why-renting-is-the-smart-move-for-millennials/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/six-reasons-why-renting-is-the-smart-move-for-millennials/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are few decisions in life as important as your first home. And with the housing market rising, everyone seems to have advice about this decision. Millennials who are moving to bigger cities feel the pressure to get into the market. They’re told that buying is the smart move, and renting is just throwing away money. But is it? I took a look at the numbers and found six reasons why renting for Millennials is sometimes the best option.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;“You build equity when you buy a house”&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
This statement is&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;affordanything.com&#x2F;is-renting-better-than-buying-should-i-rent-or-buy&#x2F;&quot;&gt; frequently used as an argument against renting&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The tenant rents for years and the landlord makes a profit, when the tenant could be using that money to save for a down payment or paying off a mortgage. On a basic level this is true, but it overstates the idea of gaining &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.investopedia.com&#x2F;terms&#x2F;e&#x2F;equity.asp&quot;&gt;equity&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from owning a property. Most 30-year mortgages build very little equity over the first 20 years, and only start building equity in the last decade. Most of your mortgage payment in the first two-thirds of time that you own a property is going towards insurance, taxes, and the organization that gave you the mortgage. Unless you’re very sure you are going to live in this house for the next 30 years, you’ll build minimal equity.
&lt;p&gt;House values also tend to increase with inflation. There have been very few periods in the last 100 years when house prices have risen beyond inflation, and when they did, they eventually declined when the “bubble burst.” When a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.investopedia.com&#x2F;terms&#x2F;h&#x2F;housing_bubble.asp&quot;&gt;housing bubble&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; bursts, the market value of your home quickly declines—but your mortgage debt doesn’t. Unless you get lucky and buy the right property at the exact right time in the right location, the chance of your house value rising by significantly more than the rate of inflation is minimal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Being tied to a place for an allotted time&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Millennials are lucky to have started our careers at a time dominated by technology. Many people have the freedom to work remotely from their computer. This freedom does not mesh well with a mortgage payment, which only sees equity growth in its later years. The economy is changing, and Millennials tend to go back to school or switch careers more often than baby boomers, but there’s little incentive for us to tie ourselves down to a 30-year mortgage until we know we’ll be staying in one place for a long time. Renting allows Millennials the freedom to spend money on travel, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.forbes.com&#x2F;sites&#x2F;petesaunders1&#x2F;2017&#x2F;01&#x2F;12&#x2F;where-educated-millennials-are-moving&#x2F;#f706ec0d3ccc&quot;&gt;starting a business&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, or paying off student debt, rather than having money tied down in a place where you aren’t sure you will want to live for the next three decades.
&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-3672 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;03&#x2F;thought-catalog-641073-unsplash-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Millenials, renting, buying a house, Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Winnipeg, Downtown Apartments, 300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;There are better ways to grow your wealth&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Not only are the gains of equity from buying a house in some ways overstated, but if investment is your goal, there are more profitable ways to go about it. Renting can save you a lot of money on your yearly spending, and that money can be used to invest in stocks, ETF’s, Index Mutual funds, RRSP’s and other investment strategies that have a higher overall gain. As mentioned above, house prices tend to increase alongside inflation. Adjusting for that, a house in 1897 cost the same as a house in 1997. As for investing, The Financial Planning Standards Council &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.tangerine.ca&#x2F;forwardthinking&#x2F;investing&#x2F;what-is-a-realistic-rate-of-return-on-an-investment-portfolio&quot;&gt;states that&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, “Return assumptions for a balanced portfolio range from 4.55%…to 6.05%.” Therefore, investing in stocks and bonds with the cash you’ve saved from renting is a more profitable option. The money you gain over years can be used to buy a home in a city that you know you’ll stay in.
&lt;h3&gt;Peace of mind&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
The &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.investopedia.com&#x2F;financial-edge&#x2F;1112&#x2F;reasons-renting-is-better-than-buying.aspx&quot;&gt;lack of stress about maintenance or repair fees is a major perk of renting&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as well, as the landlord or building manager responsible for these. This removes a major source of worry from your life as a renter, since you don’t have to think about replacing the furnace or the pipes if they break or hiring someone to check problems in your house. I know many homeowners who are frustrated with the amount of work they have to do just to maintain their living space. Renovations and repairs can be a huge drain, both financially and of your time. Renting allows you to spend your free time enjoying your home, not just keeping it in order.
&lt;p&gt;Another way renting removes stress is that you don’t have to worry about fluctuating markets and property taxes. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.gov.mb.ca&#x2F;cca&#x2F;rtb&#x2F;rentincreaseguideline&#x2F;calculate.html&quot;&gt;In Manitoba, the most rent can increase is 1% and 3% each year (with some exceptions)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which many renters can manage. Property taxes, on the other hand, can rise by more, and the value of your home can swing wildly without you having any ability to budget for it. Knowing how much you are paying at the beginning of every month is a big stress reliever for Millennials, who often freelance and work jobs that are more fluid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Amenities and extras&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Not a lot of people have a pool, a gym, a party room, or a tennis court in their house. But with a lot of newer condominiums, these are built in! These facilities are right in the building and make exercise and social gatherings easy and affordable, which is important in our society where we all seem to be so busy. These amenities would normally require Millennials to pay a membership to a gym or club, plus transportation costs. With many buildings having these amenities built in, it saves renters both money and time. Not to mention the cost of having these perks in your home as an owner would vastly outweigh what renters spend for building fees in a year!
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_3674&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;1024&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-3674&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;03&#x2F;humphrey-muleba-1119283-unsplash-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Amenities, Gym, 300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Winnipeg, Winnipeg Apartments&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; &#x2F;&gt; ? by Humphrey Muleba from Unsplash[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another benefit with renting a condo or apartment is that you are surrounded by a built-in community. Many of my good friends are people who rented beside me, went to the dog park at my building or who I just bumped into in my neighbourhood at some point. You’re surrounded by hundreds of neighbours in an apartment building, which can come in handy when you need someone to watch your dog for a day, borrow a drill for a project, or just want to get together with some new friends.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;It is the best option&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;business.financialpost.com&#x2F;personal-finance&#x2F;young-money&#x2F;student-debt-the-crippling-side-effect-of-education&quot;&gt;rising student debt&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cbc.ca&#x2F;news&#x2F;business&#x2F;house-prices-affordability-income-1.4966211&quot;&gt;tough housing market&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, many Millennials have no choice but to move back in with their parents after going to college or university. In these cases, for a young professional looking to live on their own, renting is a better option. The freedom of living on your own without the stress of the housing market allows Millennials to get closer to their dreams while saving up money and building a life.
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cnbc.com&#x2F;2018&#x2F;09&#x2F;05&#x2F;its-better-to-rent-than-to-buy-in-todays-housing-market.html&quot;&gt;new research&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from Florida Atlantic University and Florida International University Faculty, “Renting and reinvesting the savings from renting, on average, will outperform owning and building home equity, in terms of wealth creation,” which can allow younger people to live the life they want. Traveling, being in a city, having a safe home, and chasing your career: all of this is possible and more attainable while renting. Renting isn’t throwing away money; you get to live in a place with all the amenities of owning a home, without any of the costs of upkeep! Don’t let old advice keep you from living your dream.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have you chosen to rent? Are you a happy homeowner? Tell us why that choice was right for you in the comments!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Why I Choose to Live Downtown</title>
		<published>2019-02-26T17:20:16+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-02-26T17:20:16+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/why-i-choose-to-live-downtown/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/why-i-choose-to-live-downtown/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The stereotypical trappings of urban living do not make downtown—the people, food and buildings do! I began my downtown living journey when I was 19, and I’ve never looked back. Something about downtown caught my interest when I was ready to move from my 130 square foot dormitory into a more grown-up apartment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a young adult, I couldn’t decide if I wanted to create a life in an urban or suburban area. The wonderful thing about downtown Winnipeg is that combines the very best parts of Winnipeg into one neighbourhood! As the years advance and I shuffle between different downtown streets, downtown feels more and more like home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you love parks, museums, music venues or creative attractions, downtown Winnipeg has something to make your heart sing. Downtown really optimizes its space with something interesting to see, eat and&#x2F;or do around every corner.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Mixture of Old and New&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Downtown mixes the old and the new, showcasing Winnipeg’s attachment to its historical buildings by preserving them, scattered between modernized high rises. The older buildings are comforting and make downtown feel like more than just another concrete jungle. These mature buildings are one of the major reasons why I moved and stayed downtown; they’re full of stories of what Winnipeg used to be like, and how my grandparents and parents lived their lives in these streets.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_3318&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;940&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-3318&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;02&#x2F;archway-1024x683.png&quot; alt=&quot;Archway at the Grain Exchange, Exchange District, Winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;940&quot; height=&quot;627&quot; &#x2F;&gt; Archway at the Grain Exchange building, Winnipeg[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;You’re Never Hungry&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Downtown serves as a melting pot, bringing together diverse people into one place—and it really shows through the food! There’s an assortment of eateries, which is great news for foodies like me. You can turn on to any street and be greeted by mom-and-pop bistros, one-of-a-kind cafes, or the familiar chain restaurants you can eat at just about everywhere (which I swear taste better downtown, for some reason). Food and I have a pretty steady relationship, and by living downtown I get the opportunity to experiment with all sorts of flavours!
&lt;h3&gt;Building Connections&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Small town living has its romance, but urban living creates intense proximity between you and the people around you. It’s a common misconception that people who live in the heart of cities don’t interact with each other, but I beg to differ! You share laughs with the people at the bus stop as you joke about how Winnipeg Transit buses never seem to arrive on time, make small talk with the folks on the bus that you’re sardined against, groan along with people as you wait in the ridiculously long line at Tim’s, and smile at the person who held the elevator door open for you. These small but meaningful interactions make up the connections of downtown dwellers. You feel that connection because frankly, you can’t help it—you’re always in close proximity to someone.
&lt;h3&gt;The People Around You&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
It goes without saying that in some cities, downtown can seem cold and unwelcoming. However, I believe that the benefits of urban living can be seen in each unique neighbourhood. Each neighbourhood tells the story of the people who live there, and my neighbourhood downtown is full of people from all walks of life. In my apartment building, my neighbours include a family from across the pond who made me fresh juice when I moved in, an elderly man who gives everyone a Christmas card each year, and a few male university students who shovel the front walkway every winter without being asked. Maybe I’m lucky to know my neighbours, but with the hustle and bustle of downtown life, these types of people really shine a light on downtown Winnipeg’s unique spirit.
&lt;center&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;Bsx_u52AA8z&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;Bsx_u52AA8z&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.w3.org&#x2F;2000&#x2F;svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.w3.org&#x2F;1999&#x2F;xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;path&gt;&lt;&#x2F;g&gt;&lt;&#x2F;g&gt;&lt;&#x2F;g&gt;&lt;&#x2F;svg&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;Bsx_u52AA8z&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Living and working downtown, I have the option to walk to work inside through the Winnipeg Walkway system. It was the perfect way to commute this morning! #finditdowntown #winnipegwalkways #tgif&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;downtownpeggy&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt; Downtown Peggy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (@downtownpeggy) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-01-18T15:37:17+00:00&quot;&gt;Jan 18, 2019 at 7:37am PST&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt; &lt;script async src=&quot;&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Other Side of Downtown&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
City life is not always relaxing, and you really need to become accustomed to the parades of cars, constant mummers of conversation and the fast-paced environment. But when you look between the lines of it all, you see the beauty of downtown.
&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re a foodie, an art enthusiast, a people-watcher or just someone who loves a fast-paced life, downtown Winnipeg welcomes you. Now you tell us: what about downtown draws you in?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Finding the One: Choosing an Apartment in Winnipeg</title>
		<published>2019-02-07T11:00:16+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-02-07T11:00:16+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/finding-the-one-choosing-an-apartment-in-winnipeg/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/finding-the-one-choosing-an-apartment-in-winnipeg/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finding a new space to call home is an undertaking that can require serious time and energy. But apartment hunting can also be fun and exhilarating! With a bit of planning, you can avoid a headache and find a home you’re ready to commit to—at least until the lease is up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Scope out the Neighbourhood&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
Your neighbourhood has an enormous influence on your life, and there are a few very important things to consider when picking your perfect downtown neighbourhood.
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you research what sort of neighbourhood you seek to best fit your lifestyle. For example, if you like being in the center of everything, consider streets in the core of downtown Winnipeg. Streets like Graham, Garry and some areas of Portage Avenue are a five-minute walk from popular bars, restaurants and Bell MTS Place.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for somewhere more cosmopolitan, right in the middle of a richly varied area—the Exchange District may be your perfect match! This vibrant neighbourhood boasts many of Winnipeg’s one-of-a-kind boutiques, coffee shops, bars and restaurants. Also, it’s near the Centennial Concert Hall and Winnipeg’s own China Town.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BtNESe3AwDL&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BtNESe3AwDL&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;A post shared by @andrewmahon&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot;font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-01-29T03:56:35+00:00&quot;&gt;Jan 28, 2019 at 7:56pm PST&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in a more laid-back neighbourhood that’s still close to entertainment, check out West Broadway. It’s known for being an unofficial boundary between the hustle bustle commercial parts of downtown and the residential areas, so you get the best of both worlds. Backing onto the Assiniboine River, it’s a picturesque area with elm tree canopies over streets and beautiful historic buildings.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do some extra exploring around the area to make sure it has your must-haves for a neighbourhood. Keep an eye out for nearby grocery stores, drugstores, and bus stops.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When walking around the streets outside a potential apartment, do you feel at home? Can you picture yourself showing your friends and family around the streets near the building? That’s a good sign.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Size Does Matter&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
When looking for somewhere to call home, you might start to feel like Goldilocks trying to find just the right size. Starting your apartment hunt with your basic space needs figured out will make a world of difference. Consider the following for determining the square feet of your future living space.
&lt;p&gt;Do you own a lot of larger-scale furniture that needs to be accommodated—such as a pool table, a piano or a bulky sectional sofa? How many bedrooms and bathrooms do you want? Are you the type to spend a ton of time in your bedroom, or do you need a spacious living room? Do you love to host parties and need seating for your entourage?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re moving from one place to another, you might want to look for something close to the same size. If you are moving into a larger place remember that you’ll have to shell out money to fill it with furniture—an empty apartment just doesn’t feel homey!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And don’t forget about storage: how much stuff do you need to store? When touring a place or even just looking at a listing on Kijiji, pay attention to the number and size of closets. Look for a bathroom closet, kitchen storage (like cupboards or a pantry) and a coat closet. A lack of storage space can go unnoticed until move-in day when you don’t know where you’re going to store your cleaning supplies or winter coats.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Nancy Drew that Apartment&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
There’s nothing worse than moving into an apartment and finding unpleasant surprises in the crooks and crannies, so put on that detective hat. When you view a potential apartment, look closely at ceilings, walls and floors for any cracks, stains or other damage. Check the appliances: open the refrigerator and the oven and try out the sink faucets. Look for signs of wear and tear; these may not be necessarily deal-breakers for you, but something to alert the landlord about so you don’t get dinged on your security deposit.
&lt;p&gt;Also, check the cellphone reception in every room! Cellphones are a huge part of our lives so make sure you walk around the apartment checking your service bars or sending a quick text or two.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scope out the Neighbours&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
If you pass someone living inside the apartment building you’re touring, say hello! Whether they say hello back, stop to chat or just walk right by will give you an idea of what your potential neighbours are like.
&lt;p&gt;The perfect neighbours only exist in Hallmark movies, but you do want to feel comfortable with the people around you. It depends on the type of person you are but having neighbours that you can at least smile at in the hallways might be important to you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Identify Must-Have Amenities&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
These are different for everyone, but here are three that we consider deal-breakers:
&lt;p&gt;A dishwasher: You can theoretically live without a dishwasher—but for the sake of your sanity and the environment, look for an apartment with one.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An elevator: Stairs may help you with your step counter on your FitBit, but on move-in day, when you’re trying to move your couch up three flights of stairs, you’ll be kicking yourself for renting the place!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laundry facilities: Take it from someone who is a serial renter: an on-site laundry room is the holy grail of apartment living. Having to lug all your dirty clothes back and forth from a laundromat is a pain. Do yourself a favour and put a laundry room on your list of non-negotiables.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Trust Your Instincts&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
We don&#x27;t call the places where we live home without a reason. If the price is right but something just feels wrong—even if you can’t pinpoint what—trust that feeling and keep searching. The right apartment should be your home base, your personal launchpad for taking on the day and where you can cozy up to recharge.
&lt;p&gt;Have some pro tips for scoring the perfect apartment? Share your wisdom with us in the comments!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Where to Walk Your Dog in Downtown Winnipeg: 5 Beautiful Places</title>
		<published>2019-01-31T11:00:54+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-01-31T11:00:54+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/where-to-walk-your-dog-in-downtown-winnipeg-5-beautiful-places/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/where-to-walk-your-dog-in-downtown-winnipeg-5-beautiful-places/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having a dog while living downtown is a great motivator to get outside, see other people, and experience small daily bits of fun. Walking your dog in the downtown helps you feel like you’re instantly part of a community of dog owners. Dogs are great companions; they’re your best friend, and keep you warm on a cold winter night. On a bad day, a doggie tail wiggle will definitely cheer you up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people say that having a dog is like having a child. I would say it’s like having a child that &lt;em&gt;never grows up&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. But as dog lovers know, they’re worth the work! Having a dog while living in an apartment can actually help you stay motivated to get outside. Dogs need exercise, and can develop health problems if they don’t get enough. No one wants their furry friend to get sick!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So no matter how snowy, cold, rainy, or hot it is outside, you put a leash on your excited dog and get yourself outside. Sometimes it’s eye-wateringly early and you’re dreaming about your warm bed, but Fido needs his walk. And as a bonus, you get to enjoy as much fresh air and physical activity as your pet! (Ever notice how fit some dog owners are?)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But here’s the problem: Your dog is all excited about going out to see the big world, but you have no idea where to go or what route to take this time. You’re in luck: here’s a list of 5 beautiful places and parks in Winnipeg within a 20-minute walk of 300 Main Street:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BrTa1dpAcvV&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BrTa1dpAcvV&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;A post shared by David Metcalfe (@davidmetclfe)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot;font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-12-12T22:06:15+00:00&quot;&gt;Dec 12, 2018 at 2:06pm PST&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.winnipeg.ca&#x2F;PublicWorks&#x2F;parksOpenSpace&#x2F;OffLeashDogParks&#x2F;DTDogPark.stm&quot;&gt;Bonnycastle Dog Park&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. The park is just a 12-minute walk from 300 Main Street. It’s located in the beautiful Assiniboine Avenue area, right across from the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.fortgarryhotel.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Fort Garry Hotel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I love spending summer days here, just walking around and seeing happy dog owners playing with their pets! The park even has a bottle-refill fountain that operates in the hot summer months. Bonnycastle Park was opened in February 2016 and has become very popular with downtown doggies. The off-leash park is fully fenced and has almost 13,000 square feet of playing area. Its design includes artificial turf that was specifically designed for dog parks. Take your dog to Bonnycastle dog park—I promise you both will enjoy it!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theforks.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt; The Forks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; You can’t let your dog go off-leash in this heritage area, but why not combine your dog walk with some entertainment for yourself? The Forks is just a 9-minute walk away from 300 Main Street. In the summertime, wander around with an ice cream in one hand and dog’s leash in the other while listening to buskers. In the wintertime, enjoy Christmas lights, watch people skate and absorb the joyful holiday vibes. Keep in mind that the Forks can get very crowded during festivals; unless your furry friend is very used to big crowds of people, you might want to avoid busy days.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;Bc6VNxqjs2x&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin: 8px 0 0 0; padding: 0 4px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #000; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none; word-wrap: break-word;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;Bc6VNxqjs2x&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;every time I visit this place I make a new friend&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;93mp&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt; Winnipeg&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (@93mp) on &lt;time style=&quot;font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-12-20T04:56:37+00:00&quot;&gt;Dec 19, 2017 at 8:56pm PST&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;downtownwinnipegbiz.com&#x2F;business&#x2F;central-park&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Central Park&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; This park is not an off-leash dog park, but pet owners love it anyway. After a 17-minute walk away from downtown, you can stroll in a peaceful place surrounded by historical architecture. The park is also a good place for a relaxing pause if you and your dog walked for a long time and need some rest. Bring a book and settle in on a bench to enjoy a relaxing day in the park.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipeg.ca&#x2F;ppd&#x2F;planning&#x2F;pdf_folder&#x2F;WaterfrontDriveExpectations.pdf&quot;&gt;Waterfront Drive&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; This is one of my favourite areas in Winnipeg because it combines historical and brand-new buildings with a wide sidewalk through the park. Taking a walk here feels like wandering through a picturesque forest. Dog owners, bikers, and joggers share the walking route at Waterfront Drive. The sidewalk is paved, wide, and well maintained, and runs right beside the mighty Red River. It’s a lovely place to have some quality time by yourself, with a good friend, or with your dog.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. The Legislative Grounds.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; The park around the monumental &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.gov.mb.ca&#x2F;legislature&#x2F;visiting&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;Manitoba Legislative Building&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is easily one of the best in Winnipeg for walking with your dog. The Legislative Grounds are a bit further from 300 Main, clocking in at 21 minutes at a walking pace, but it’s worth the extra effort. It’s peaceful right in the middle of the city, and it’s always full of dogs and their owners enjoying some time together. Personally, I believe the Legislative Grounds are so popular because it feels like time stands still there. As soon as you walk into the park and see the Legislative Building, you slow down, and a strong feeling of being part of history overcomes you. Seriously—just put a leash on your dog and go experience it for yourself. Just forget about your cell phone in your pocket, and lift your eyes to the ledges of the Manitoba Legislative Building. The details might surprise you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BrQCBAEDlO9&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin: 8px 0 0 0; padding: 0 4px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #000; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none; word-wrap: break-word;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BrQCBAEDlO9&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Mommy, look! The Golden Boy! I’m golden too right? ⚜️&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;loki_pomchi&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt; Loki&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (@loki_pomchi) on &lt;time style=&quot;font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-12-11T14:31:39+00:00&quot;&gt;Dec 11, 2018 at 6:31am PST&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
It might seem like a concrete jungle, but downtown Winnipeg is full of beautiful and safe park spaces for getting outside with your canine companion. Now you know all of my favorite parks and hidden gems for dog walking—share &lt;em&gt;your&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; favourites in the comments</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Making Downtown Your First Home in Winnipeg</title>
		<published>2019-01-17T11:00:52+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-01-17T11:00:52+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/making-downtown-your-first-home-in-winnipeg/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/making-downtown-your-first-home-in-winnipeg/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Henry glanced at his watch as he gulped down his coffee, standing outside the Tim Hortons on Portage Avenue. He would be on time for his career counselling session at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;manitobastart.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Manitoba Start&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, just a few blocks away. This was his first session, and he breathed an inward sigh of relief that such a great resource was so close to his apartment building. He had just arrived last week and was eager to get settled. Securing a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.gov.mb.ca&#x2F;health&#x2F;mhsip&#x2F;mbcard.html&quot;&gt;Manitoba Health Card&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and finding a family doctor had been fairly easy. He had even been able to use the free services of the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipegtransit.com&#x2F;service&#x2F;downtownspirit&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Downtown Spirit&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; bus since everything was within a few blocks of his new apartment in downtown.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BhrT9cyHBbK&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BhrT9cyHBbK&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;A post shared by Downtown Winnipeg BIZ (@downtownwpgbiz)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot;font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-04-17T15:34:01+00:00&quot;&gt;Apr 17, 2018 at 8:34am PDT&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As he walked to his destination, Henry cast a cursory glance around him. He was amazed at the diversity; people of all ethnicities and ages walked past him, in harmony with each other yet comfortably oblivious to their own surroundings. He noticed people rushing to work, too rushed to drink their coffee yet taking the time to hold open doors for others. He was falling in love with his new home! He felt a sense of belonging and was already looking forward to the weekend. He had seen posters for &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.manyfest.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ManyFest&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and was excited to be living a short walk from where all the action would be. As he rushed across the cross walk, he thought about his plans for the coming weekend: the festival, a visit to the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wpl.winnipeg.ca&#x2F;library&#x2F;&quot;&gt;public library&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to check out their collection and perhaps some Indian cuisine at a nearby restaurant. He realized he was talking to himself as he entered the the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;downtownwinnipegbiz.com&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2013&#x2F;06&#x2F;downtown_winnipeg_indoor_walkway_map_2013.pdf&quot;&gt;Downtown Winnipeg Indoor Walkway (lovingly known as the skywalk by locals)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to escape the gust of wind that threatened to sweep away the documents that he had been carrying. He shook his head, smiling. He couldn’t wait to get back to his apartment to finish settling in. His days now began with sipping his morning tea while waiting for the sun to light up the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.gov.mb.ca&#x2F;legislature&#x2F;visiting&#x2F;docs&#x2F;goldenboy_factsheet.pdf&quot;&gt;Golden Boy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as it serenely overlooked downtown. For the tenth time that day, he made a mental note to thank the friend who had suggested he find a place downtown to start his new life in Winnipeg.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BrMdU1xga5f&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BrMdU1xga5f&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;A post shared by Heather’s iPhotos (@heathers.iphotos)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot;font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-12-10T05:13:20+00:00&quot;&gt;Dec 9, 2018 at 9:13pm PST&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting a new life in an unfamiliar city can be unnerving. Resources are limited, expectations are high and there is always too much to do. That’s why it is important to choose a location that can help you get things done on the fast track. Living at the heart of the city and near all the major institutions not only saves precious time, but also gives the added advantage of being mobile even if you’re not ready to own a vehicle. It’s cost-effective to be able to walk to most places which is exactly what you’re looking for when starting your life in a new city. Better to burn calories than cents when you’re relying on your savings!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downtown Winnipeg is also a great place to network, which is invaluable when you’re adjusting to a new culture and looking for a job in your field. You need to be at the right place at the right time. Fortunately, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.canada.ca&#x2F;en&#x2F;employment-social-development&#x2F;corporate&#x2F;portfolio&#x2F;service-canada.html&quot;&gt;Service Canada&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;portageplace.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Portage Place&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; offers free resources for job seekers. If you need to focus, search for a job and print a few resumes, make use of their free computer and printing services.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;Bdm6jzJA_3Y&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;Bdm6jzJA_3Y&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;A post shared by @simplicityshots&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot;font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-01-06T12:29:31+00:00&quot;&gt;Jan 6, 2018 at 4:29am PST&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
And in case you’re wondering, downtown Winnipeg is definitely not an “all work and no play” kind of place. Looking to relax after a long working week? That’s the beauty of downtown: it’s home to a lot of tourist attractions and entertainment spots. Whether it’s a stroll through the beautiful grounds at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theforks.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Forks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;downtownwinnipegbiz.com&#x2F;programs-services&#x2F;events&#x2F;movies-on-memorial&#x2F;&quot;&gt;movie in Memorial Park&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, everything is within reach. If you need to use &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipegtransit.com&#x2F;en&quot;&gt;Winnipeg Transit&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, most major bus routes run right through downtown, making it easy to get around! There are convenient options for grocery shopping, and a plethora of ethnic stores makes for a diverse retail environment that caters to a multicultural community.
&lt;p&gt;And downtown Winnipeg is exceptionally multicultural. You’ll see Diwali celebrations happening amidst decorations waiting for the Christmas season to gain momentum, and people rushing for Eid prayers right after Easter wraps up. There is something for everyone here: the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wag.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Winnipeg Art Gallery (WAG)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for the art enthusiast who wants to analyse each piece, free yoga classes in Memorial Park for the fitness freak, and tons of delectable dining options for the foodie. And in case you’re all three, everything is always only a few blocks away! &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.downtownwinnipegbiz.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Downtown Winnipeg Biz&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a great resource for finding ways to experience the best Winnipeg has to offer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about starting a new chapter of your life in Winnipeg, look no further than downtown—and I mean literally! Be where the government services are, where the action is and where breakfast meets business.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re new to Winnipeg or considering relocating, what else would you like to know? Tell us in the comments!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Decorating an Apartment with Downtown Spirit and Style</title>
		<published>2018-10-31T20:54:10+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-10-31T20:54:10+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/decorating-an-apartment-with-downtown-spirit-and-style/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/decorating-an-apartment-with-downtown-spirit-and-style/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Living downtown might sound like a dream to some. City lights, coffee shops, boutiques, food trucks, and skyscrapers; images of “urban” materialize in your mind when conversation turns to “downtown lifestyle.” It could even be the idea of walking to your workplace instead of being stuck in traffic that sways you to move into the heart of the city.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233279&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when you’ve finally made the dream come true and you are living right in the center, there appears another question: How will you decorate your new apartment? How can you make this space a reflection of who you are and who you want to be? For your guests, how can your apartment be comfortable, modern and inviting? The challenge is to create a space you look forward to coming home to at the end of a day, and to like it enough that you feel free to invite in friends, family and neighbors.&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233279&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233279&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living in a small apartment doesn’t mean your space has to be boring. If you are living in downtown Winnipeg’s Exchange District, you are already surrounded by some of the most historic and beautiful architecture in Western Canada. Looking out of your window every morning is your first source of inspiration for your downtown apartment décor! &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233279&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233279&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me give you a few more sources of inspiration. Here are &lt;em&gt;&lt;b&gt;seven easy tips to decorate your apartment with style.&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;1. Decide what you want to say through the interior design of your apartment&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our houses show the world who we are just as our clothing does. It is said, “Dress to impress. Dress for success.” I would also say, “Dress up your house so people can know who you are and what you’re about.” I love looking at the small details of someone’s home. Books on shelves, pictures on walls, and decor from foreign countries can tell a lot about the dweller. How do you want people to feel or what do you want them to know about you when they walk into your apartment? “He must be a musician, I see sheet music all around and a guitar right there in the corner”; or “I love those strict and simple lines of his furniture. He must be a pragmatic and realistic person.” When I lived in a small studio in downtown Winnipeg, I placed an open easel right beside the window along with oil colors and canvases. I didn&#x27;t have to say a single word to my guests about who I am or what I value. They could see a creative woman living in that studio just because an easel was a part of the interior.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;a data-pin-do=&quot;embedPin&quot; data-pin-width=&quot;medium&quot; data-pin-terse=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.pinterest.com&#x2F;pin&#x2F;514888169892992854&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. Minimalism, modern, boho…step number two is to &lt;b&gt;decide on the style&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;.&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233279&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
There are many sources of inspiration for new style ideas. However, before you start browsing the internet and designer magazines, make a list of what you like. Try to list colors, shades, lines and textures. Your perfect home—what does it look like? Does it have darker or lighter furniture? Would you prefer surrounding yourself with books, pillows and candles, or do you feel more relaxed in an empty and open space? &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233279&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233279&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your list seems complete, it’s time to start browsing. You need to describe the desired style in one word. Why? Let me give you an example based on minimalistic style. You decided that Scandinavian minimalism makes your heart beat faster. When your eyes rest on perfect wooden details, grey couches, potted plants in nooks and on sills, you are in love. This Scandinavian minimalism will become your base. White, grey and cold dusty blue will be the palette for this minimalistic style. Interior design has the same building techniques as clothing capsule; you will build, add, and create from your base. When you have a strong base, incorporating items and accessories from a different style won’t ruin your look; the spirit of your space will remain the same.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a data-pin-do=&quot;embedPin&quot; data-pin-width=&quot;medium&quot; data-pin-terse=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.pinterest.com&#x2F;pin&#x2F;114630753000986248&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;3. Mix them all up!&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
In step two, you’ve done the hard work of finding one style to act as a strong base. Step three is more fun! If you want to add more life, more chic, and a professional-looking vibe to your place - mix styles. You might have a very simple grey couch in minimalistic style, but the coffee table, rugs, and wall prints are funky in a creative or modern style. Mix modern and classic, urban and traditional; many interior designers use this method. It helps breathe a sense of life into a space.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;4. Add textures.&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Even the most minimalistic person with the most minimalistic interior design would love to cuddle up under a warm throw on a cold winter evening. Texture adds comfort. Look for textured pillows, curtains, blankets and rugs. Textured curtains with a print mounted close to the ceiling can be a great way to add some visual height to apartment walls. &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233279&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a data-pin-do=&quot;embedPin&quot; data-pin-width=&quot;medium&quot; data-pin-terse=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.pinterest.com&#x2F;pin&#x2F;275634439666792944&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;5. Don’t forget&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;memorable pieces or vintage details&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;. &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233279&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
What I love most about Winnipeg is the antique stores and flea markets. Among other interesting items, I have found 1920’s picture frames, extravagant lamps, and even an umbrella holder. Antique stores and flea markets are full of hidden gems that have the power to make your place look special. We’ve all been in a house or apartment that presents the finest furniture, yet it feels plastic and fake. There is no spirit of home. These houses do not reflect the owner’s vision; on the contrary, those expensive, perfect pieces of furniture only bring with them an impersonal feeling of coldness. &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233279&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233279&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you, on the other hand, are the owner of a basic, simple couch, what is the trick to making your place look and feel interesting and inviting? Try displaying vintage photo frames with pictures of your happy self or your cat (or better yet--you with your cat!), or the people most important in your life. If vintage details are not your thing, do the opposite. Allow yourself to splurge on just one unique and funky looking piece of furniture, a piece which will express your style and personality. It might be a sofa chair with curved legs, or a set of bar chairs offering an unusual shape, shade or aesthetic detail. Don’t shy away from bringing interesting pieces into your life. Have fun creatively incorporating into your décor items that are particularly meaningful to you; pieces with history or which have a story to tell.&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233279&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;6. Add &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;color &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;accents.&lt;&#x2F;b&gt; &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233279&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Living in Winnipeg with its long, cold winters has its effect on our visual appetite. We crave bright colors time after time. The best way to bring more color into your daily life is through intentionally incorporating richly-colored accents and prints into your interior design. &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233279&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love colorful pillows in my living room. When the seasons change, I change my pillows from mustard yellow to crisp, bright blue. Colors make a room look different. (Though I would recommend keeping your walls white or light grey to make the room appear more spacious.) Adding colorful pillows&lt;b&gt; &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;here and there can make any gloomy and snowy day seem better.&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233279&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;7. Maximize space&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a data-pin-do=&quot;embedPin&quot; data-pin-width=&quot;medium&quot; data-pin-terse=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.pinterest.com&#x2F;pin&#x2F;325525879309312118&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
Living in a smaller space can be challenging in the way of finding storage solutions for your stuff and protecting your place from feeling or becoming overcrowded. Bring more air into any room by minimizing the clutter. Clutter could include things like overloaded piles of papers, too many countertop appliances in the kitchen, or even chairs around a table that are too close to each other. To instantly make your apartment feel more spacious, rearrange furniture pieces so they have at least two steps between them. You’ll be amazed at what this simple trick can do.&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233279&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233279&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I could leave only one parting tip, it would be this: Don’t be scared to be bold and brave. Life is too short to decorate your home with boring furniture. To prove it, I just purchased a yellow couch. That’s right, a yellow one! And I’m not turning back.&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;134233279&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&quot;&#x2F;&#x2F;assets.pinterest.com&#x2F;js&#x2F;pinit.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A Composting Guide for Apartment Living</title>
		<published>2018-10-30T20:31:24+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-10-30T20:31:24+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/a-composting-guide-for-apartment-living/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/a-composting-guide-for-apartment-living/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Let’s play a game. Take a moment and peek into your garbage can. For every fruit or vegetable scrap, eggshell, pile of coffee grinds or pizza crust you see, give yourself a point. For this game we’re playing by golf rules: the lower the points, the higher the score. How did you do?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food scraps comprise a large portion of Canadian waste-bin space, but they don’t belong there! Don’t let being an apartment dweller prevent you from composting and living your best eco-friendly life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t know where to begin? Here are some quick and easy tips on how you can gain your environmental karma back.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Worm Bin&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
For most urban renters, a compost bin is probably the best solution. Worm compost bins are one of the most resourceful compost options available for apartment dwellers. The worm method is portable and quick, as worms help process your household waste and produce nutrient-rich “worm-tea”—a beneficial addition to the soil of your household plants.
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;DIY Worm Compost Bin&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
Purchase a medium to large plastic bin with two lids: one for the top and the other to place under the bottom. Poke a few, scattered holes in the bottom of the bin for drainage, and a few holes in the top of the lid for ventilation. Place the second lid underneath the bin to catch liquid.
&lt;p&gt;Now onto the wiggly night-crawlers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can purchase worms in various places around Winnipeg: your local garden centre, a vermicomposting facility (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.naturesperfectplantfood.com&quot;&gt;www.naturesperfectplantfood.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), or even &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.kijiji.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Kijiji&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, just to name a few. To make the bin feel like home for the worms, soak the bin with water and line the sides and bottom of the bin with shredded newspapers. Lastly, spread a little soil over the paper and plop in those slimy fellas.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have prepared the compost bin, you can begin throwing in your food scraps. To avoid odors and to guarantee more efficient composting, be sure to continue adding more damp newspaper strips, leaves and&#x2F;or dirt along with your scraps.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Compost Bin Without the Worms&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
If you’re not fond of worms, you need not include them! Follow the steps above and simply omit the worms; just be prepared for the food to take a bit longer to break down.
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where to Store your Bin&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
Determine the best place for you. Common locations are under the sink, in an infrequently used closet, on the balcony, or even in a window flower box.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_405&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignnone&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;940&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-405 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;10&#x2F;markus-spiske-624932-unsplash-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;300 Main Winnipeg Apartments&quot; width=&quot;940&quot; height=&quot;627&quot; &#x2F;&gt; Photo by Markus Spiske on Unsplash[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Freezer Composting&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
The benefit of keeping compost in your freezer is that you don’t have to worry about maintaining the compost bin and it’s out of sight, out of mind.
&lt;p&gt;Slide that tub of Ben and Jerry’s ice cream and that freezer-burned hamburger meat to one side to clear up some space. You can use brown paper bags, compostable plastic bags or a freezer-safe jar or tub. This composting solution is great for dropping your food waste straight from the chopping board.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only downside to this alternative is that you’ll be taking more trips to dispose of your composting drop-off.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where to Take Your Compost&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
Compost can be dropped off at various locations around the city.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;greenactioncentre.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-346 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;10&#x2F;green-action-centre-300x143.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;143&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Green Action Centre (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.greenactioncentre.ca&quot;&gt;www.greenactioncentre.ca&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) provides a list of local places that accept compost waste; and if you’re really dedicated, Compost Winnipeg (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.compostwinnipeg.ca&quot;&gt;www.compostwinnipeg.ca&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) offers home compost pick-up for a small fee. Alternatively, you might consider approaching a local community garden with an offering of your compost.&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.compostwinnipeg.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-345 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;10&#x2F;Compost-Winnipeg-300x110.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Blender Composting&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
This method is for those who want to compost their extra food bits a bit faster!
&lt;p&gt;You can use your blender to break down food scraps—though I would recommend skipping the avocado pits or anything too tough for your blender to tackle. Go ahead and throw those egg shells, coffee grinds, and fruit peels into the blender, add some water and let it rumble.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can easily dispose of this compost smoothie by adding small amounts to the soil of your indoor plants, or by pouring it into a flowerbed or soil patch near your apartment. With the onset of our traditional Winnipeg six-month winters, ask your friends or work colleagues if they have an outdoor compost bin you can use during the snowy months, or contact your local indoor greenhouses&#x2F;gardens.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, have fun with composting! Don’t think of it as a chore. It will soon become routine, just like separating your recycling from the rest of your garbage. You just may inspire your other apartment-dwelling friends and neighbours to take on an eco-friendlier lifestyle.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
