<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Home - Living at 300Main Downtown Winnipeg - living-space</title>
	<subtitle>We all love 300Main</subtitle>
	<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/living-space/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2019-09-10T21:29:09+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/living-space/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>No Nail Holes: Decorating Your New Apartment</title>
		<published>2019-09-10T21:29:09+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-09-10T21:29:09+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/no-nail-holes-decorating-your-new-apartment/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/no-nail-holes-decorating-your-new-apartment/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;To your right: an empty wall. To your left—another one. You’re surrounded by large, blank walls. The walls of your new apartment are the bones of the space that you have decided works best for you. Now that you’ve moved in, they need some attention to personalize your new home and make it truly yours.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to sound corny, but those empty walls are a canvas—a beautiful, clean canvas that gives you an opportunity to express yourself. But you want to do it without putting holes in them. To get you started, here are three tips on how to showcase your personality when decorating your new apartment—without risking your security deposit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;small-space-design-ideas&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Wall Pops&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
According to Winnipeg interior designer Kelly Porath, of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.blueroseinteriors.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Blue Rose Interiors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wallpops.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Wall Pops&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are very on-trend. Removable decals that are relatively &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wallpops.com&#x2F;how-to-hang-peel-and-stick-wallpaper&quot;&gt;easy to install and remove&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Wall Pops are definitely not the wallpaper of old. Whether you’re inspired by simplicity or drawn to the big and bold, there are plenty of options to highlight and define your space.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-pin-do=&quot;embedPin&quot; data-pin-width=&quot;large&quot; data-pin-terse=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.pinterest.com&#x2F;pin&#x2F;636485359817214732&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Textiles&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
More than just window dressings, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;society6.com&#x2F;tapestries&quot;&gt;textiles&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; can add colour, design and texture to any space. Consider blankets and woven pieces that mean something to you or speak to your personality. Whether they were handmade by a family member or discovered while shopping at a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;mulveymarket.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;local market&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, textiles can add warmth and character.
&lt;h3&gt;Command products by 3M&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Command hooks and strips allow you to hang everything from your favourite art work and photos to travel memorabilia. These nifty products are designed to work on a variety of surfaces and come in different sizes. Follow the product specifications and be careful to choose the right strength strip or hook for your art. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.command.com&#x2F;3M&#x2F;en_US&#x2F;command&#x2F;how-to-use&#x2F;all-other-hooks&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Detailed instructions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on how to use them are available online.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-pin-do=&quot;embedPin&quot; data-pin-width=&quot;medium&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.pinterest.com&#x2F;pin&#x2F;333899759859867789&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Resources&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
For more information, check out these resources:
&lt;ul&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wallpops.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Wallpops.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; offers peel-and-stick wall decals, wallpaper, and floor tiles&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;society6.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Society6.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is an international marketplace and community for artists&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.command.com&#x2F;3M&#x2F;en_CA&#x2F;command-ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Command.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has products for hanging everything, including art, purses and brooms&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Home decor retailers such as &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wayfair.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;wayfair.ca&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and HomeSense have great bargains&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Home improvement stores like Home Depot, Loews and Canadian Tire have décor and storage items&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
Thank you to Kelly Porath of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.blueroseinteriors.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Blue Rose Interiors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for sharing her tips and tricks with us. Kelly’s final words of advice: “Make your art count.”
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What would your advice be to someone decorating a new apartment?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&quot;&#x2F;&#x2F;assets.pinterest.com&#x2F;js&#x2F;pinit.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How to Maximize Your Tiny Kitchen</title>
		<published>2019-08-09T21:05:13+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-08-09T21:05:13+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/how-to-maximize-your-tiny-kitchen/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/how-to-maximize-your-tiny-kitchen/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My kitchen is tiny. So tiny that guests will walk through it and ask, “Where’s the rest of it?” But I don’t let the size of my kitchen make me shy away from cooking! I’m a foodie, but most importantly, a foodie on a budget—so I cook most of my meals at home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why I Love Cooking&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Over the years, I’ve fallen in love with cooking. I walk into my kitchen and the possibilities feel endless! My favourite way to cook is with no plan or recipe. In the kitchen there are no rules, and I love that. In school, work, and even my hobbies I always feel pressure to be creative in a certain way; but cooking is a different kind of creativity, and I can create without limitations!
&lt;p&gt;And because I love cooking so much, I don’t let my small kitchen prevent me from cooking up a storm. Here are some of my favourite ways to use my space!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-5630&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;08&#x2F;hanging-kitchen-kitchen-utensils-211760-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Small kitchen, Organizing Kitchen, 300 Main Apartments, Kitchen Interiors, Kitchen Clutter, Kitchen utensils&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Stacking&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Stacking is your best friend with a tiny kitchen. My kitchen is what some might call an organized mess. As soon as you walk into my space, you’re greeted by my microwave underneath my coffee maker, which is tucked up against my slow cooker, which has three cookbooks stacked neatly on top. Small kitchens usually don’t have room for much horizontal space, but what about vertical space? Start by stacking items that you don’t tend to grab as much, and then stack items that you frequently use together. Not only will you save space, but you’ll also know which stack to pull things from when you’re in a time crunch rather than running around trying to find your food processer or a cookbook.
&lt;h3&gt;2. Clean as You Go&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Cleaning as you go is a crucial habit for cooking in a small space. You cannot use your space to its fullest potential with pots and food scrapes taking over half of your counter space! This tip is basic, but a total game changer.
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: none; overflow: hidden;&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;plugins&#x2F;post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2F300MainWinnipeg%2Fposts%2F1497982703677591&amp;amp;width=500&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;573&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Use ALL Your Space&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Utilizing all your space is also a key component to enlarging your kitchen. Try placing a cutting board over your stove top or an open drawer. Use your kitchen table as a prep space or place one of your larger cutting boards over your sink to make extra counter space. Get creative. Just because it isn’t a countertop doesn’t mean it can’t function like one!
&lt;h3&gt;4. Look Up for Utensil Storage&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Store your utensils up high! I’m very particular about where my utensils go. I recommend that anyone who does a lot of cooking in a small kitchen store their most used utensils, pots, and pans on hooks. If possible, a shallow cubby is a great space to store utensils. I find it very stressful to rifle through drawers in search of my whisk or a medium frying pan. By displaying a few of your most crucial cooking tools, you set yourself up for success!
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: none; overflow: hidden;&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;plugins&#x2F;post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2F300MainWinnipeg%2Fposts%2F1510041235805071&amp;amp;width=500&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;491&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kitchen Appliances I Can Vouch For&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Every birthday and holiday, it seems like a new kitchen appliance is at the top of my list! Here are some of my favourite kitchen appliances that are a must for those of us with limited space.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mini Food Processor&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mini food processor is an essential! Not only is this contraption small, but it’s also a great tool for chopping up food quickly. It saves you so much counter space over clunky cutting boards.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slow Cooker&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slow cookers solve all our problems, honestly. They’re a necessity for those who dread coming home and cooking dinner after their 9-to-5. Just pop in your ingredients in the morning, leave it for the day and boom, a hot meal to welcome you home!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coffee Maker&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good ol’ coffee maker is a must for us downtowners—it’s just a way of life! I have both a coffee maker and an espresso maker, but coffee for me is a lifestyle more than a drink. I think a standard coffee maker is a necessity for all kitchens. Nowadays, they’re so compact they don’t take up much room in your kitchen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rolling Cart&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While not exactly an appliance, a rolling cart is life-changing! I bought mine from Ikea for $35, but the amount of use I get out of it makes it priceless in my book. I mainly use it to store ingredients and utensils that I need while cooking but don’t have the counter space for. The best part is, once I am done with it I can roll it into a corner and it’s out of my way!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Got any other small kitchen tips and tricks? Let us know in the comments below!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>New Season, New Apartment: Decluttering your Space for Spring</title>
		<published>2019-03-20T20:13:11+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-03-20T20:13:11+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/new-season-new-apartment-decluttering-your-space-for-spring/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/new-season-new-apartment-decluttering-your-space-for-spring/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whether you just finished binging Marie Kondo’s Netflix series or are just looking for a neater home, decluttering is a key part of spring cleaning.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve all been there: Despite your best intentions, what was once a spotless and organized space has now drawn piles of clutter like moths to the flame. Don’t waste time feeling embarrassed; we’ve all been there! Follow these quick tips and you’ll feel like you have a new apartment by spring.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Create a Schedule and Set Aside the Time&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Start off by making a list of all the rooms in your apartment, and don’t forget coat closets or cleaning supplies closets! No two rooms will need the same amount of time; your bathroom might take 30 minutes whereas your bedroom could take half a day.
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve identified the rooms you need to tackle, create a schedule and be specific about what you hope to accomplish in each room. For example, your goal for your kitchen might be to create more countertop room, or you might want to clear more wardrobe space in your bedroom.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Out with the Old&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Winter clothing can truly take a beating in these harsh chilly months. Set aside a couple of hours and inspect your wardrobe. Recycle any hole-infested sweaters and worn-down thermal socks.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_3617&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignnone&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;1024&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-3617&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;03&#x2F;dan-gold-544435-unsplash-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;De-cluttering, Spring Cleaning, 300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Living, Downtown Winnipeg, Downtown Apartments&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; &#x2F;&gt; by Dan Gold from Unsplash[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clothes are one of the easiest things to collect and hoard within your home. Ask yourself, “Have I worn this in the past 6 months?” If you haven’t (be honest!) and there’s no sentimental value to it (like a wedding dress or your grandmother’s hand-knit sweater,) donate it. You’ll thank yourself later when looking for your favourite shirt doesn’t count as an arm workout.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are anything like me, you fear getting rid of stuff because you can’t help but think, “&lt;em&gt;But what if I need this later?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;” Trust me on this: You’re never going to need those hotel toiletries you snagged on your past six vacations, or that one phone charger that works when you place it just right—it’s time to toss ‘em!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Become Friends with your Countertops and Tables Again&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Flat surfaces in your apartment accumulate the most clutter because it’s just so easy to let things pile up. Remove every item from the surface, including decorations, appliances and all the haphazard junk. Lay everything out on a flat surface like another table (or even the floor), so you have a clear view of each item.
&lt;p&gt;An easy place to start is by throwing away all the random flyers, coupons and other non-important loose papers that tend to accumulate. Next, tackle things that spark more annoyance than joy, such as decorations you don’t remember buying.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve picked the items worthy of being on your counter or table, find a permanent home for them in a convenient and logical spot. Be selective of what you keep on your counters; you don’t need to have every single appliance on the counter! If you don’t use it every day, store it in a cabinet or on top of the fridge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Don’t Forget to Tackle the Junk Drawer&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Drawers are the first place you throw miscellaneous stuff into, especially when you’re quickly tidying up. I get it; out of sight, out of mind. But this spring, we’re reversing that mindset! The purpose of a junk drawer is to provide a place to store all the little odds and ends that don&#x27;t quite fit in anywhere else. This is still possible, but it can be done in a more intentional way.
&lt;p&gt;Toss anything that is expired, unnecessary or is just plain garbage. Keep extra batteries, packs of pens and chip clips, but get rid of extra chopsticks, expired coupons, and that stack of random business cards.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ready, Shreddy, Go!&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Paper junk can collect quickly, like old receipts, bank invoices or even more of those random business cards. Shredding these will clear up your office space.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_3623&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignright&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;576&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-3623&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;03&#x2F;felipe-bustillo-1176758-unsplash2-576x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;De-cluttering, Spring Cleaning, 300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Living, Downtown Winnipeg, Downtown Apartments&quot; width=&quot;576&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt; by Felipe Bustillo from Unsplash[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Collections of any Kinds Have to Go&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Items like books, CD’s or DVD’s can really pile up over the years. Ask yourself if these mementos are necessary, or just part of your past that you’re holding onto. It’s a brave, new virtual world, and most of us don’t even have CD&#x2F;DVD players any more thanks to Netflix. So why are you wasting space for stacks of CDs from the early 2000s?
&lt;p&gt;The same thing goes for books. It might be nice to look like a bookworm when your friends pop by, but you know they’re mostly just taking up space. This doesn’t mean you have to give up every book but ask yourself if you’ll really ever read it again. If you won’t, donate it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick Tip: Donate your books to newcomer organizations (such as N.E.E.D.S) or a senior living facility!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Be Ruthless&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Getting rid of stuff in your home is difficult at first because we create connections with items. But, once you get the hang of it, you’ll wonder why you didn’t tackle it sooner!
&lt;h3&gt;Organize the Rest&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Decluttering isn’t just about getting rid of stuff; it’s also about knowing how to manage what you have. From racks, baskets, or under-bed storage, there’s an assortment of storage products for every need on the market.
&lt;h3&gt;Out of Sight, Out of Mind&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
A forgotten place that is one of the most convenient storage spaces is hiding out under your bed. Grab a few thin, narrow bins and you have the perfect place to store out of season clothes, booksyou want to keep but don’t need on your shelf, or any mish-mashed items that don’t seem to have a place but that you know you need.
&lt;p&gt;Shelving units are also a great way to kill two birds with one stone: Grab a few baskets and tuck away all those miscellaneous items such as cords or craft supplies. Your shelves will look neat and aesthetically pleasing, and what they hold is your little secret.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Celebrate!&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Now that your hard work is over, sit back and celebrate Apartment 2.0! Now your mission is to keep your home decluttered. Remember to follow the golden rule: Only bring things into your home that you actually need and will use. Once your apartment is decluttered, it’s easy to follow into old habits and end up buying more stuff you don’t need.
&lt;p&gt;Before bringing something new into your home, ask yourself, “Do I need this? How will this benefit my home?” If you can’t answer both questions, don’t buy it. Another great trick is the one in, one out rule. For every item that comes into your apartment, try to get rid of one item so you don’t end up with a cluttered apartment once again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tips might seem ambitious, but you can do it! And once you see how freeing it can feel to have less &lt;em&gt;stuff&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; around you, you’ll be kicking yourself for not starting sooner. What’s your personal decluttering challenge?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Surviving the Roommate Experience</title>
		<published>2019-01-24T11:00:15+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-01-24T11:00:15+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/surviving-the-roommate-experience/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/surviving-the-roommate-experience/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While most of us love the idea of having our own space to do exactly what we want in, the reality is that living alone can be expensive. It can also be lonely, so some of us choose to have roommates for companionship. Whatever your reasons might be, living with roommates can be a lovely—or disastrous—experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Good&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Splitting living costs means you have more money for other things. You can also create great memories with roommates. I’ve had roomies off and on in my life, particularly in my university years. One of my favourite aspects of living with others is the meshing of traditions and cultures around the holidays. One year, three of us celebrated Christmas and two celebrated Hanukkah. We decided to mash everything together and made a Chrismukkah tree. It was a traditional Christmas evergreen tree, but we covered it in blue and silver decorations (the colours of Hannukah) and used a big Star of David as a tree topper. It was fun watching the roomies who’d never had a tree try to figure out how to hang balls and baubles, as those little squeezable hooks aren’t really used for anything but Christmas decorations. We also got to teach our roommates all of the lyrics to cheesy Christmas songs. And later that school year, I learned how to celebrate Passover. We always enjoyed our combined holiday events.
&lt;p&gt;Being students, we had lots of silly drunken nights and sometimes came up with imaginative solutions to our problems. We had been given a TV by one set of parents, but it had no remote control. We were entirely too lazy to get up and change the channel, so one night we found some duct tape and taped all of our wooden spoons and spatulas together in a long line that reached from the couch to the TV. It served as a handy, and remarkably sturdy, remote control for the rest of the year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And having roommates means there is often someone there to talk to and do things with without having to schedule plans days in advance, which is a nice bonus.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Bad&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Having roomies isn’t always idyllic. Living with others is often fraught with annoyances and drama. One of the most common fights is over cleanliness, or lack thereof. I’m sure our bathrooms were teeming with germs, as no one ever wanted to clean them. We had the same problem with dishes. No one ever believed it was their turn to wash, so the dishes just piled up in the sink in ever-teetering towers.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_2955&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;900&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2955&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;01&#x2F;rawpixel-804799-unsplash-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;dirty dishes, dirty kitchen, messy kitchen. apartment living, living with roommates, roomies, winnipeg apartments, 300 Main apartments, downtown winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;612&quot; &#x2F;&gt; ? by rawpixel on Unsplash[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your best bet to avoid similar problems is to have a conversation with your roomies right at the start, to decide what is and isn’t acceptable for everyone. You may also want to create a chore schedule so everyone knows exactly who will be doing what and by when.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another issue can be sharing food or other resources. You should decide right away if you are sharing food or keeping things completely separate. This does not guarantee success, by the way. We had one roommate in university (I’m calling her Jane to protect the guilty) who never bought her own food and pilfered from everyone else when we weren’t around. It wasn’t something we were able to successfully stop, and it was one of the reasons she ended up moving out before the year was up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Ugly&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Some problems grow from small to breathtakingly bad. We had one roommate (surprisingly, not Jane) come back from summer break in second year with a large package in tow. She worked on her parents’ travelling carnival every summer. That year, she had fallen for a 6’8” carny and decided to bring him back to university with her. He was supposed to stay a few days, maybe a week or two, before finding his own place. He never left. He spent the entire year living with us, moving from job to job, and never contributed anything towards rent or utilities. It was an ongoing fight all year to get him to pay up or move out, but we didn’t get the big mooch to leave until we all moved out at the end of the school year.
&lt;p&gt;Most roommate situations don’t turn out this badly, but it’s important to know something about the person you are living with and to set clear ground rules from the start. It’s no fun if you suddenly find yourself in need of a new living situation because things have become untenable at home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;And the Downright Weird&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Some roommate situations just become weird. Like Jane, who had a revolving door of friends constantly in our apartment. It’s a little disconcerting to walk into your bathroom at 7 am and find some guy you’ve never met before passed out over your toilet. (Hello, awkward conversation.)
&lt;p&gt;In our student apartment building, people regularly set off the fire alarm with burned popcorn and toast. But when Jane decided it would be a great idea to butt a cigarette into a wastebasket full of paper, the ensuing full-fledged fire didn’t set off the alarms until our apartment was fully consumed by smoke. Most of the damage was contained to her room, but the entire apartment had a distinctly smoky smell for weeks after. I guess my tip here is to choose your roommates wisely.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bottom Line&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
[caption id=&quot;attachment_2957&quot; align=&quot;aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;900&quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2957&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;01&#x2F;kelly-sikkema-411622-unsplash-1024x678.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sticky notes, delegating, tasks, communication, assertive, apartment living, downtown Winnipeg, 300 Main Apartments&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;596&quot; &#x2F;&gt; ? by Kelly Sikkema on Unsplash[&#x2F;caption]
&lt;p&gt;There are benefits and drawbacks both to living alone and with others. You need to pick the option that best works for you. If you have roommates, spend a little time making the right choice or you could spend a lot of time regretting it. Set clear ground rules and expectations, and be prepared to have frank discussions when things don’t run smoothly. This happens sometimes, even with great roommates. And if you have some bad experiences, remind yourself they make great fodder for party stories later. (And share them below!)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Creative Ways to Control Kitchen Clutter</title>
		<published>2018-12-06T11:00:49+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-12-06T11:00:49+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/creative-ways-to-control-kitchen-clutter/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/creative-ways-to-control-kitchen-clutter/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Is your kitchen bursting at the seams? Don’t hide from your culinary creativity because of a mess! Here are five ways to keep your kitchen from looking like a hurricane made landfall in your cupboards.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Learn to love your Tupperware&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
The dreaded Tupperware cupboard: we all have one. Despite the mysterious lids and tumbling bottoms, tackling this beast doesn’t need to be intimidating. For a smooth post-dinner clean-up, invest in a simple file organizer. Yes—the file organizer on your desk can be put to work in your kitchen, too. Slide lids in one organizer and containers in another to make packing up leftovers a cinch.
&lt;h3&gt;2. High rise&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Don’t compromise your charming mug collection just because you’re short on storage. Get the most out of the space you have by thinking vertical! Adding a shelf riser is a quick fix that lets you store more by instantly turning one shelf into two. With all that extra space, why not see what &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.tinyfeast.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Tiny Feast&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has in stock to add to your collection?
&lt;h3&gt;3. Stash away your sprays&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
The cupboard under the sink—also known as the “I’ll just throw it under there” shelf—is an organizing challenge. Finding that one particular kitchen cleaner can be easy with a little creativity: buy a tension rod (the kind you use to hang a shower curtain) and install it under the cupboard. Hook sprays on the rod to create more room on the bottom shelf for “unhangables,” such as garbage bags. For bonus points, pare your collection down to one or two earth-friendly alternatives from &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;generationgreenwpg.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Generation Green&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;h3&gt;4. Double-duty backsplash&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
When it comes to organizing your kitchen, don’t let space goes to waste. Lean a square of pegboard against the back wall of your kitchen counter. Simply insert hooks into the board and hang the tools you use most often to keep them handy. This customizable option can be used for measuring cups, spatulas, and even whisks.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_573&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;682&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-573 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;11&#x2F;calum-lewis-387582-unsplash-682x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hanging Cups, Organizing Kitchen, 300 Main Apartments&quot; width=&quot;682&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt; Photo by Calum Lewis from Unsplash[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5. Stickin’ your spices&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Cooking a meal can feel intimidating when you’re fumbling through your cabinet of toppling jars, bags, and containers of spices. Head to the nearby dollar store to purchase small glass jars and magnets. With a little bit of hot glue, your made-for-the-counter jars can become fridge magnets. Fill them up with your favourite spices for an easy way to grab cinnamon or oregano while minimizing cabinet clutter.
&lt;p&gt;Storage spaces and gadgets don’t need to be used the way they were intended to be; with a bit of imagination, you can make your kitchen a welcoming place to whip up your favourite meals! Feeling inspired to get the rest of your home in shipshape? Gather ideas by browsing &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;hutk.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;HutK&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;’s collection of beautiful furniture that doubles as clever storage.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your favourite ways to make your kitchen an inviting place to cook?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
