<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Home - Living at 300Main Downtown Winnipeg - natural-tile-cleaner</title>
	<subtitle>We all love 300Main</subtitle>
	<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/natural-tile-cleaner/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2019-07-24T15:42:08+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/natural-tile-cleaner/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How to Make Your Own Natural Cleaning Supplies</title>
		<published>2019-07-24T15:42:08+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-07-24T15:42:08+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/how-to-make-your-own-natural-cleaning-supplies/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/how-to-make-your-own-natural-cleaning-supplies/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cleaning your home naturally is no more difficult that cleaning it with harsh chemicals. In fact, homemade cleaning supplies are better for your wallet, last longer, and help keep toxins out of your downtown oasis! Here are some of my favourite homemade cleaning supply formulas.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s start with where the most messes appear: the kitchen.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;All-Purpose Cleaner&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
½ cup white vinegar 2 tablespoons baking soda 10 drops tea tree, lavender, or lemon essential oil (for their disinfectant properties)
&lt;p&gt;Mix the vinegar, essential oils and a little water before adding baking soda in a clean spray bottle (glass is best). Fill to the top with water. I use about a 12-ounce bottle. Gently shake to mix the ingredients, and then spray, wipe with a cloth, and allow to dry.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2955&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;01&#x2F;rawpixel-804799-unsplash-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;dirty dishes, dirty kitchen, messy kitchen. apartment living, living with roommates, roomies, winnipeg apartments, 300 Main apartments, downtown winnipeg, natural cleaning products, winnipeg, downtown living, cleaning products winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;1021&quot; height=&quot;694&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Liquid Dish Soap&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
½ cup distilled water
&lt;p&gt;1 tablespoon white vinegar&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;½ cup Sal Suds (find it at most health food stores or Walmart)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 tablespoon moisturizing oil, such as coconut or olive&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour the water and vinegar into a bottle. Shake to mix, and then add the Sal Suds and oil. Gently shake the bottle again to combine the ingredients.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Homemade Drain Cleaner&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
½ cup baking soda
&lt;p&gt;¼ cup white vinegar&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sprinkle baking soda down the clogged or smelly drain, then pour in the vinegar. Let the bubbling mixture sit for an hour or so, then pour boiling hot water down the drain to rinse. Depending on how clogged the drain is, you may need to repeat the process. If you clean your drain regularly, you’ll find that one dose will keep things clear.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now let’s move on to the bathroom!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-5456&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;07&#x2F;daiga-ellaby-uooMllXe6gE-unsplash-683x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Homemade cleaning products, natural cleaning products, cleaning products winnipeg, winnipeg apartment living, downtown winnipeg living, apartment living&quot; width=&quot;683&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tub and Tile Cleaner&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
12 ounces white vinegar
&lt;p&gt;12 ounces dish soap (I usually use Dawn)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heat vinegar in the microwave until hot and then pour into the spray bottle. Add the dish soap, put the lid on, gently shake and you are ready to clean! To get rid of soap scum, spray the mixture on and leave it to sit overnight.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Toilet Cleaner &lt;em&gt;(This is going to sound a bit odd. Just hear me out!)&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
1 can Coca Cola
&lt;p&gt;1 cup baking soda&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 cup white distilled vinegar&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dump the Coca Cola into the toilet and let it sit for 10-15 minutes, then flush. Add the vinegar and the baking soda to the toilet next (without stirring or scrubbing) and wait until the mixture stops bubbling. Scrub any tough stains, otherwise just flush and you’re done! The soda and the vinegar&#x2F;baking-soda mixture will also help to keep the pipes clear of buildup.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But what about carpets or stinky smells that linger around your house?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Homemade Air Freshener&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
15 drops pure essential oil (grapefruit and lavender are my favourite!)
&lt;p&gt;½ cup white vinegar&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;½ cup water&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combine ingredients in a spray bottle and shake. Spray liberally around your home to freshen things up!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Carpet Cleaner&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
1 cup white vinegar
&lt;p&gt;2 cups water 2 teaspoons salt 15 drops lavender essential oil or another clear, pure essential oil of choice&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combine vinegar and water in a large spray bottle. Add in salt and lavender essential oil; close the cap and shake bottle. Spray on carpets where needed and allow carpets to air-dry. Once dry, vacuum the treated areas and enjoy a carpet that looks brand-spanking new!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And finally, the laundry room.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-5460&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;07&#x2F;laundry-4017609_1920-1024x681.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Homemade cleaning products, natural cleaning products, cleaning products winnipeg, winnipeg apartment living, downtown winnipeg living, apartment living&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;681&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Liquid Laundry Detergent&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
½ cup Borax
&lt;p&gt;½ cup washing soda (I use Arm &amp;amp; Hammer Super Washing Soda Laundry Booster)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;½ cup Dawn dish soap&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 cups hot water&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combine the Borax, washing soda, and Dawn soap into a clean, empty gallon plastic jug (use a funnel to get it all in without a mess). Fill the container to the top with cold water to help the ingredients to dissolve. Shake before use. ½ cup should be enough for a regular sized load!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Stain Remover&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
2&#x2F;3 cup Dawn dish detergent
&lt;p&gt;2&#x2F;3 cup ammonia&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6 tablespoons baking soda&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 cups warm water&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mix ingredients in a bowl before pouring the mixture into a spray bottle. Spray onto the stain and let it rest for a minute or two. Launder normally.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share your favourite natural cleaning recipe with us below!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
