<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Home - Living at 300Main Downtown Winnipeg - kitchen-organizing</title>
	<subtitle>We all love 300Main</subtitle>
	<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/kitchen-organizing/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2019-08-09T21:05:13+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/kitchen-organizing/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How to Maximize Your Tiny Kitchen</title>
		<published>2019-08-09T21:05:13+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-08-09T21:05:13+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/how-to-maximize-your-tiny-kitchen/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/how-to-maximize-your-tiny-kitchen/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My kitchen is tiny. So tiny that guests will walk through it and ask, “Where’s the rest of it?” But I don’t let the size of my kitchen make me shy away from cooking! I’m a foodie, but most importantly, a foodie on a budget—so I cook most of my meals at home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why I Love Cooking&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Over the years, I’ve fallen in love with cooking. I walk into my kitchen and the possibilities feel endless! My favourite way to cook is with no plan or recipe. In the kitchen there are no rules, and I love that. In school, work, and even my hobbies I always feel pressure to be creative in a certain way; but cooking is a different kind of creativity, and I can create without limitations!
&lt;p&gt;And because I love cooking so much, I don’t let my small kitchen prevent me from cooking up a storm. Here are some of my favourite ways to use my space!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-5630&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;08&#x2F;hanging-kitchen-kitchen-utensils-211760-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Small kitchen, Organizing Kitchen, 300 Main Apartments, Kitchen Interiors, Kitchen Clutter, Kitchen utensils&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Stacking&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Stacking is your best friend with a tiny kitchen. My kitchen is what some might call an organized mess. As soon as you walk into my space, you’re greeted by my microwave underneath my coffee maker, which is tucked up against my slow cooker, which has three cookbooks stacked neatly on top. Small kitchens usually don’t have room for much horizontal space, but what about vertical space? Start by stacking items that you don’t tend to grab as much, and then stack items that you frequently use together. Not only will you save space, but you’ll also know which stack to pull things from when you’re in a time crunch rather than running around trying to find your food processer or a cookbook.
&lt;h3&gt;2. Clean as You Go&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Cleaning as you go is a crucial habit for cooking in a small space. You cannot use your space to its fullest potential with pots and food scrapes taking over half of your counter space! This tip is basic, but a total game changer.
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: none; overflow: hidden;&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;plugins&#x2F;post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2F300MainWinnipeg%2Fposts%2F1497982703677591&amp;amp;width=500&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;573&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Use ALL Your Space&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Utilizing all your space is also a key component to enlarging your kitchen. Try placing a cutting board over your stove top or an open drawer. Use your kitchen table as a prep space or place one of your larger cutting boards over your sink to make extra counter space. Get creative. Just because it isn’t a countertop doesn’t mean it can’t function like one!
&lt;h3&gt;4. Look Up for Utensil Storage&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Store your utensils up high! I’m very particular about where my utensils go. I recommend that anyone who does a lot of cooking in a small kitchen store their most used utensils, pots, and pans on hooks. If possible, a shallow cubby is a great space to store utensils. I find it very stressful to rifle through drawers in search of my whisk or a medium frying pan. By displaying a few of your most crucial cooking tools, you set yourself up for success!
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: none; overflow: hidden;&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;plugins&#x2F;post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2F300MainWinnipeg%2Fposts%2F1510041235805071&amp;amp;width=500&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;491&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kitchen Appliances I Can Vouch For&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Every birthday and holiday, it seems like a new kitchen appliance is at the top of my list! Here are some of my favourite kitchen appliances that are a must for those of us with limited space.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mini Food Processor&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mini food processor is an essential! Not only is this contraption small, but it’s also a great tool for chopping up food quickly. It saves you so much counter space over clunky cutting boards.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slow Cooker&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slow cookers solve all our problems, honestly. They’re a necessity for those who dread coming home and cooking dinner after their 9-to-5. Just pop in your ingredients in the morning, leave it for the day and boom, a hot meal to welcome you home!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coffee Maker&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good ol’ coffee maker is a must for us downtowners—it’s just a way of life! I have both a coffee maker and an espresso maker, but coffee for me is a lifestyle more than a drink. I think a standard coffee maker is a necessity for all kitchens. Nowadays, they’re so compact they don’t take up much room in your kitchen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rolling Cart&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While not exactly an appliance, a rolling cart is life-changing! I bought mine from Ikea for $35, but the amount of use I get out of it makes it priceless in my book. I mainly use it to store ingredients and utensils that I need while cooking but don’t have the counter space for. The best part is, once I am done with it I can roll it into a corner and it’s out of my way!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Got any other small kitchen tips and tricks? Let us know in the comments below!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Creative Ways to Control Kitchen Clutter</title>
		<published>2018-12-06T11:00:49+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-12-06T11:00:49+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/creative-ways-to-control-kitchen-clutter/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/creative-ways-to-control-kitchen-clutter/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Is your kitchen bursting at the seams? Don’t hide from your culinary creativity because of a mess! Here are five ways to keep your kitchen from looking like a hurricane made landfall in your cupboards.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Learn to love your Tupperware&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
The dreaded Tupperware cupboard: we all have one. Despite the mysterious lids and tumbling bottoms, tackling this beast doesn’t need to be intimidating. For a smooth post-dinner clean-up, invest in a simple file organizer. Yes—the file organizer on your desk can be put to work in your kitchen, too. Slide lids in one organizer and containers in another to make packing up leftovers a cinch.
&lt;h3&gt;2. High rise&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Don’t compromise your charming mug collection just because you’re short on storage. Get the most out of the space you have by thinking vertical! Adding a shelf riser is a quick fix that lets you store more by instantly turning one shelf into two. With all that extra space, why not see what &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.tinyfeast.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Tiny Feast&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has in stock to add to your collection?
&lt;h3&gt;3. Stash away your sprays&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
The cupboard under the sink—also known as the “I’ll just throw it under there” shelf—is an organizing challenge. Finding that one particular kitchen cleaner can be easy with a little creativity: buy a tension rod (the kind you use to hang a shower curtain) and install it under the cupboard. Hook sprays on the rod to create more room on the bottom shelf for “unhangables,” such as garbage bags. For bonus points, pare your collection down to one or two earth-friendly alternatives from &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;generationgreenwpg.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Generation Green&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;h3&gt;4. Double-duty backsplash&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
When it comes to organizing your kitchen, don’t let space goes to waste. Lean a square of pegboard against the back wall of your kitchen counter. Simply insert hooks into the board and hang the tools you use most often to keep them handy. This customizable option can be used for measuring cups, spatulas, and even whisks.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_573&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;682&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-573 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;11&#x2F;calum-lewis-387582-unsplash-682x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hanging Cups, Organizing Kitchen, 300 Main Apartments&quot; width=&quot;682&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt; Photo by Calum Lewis from Unsplash[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5. Stickin’ your spices&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Cooking a meal can feel intimidating when you’re fumbling through your cabinet of toppling jars, bags, and containers of spices. Head to the nearby dollar store to purchase small glass jars and magnets. With a little bit of hot glue, your made-for-the-counter jars can become fridge magnets. Fill them up with your favourite spices for an easy way to grab cinnamon or oregano while minimizing cabinet clutter.
&lt;p&gt;Storage spaces and gadgets don’t need to be used the way they were intended to be; with a bit of imagination, you can make your kitchen a welcoming place to whip up your favourite meals! Feeling inspired to get the rest of your home in shipshape? Gather ideas by browsing &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;hutk.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;HutK&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;’s collection of beautiful furniture that doubles as clever storage.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your favourite ways to make your kitchen an inviting place to cook?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
