<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Home - Living at 300Main Downtown Winnipeg - experience-winnipeg</title>
	<subtitle>We all love 300Main</subtitle>
	<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/experience-winnipeg/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2019-02-13T17:24:06+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/experience-winnipeg/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Valentine’s Day in Winnipeg’s Heart</title>
		<published>2019-02-13T17:24:06+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-02-13T17:24:06+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/valentines-day-in-winnipegs-heart/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/valentines-day-in-winnipegs-heart/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With Valentine&#x27;s day around the corner, it never hurts to plan a little something special for your darling. The typical breakfast in bed, dozen red roses and heart-shaped box of chocolates are all fine and dandy, but we can do better. This year, pump up the creativity, explore Winnipeg&#x27;s downtown and surrounding areas, and leave your partner speechless!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;manitobamuseum.ca&#x2F;main&#x2F;event&#x2F;after-hours-wild-romance&#x2F;&quot;&gt;After Hours: Wild Romance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
The &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;manitobamuseum.ca&#x2F;main&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Manitoba Museum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; isn’t the first place that comes to mind when I think romance, but throw in some sensual Argentinian tango, a signature drink, and seriously &lt;em&gt;wild&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; activities, and voilà: a modern-day Valentine&#x27;s celebration! Over the course of the evening, enjoy scavenger’s hunts, beer tastings with &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;littlebrownjug.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Little Brown Jug&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and pop-up talks. But these aren’t your average panel discussions; the talk themes are &quot;all things horn-y&quot; and &quot;plants just wanna have sex.&quot; (Get your mind out of the gutter—the talks are about wildlife, not humans!)
&lt;p&gt;This wild night is perfect for friends, couples, and singles looking for a new spin on a beloved night. It’ll be a night of unexpected fun, romance, and good bites with delicious drinks. The best part? It&#x27;s a short walk away from &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;300 Main&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. Winnipeg&#x27;s ultimate sports night&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Looking for the ultimate Winnipeg experience? What is more Winnipeg than grabbing a beer or wine and great seats to a live hockey game? On cupids chosen day, you can score yourself tickets to the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www1.ticketmaster.ca&#x2F;winnipeg-jets-vs-colorado-avalanche-winnipeg-manitoba-02-14-2019&#x2F;event&#x2F;1100550D92A2396A?dma_id=530&amp;amp;brand=nhl&amp;amp;wt.mc_id=NHL_TEAM_WIN_WEB_MIG&amp;amp;utm_source=NHL.com&amp;amp;utm_medium=client&amp;amp;utm_campaign=NHL_TEAM_WIN&amp;amp;utm_content=WEB_MIG&quot;&gt;Winnipeg Jets vs Colorado Avalanche&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. If your partner is the ultimate Jets fan, give them a gift they’ll truly cherish by spending a memorable night screaming &quot;GO JETS GO!” For some pre-game fun, think outside of the box: present your sweetie with Jets gear, stick-on tattoos and tickets to that night’s game. On your walk to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bellmtsplace.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;BellMTS Place&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, surprise your date with dinner at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.carbonecafeclub.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Carbone Cafe Club&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (who’s up for recreating &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=1nWNXO3CZkU&quot;&gt;Lady and The Tramp’s pasta kiss&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;?), or grab some apps at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;moxies.com&#x2F;restaurant-locations&#x2F;manitoba&#x2F;winnipeg-MTS-place&quot;&gt;Moxie&#x27;s&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Winnipeg&#x27;s downtown is filled with restaurants to suit everyone&#x27;s palate.
&lt;p&gt;Check out some recommendations on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;where-to-stop-for-a-nightcap-after-a-jets-game&#x2F;&quot;&gt;where to stop for a nightcap after a Jets game&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_3106&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;500&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;where-to-stop-for-a-nightcap-after-a-jets-game&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-3106&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;02&#x2F;Where-to-Stop-for-a-Nightcap-After-a-Jets-Game_v2-300x200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Where to Stop for a Nightcap After a Jets Game&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Read blog: Where to stop for a nightcap after a Jets game[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. The Classic Valentine&#x27;s day: Dinner &amp;amp; a Movie at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.themetwinnipeg.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the Met&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Is your partner the ultimate romantic that loves to be swept off their feet? The original 1942 black and white version of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.imdb.com&#x2F;title&#x2F;tt0034583&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Casablanca&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; will be showing at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.themetwinnipeg.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the Metropolitan Entertainment Center&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. One of Winnipeg&#x27;s national historic sites, originally built in 1919, the Met opened as a grand theatre to entertain the masses during cinema&#x27;s height of film. The Met now boasts a 35-foot screen—so any seat in the house is a good one—and elegant furnishings. This is not your average movie date: pre-movie, you’ll be wined and dined with the Mets’ signature buffet; during the movie, you’ll enjoy hot-off-the-press buttery popcorn. Does your average &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.urbandictionary.com&#x2F;define.php?term=netflix%20and%20chill&quot;&gt;Netflix and chill&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; session come with an intermission to delight your senses with coffee and dessert?&lt;em&gt; I don’t think so&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. Create your own “We’ll always have Paris” moment and get carried away on all the romance in the air.
&lt;h3&gt;4. A little winter &lt;em&gt;amour&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Living in Winnipeg, we’re lucky enough to have to picturesque winter backdrop that emanates that cozy, idealistic fairy-tale feeling. Valentine&#x27;s Day is smack-dab in the middle of the best part of our winters, so some of the best outdoor activities are available—including ice skating at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theforks.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Forks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theforks.com&#x2F;events&#x2F;red-river-mutual-trail&quot;&gt;The Red River Mutual Trail&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; currently &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cbc.ca&#x2F;news&#x2F;canada&#x2F;manitoba&#x2F;guinness-gives-official-nod-to-winnipeg-skating-trail-1.740139&quot;&gt;holds the Guinness record&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for the longest naturally frozen skating trail in the world.
&lt;p&gt;Share a piece of Winnipeg&#x27;s history with your special someone and capture the moment with The Forks’ many selfie-worthy spots. Picture yourself holding your date&#x27;s hand while floating down the trail under the stars, enjoying the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.warminghuts.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;warming huts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; brought to Winnipeg by architects from all over the world, hanging out under the magical lit walkway, and gliding across the historic rail bridge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little history + some fresh air + Winnipeg&#x27;s beloved pass time = authentic Winnipeg romance. Don&#x27;t end your evening on the trail: head over to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theforks.com&#x2F;attractions&#x2F;the-forks-market-plaza&quot;&gt;The Forks Market&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for some &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theforks.com&#x2F;eat-and-drink&#x2F;dine&quot;&gt;food and a drink&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to wrap up the evening.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5. Sweet Tooth delight&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
If your date has a serious sweet tooth, why not gift them with a personalized tour of Winnipeg&#x27;s sweet spots? You don&#x27;t have to venture far to satisfy their every craving! Let&#x27;s start our delightful date at &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;constancepopp.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Chocolatier Constance Popp&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with some chocolate marshmallow puffs. This no ordinary chocolate shop: Constance Popp displays each piece of decadent chocolate with beautiful artistry and creativity. Next, head over to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.chocoberrydesserthouse.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Chocoberry Dessert House&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for something savoury; my recommendation is the Salted Caramel S&#x27;mores Dip.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_3104&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;683&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-3104&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;02&#x2F;04-683x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chocolatier Constance Popp, Valentine Day, 300 Main Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;683&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt; Shot by author, Reanna Khan[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up is one of Winnipeg&#x27;s coveted gourmet doughnut shops, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ohdoughnuts.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Oh Doughnuts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Whether you try a classic Boston cream or the Valentine’s specials, each flavour is delightful and activates every taste bud on your tongue. Continue the night at local favourite cake bakery, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bakedexpectations.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Baked Expectations&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Their cake display will dazzle your eyes, satisfy your cravings—and make you unbutton the top of your jeans. This fun, sugar-filled adventure will take you and your partner to old favourites to create new memories!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winnipeg&#x27;s downtown and surrounding areas will thrill you with new events, undiscovered favourites, and romantic hot spots. Whether you’re looking for a little romance, an intense hockey game, a sweet-tooth adventure or a &lt;em&gt;wild&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; night out, downtown has it all. A little creativity and the right partner or friend are the perfect recipe for your most memorable Valentine&#x27;s Day yet! How are you spending this V-Day?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
