<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Home - Living at 300Main Downtown Winnipeg - windy-city</title>
	<subtitle>We all love 300Main</subtitle>
	<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/windy-city/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2019-11-21T21:41:11+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/windy-city/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Bigger is Greener: The Environmental Benefits of High-Density Housing</title>
		<published>2019-11-21T21:41:11+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-11-21T21:41:11+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/bigger-is-greener-the-environmental-benefits-of-high-density-housing/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/bigger-is-greener-the-environmental-benefits-of-high-density-housing/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Canadians are increasingly &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.macleans.ca&#x2F;news&#x2F;canada&#x2F;census-2016-a-picture-of-a-bigger-more-urban-canada&#x2F;&quot;&gt;living in cities&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;canadapopulation.org&#x2F;winnipeg-population&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Winnipeg is no exception&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It can sometimes be hard for communities with fast-growing populations to keep up with the infrastructure needs for new residents. That’s why many cities are gravitating towards more high-density housing as part of their “&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.smartcitiesdive.com&#x2F;ex&#x2F;sustainablecitiescollective&#x2F;urban-density-and-sustainability&#x2F;241696&#x2F;&quot;&gt;smart growth&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;” strategies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is High-Density Housing?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
High-density housing simply is housing that packs more people per geographic unit. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;300 Main&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a 40-storey apartment building that will be home to several hundred city dwellers. Communities that are urbanizing sometimes encourage developers to add higher-density complexes to their downtown areas. There are many advantages to these tall multiplexes.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_6065&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;1024&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-6065&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;Final_C2-1024x775.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Apartment Buildings, Apartments in Winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;775&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; 3D Rendering of 300 Main[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Higher-density neighbourhoods have a strong sense of community and connectedness because people are just in closer contact with each other. High-density housing usually entails high-rise buildings such as 300 Main. Higher population density is essential for &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.huffingtonpost.ca&#x2F;ypnexthome&#x2F;high-density-housing-gta_b_17208346.html&quot;&gt;developing busy, vivacious neighbourhoods&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with lots of features. It allows for beautiful public spaces like downtown Winnipeg to make life convenient, enjoyable and, most importantly, green!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sustainable Design&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
As cities &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;canada.constructconnect.com&#x2F;dcn&#x2F;news&#x2F;economic&#x2F;2019&#x2F;04&#x2F;canadas-major-cities-ride-slipstream-surging-population-growth&quot;&gt;boom in population&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and invest to meet the needs of their new citizens, sustainability has also become a major focus. High-rise apartments are one of the easiest ways to make a community more sustainable. They have a smaller footprint than that of many smaller buildings.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_6069&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;680&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-6069&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;apartment-architectural-design-architecture-bridge-1152849-3-680x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Apartment Buildings, Apartments in Winnipeg, Chicago, High Rise Buildings in Chicago, High Rise Apartments in Chicago&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt; Chicago, United States by Cameron Casey from Pexels[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If neighbourhoods want to continue to grow, all they need to do is look up! Building up, or even on top of, is &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.citylab.com&#x2F;equity&#x2F;2012&#x2F;01&#x2F;why-most-environmental-building-building-weve-already-built&#x2F;1016&#x2F;&quot;&gt;more environmentally-friendly&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; than conventional demolished-site redevelopment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Size Matters (For Energy)&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Denser neighbourhoods that include apartment blocks or condos also use less energy. Residences that are stacked or bunched should &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ottawacitizen.com&#x2F;life&#x2F;homes&#x2F;modern-housing-why-highrises-are-good-for-the-environment&quot;&gt;use less energy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. For example, an apartment suite in 300 Main is more efficient to heat and cool than a detached suburban house. So even on cold winter nights (which us Winnipeggers know sometimes start in October), if every apartment suite were to turn their heat up, they’d be using less energy than the equivalent number of houses. Higher-density neighbourhoods also &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cbsnews.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;trying-to-reduce-your-carbon-footprint-dont-fall-for-these-myths&#x2F;&quot;&gt;create fewer harmful emissions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. As &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.citylab.com&#x2F;life&#x2F;2012&#x2F;04&#x2F;why-bigger-cities-are-greener&#x2F;863&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Richard Florida at CityLab&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; says, “When it comes to greenness, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;martinprosperity.org&#x2F;insights&#x2F;insight&#x2F;cities-and-co2-bigger-is-better&quot;&gt;size matters&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.”
&lt;h3&gt;Encourages more Walking, Cycling and Use of Public Transportation&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Though downtown areas can seem busy, there are major benefits to living and working downtown. Dense downtown neighbourhoods help residents drive less and walk more, without giving up their lifestyles. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.fastcompany.com&#x2F;40492045&#x2F;living-in-a-dense-city-makes-citizens-healthier&quot;&gt;Research&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has shown that lower density promotes sedentary behavior. If your home is far away from the grocery store and your office, you’re going to spend more time in a car and less time being active.
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;getting-around-winnipeg-without-a-car-yes-its-possible&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High-density housing encourages walking and cycling &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cbsnews.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;trying-to-reduce-your-carbon-footprint-dont-fall-for-these-myths&#x2F;&quot;&gt;because everything is closer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; together! Transit is also promoted by high-density housing, as transit connections become more common when neighborhood density increases. Many city dwellers find it more convenient to jump on a transit bus and be at work in a stress-free jiffy, rather than drive to work, deal with traffic, and find parking. Talk about a headache!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individuals who live in suburban areas can also benefit from people taking transit to work. Fewer cars on the road equal fewer harmful emissions, like carbon dioxide.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What’s Big, Green, and Sustainable?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
High-density housing is a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theguardian.com&#x2F;environment&#x2F;georgemonbiot&#x2F;2011&#x2F;jun&#x2F;30&#x2F;sustainable-cities-urban-planning&quot;&gt;sustainable choice&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for growing cities. Tall buildings are more than just towers of concrete and steel; they’re a fundamental part of successful urbanization. They offer a greener, less wasteful, and more energy-efficient way of life.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_6072&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;954&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-6072&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;vehicles-on-road-between-high-rise-buildings-1525612-954x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Apartment Buildings, Apartments in Winnipeg, New York, New York Apartment Buildings&quot; width=&quot;954&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt; New York, United States by Craig Adderley from Pexels[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Winnipeg As Little Chicago</title>
		<published>2019-04-02T16:00:09+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-04-02T16:00:09+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/winnipeg-as-little-chicago/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/winnipeg-as-little-chicago/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When Winnipeg finally introduced itself to me, it was not the first time I had been to the city. The very first time I had been to Winnipeg was on a cold December afternoon when my family moved from Russia to Canada. Our friends met us at the airport, and we drove straight from the airport to a small city just south of Winnipeg. Winnipeg and I didn&#x27;t get a chance to get to know each other yet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next few times when I visited Winnipeg with friends, we mainly went shopping at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cfshops.com&#x2F;polo-park.html&quot;&gt;Polo Park&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. To really get to know the city, you need to get out and explore its oldest parts. You must open your eyes to seeing history, and your ears to hearing what the city wants to tell you. That is exactly what happened to me when I came back to Winnipeg with a pile of documents to apply to college.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That morning, my sister and I had one specific mission: to explore. We got Starbucks and started our walk from the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.fairmont.com&#x2F;winnipeg&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Fairmont Hotel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on Portage Avenue, through the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.exchangedistrict.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Exchange District&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and back to Portage Avenue. I was lifting my eyes, trying to catch architectural details on buildings like the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mhs.mb.ca&#x2F;docs&#x2F;sites&#x2F;unionbankbuilding.shtml&quot;&gt;Union Bank on Main Street&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;pantagesplayhouse.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Pantages Playhouse Theatre&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on Market Street, the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mhs.mb.ca&#x2F;docs&#x2F;sites&#x2F;maltesecrossbuilding.shtml&quot;&gt;Maltese Cross Building&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on King Street, and others. I was enjoying the fresh summer morning air and a strong feeling of familiarity that was pressing on me from all sides. It was a long walk, but that morning something hit me. It was &lt;em&gt;déjà vu&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; feeling that I had already been in this place before. I felt like I&#x27;d seen it before, and not just once.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_3876&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;819&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BSe9ybtBCjl&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-3876 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;04&#x2F;by-arianneyuson-819x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;819&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; ? by @arianneyuson from Instagram[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, while studying in college and spending all my free time in the Exchange District, I found out that movies about early 20th century Chicago had been shot in Winnipeg. Puzzle pieces fell into place. That is where I had seen these streets before I fell in love with them! I&#x27;d seen the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;mbfilmmusic.ca&#x2F;en&#x2F;film&#x2F;filming-in-manitoba&quot;&gt;streets of Winnipeg in movies&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; when I still lived in Russia.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winnipeg has been called &amp;quot;Little Chicago&amp;quot; or most commonly &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Exchange_District&quot;&gt;The Chicago of the North&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&amp;quot; for good reason. At the turn of the century, Chicago and Winnipeg were rivals. Is that hard to believe? Before World War I, Winnipeg was the fastest-growing city in North America. By 1911 Winnipeg was the third-largest city in Canada. Winnipeg, like Chicago, was an international finance, industry, and transportation hub. From the late 1800s to the early 1900s, Chicago architects came to Winnipeg to practice their art and technique in buildings designs. They designed many buildings in the Exchange District. The Chicago architects&#x27; style influenced and inspired local Winnipeg architects, and the city kept growing in the Chicago style.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best examples of the Chicago style is the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mhs.mb.ca&#x2F;docs&#x2F;sites&#x2F;maltesecrossbuilding.shtml&quot;&gt;Maltese Cross Building&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; at 66 King Street. Personally, this building always made my imagination run towards early &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.imdb.com&#x2F;name&#x2F;nm0000095&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Woody Allen&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; movies about New York, love, and love in New York. (Even though we’re talking about Chicago.) The building was designed by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mhs.mb.ca&#x2F;docs&#x2F;people&#x2F;atchison_jd.shtml&quot;&gt;J.D. Atchison&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a Chicago architect who moved to Winnipeg in 1905. Atchison designed nearly 100 buildings in the Exchange District area.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also want to highlight the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mhs.mb.ca&#x2F;docs&#x2F;sites&#x2F;confederationbuilding.shtml&quot;&gt;Confederation Life Building on Main Street&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I remember walking by that building, staring at its detail and marvelling at how much effort and creativity someone had to put into it. The Confederation Life Building was designed by a Toronto architect named &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.historicplaces.ca&#x2F;en&#x2F;rep-reg&#x2F;place-lieu.aspx?id=5950&quot;&gt;Wilson Gray&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who was influenced by Chicago style. This building is such an example of power, dignity, and strength that it takes your breath just for a moment. Next time you walk downtown and turn on Main Street, pay attention to the roof of the building. I promise, the details will surprise you, and perhaps inspire you to create something beautiful yourself.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-3874&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;04&#x2F;DSC01294-2-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many locations in Winnipeg were inspired by the Chicago style. That’s why film directors do not hesitate to use Winnipeg streets as location sets when a plot includes scenes in 20th century Chicago. &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.imdb.com&#x2F;title&#x2F;tt0358135&#x2F;locations&quot;&gt;Shall We Dance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,&amp;quot; with Richard Gere and Jennifer Lopez, was shot in Winnipeg but set in Chicago. Just writing this makes me want to watch that movie again and point out all the familiar streets that now hold so many memories for me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other common links between Winnipeg and Chicago are water and wind. Chicago is located on the shores of Lake Michigan and the Mississippi River; Winnipeg was born at the cross of the Assiniboine and Red rivers. Both cities are built on an open prairie area near a fresh water source. At the beginning of 20th century, Winnipeg was a transportation hub, with access to one of the longest rivers in Canada (the Assiniboine River stretches over 1,070 kilometres).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being built on open shores of lakes and rivers explains why both cities are known as windy cities. The average wind speed in Chicago is 16.6 km&#x2F;hr, while Winnipeg wind speeds can reach 17.1 km&#x2F;hr. If you think those are not big numbers, try to stand at the intersection of Portage and Main on a cold and windy February afternoon! Winnipeg’s wind speed is the second highest of any city in Canada, after Regina, Saskatchewan (18.4 km&#x2F;hr). Chicago is also in second place, after Boston, Massachusetts (20.0 km&#x2F;hr). On November 20, 1892, the Freeborn County Standard of Albert Lea, Minnesota, had &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Windy_City_(nickname)&quot;&gt;this to say&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; about Chicago being called the Windy City:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-3880 size-large aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;04&#x2F;Portage-and-Main-683x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;683&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;“But in another sense, Chicago is actually earning the title of the ‘windy’ city. It is one of the effects of the tall buildings, which engineers and architects apparently did not foresee that the wind is sucked down into the streets. Go ahead and walk past the Masonic Temple or the Auditorium. A day that may be perfectly calm elsewhere, will meet you with a lively breeze at the base of the buildings that will compel you to put your hand to your hat.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
I’ve experienced exactly that many times while walking in downtown Winnipeg. The summer wind always tries to take my hats (but I always catch them, and lucky strangers get a laugh as I jog after my hat).
&lt;p&gt;Winnipeg, the Chicago of the North, has everything you need to take a trip back in time and land in 1905 Chicago. Chicago’s influence is all around: J.D. Atchison designed both the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cmu.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Canadian Mennonite University&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the stunning &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mhs.mb.ca&#x2F;docs&#x2F;sites&#x2F;unionbankbuilding.shtml&quot;&gt;Union Bank Building&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.virtual.heritagewinnipeg.com&#x2F;vignettes&#x2F;vignettes_039.htm&quot;&gt;Great-West Life building on Lombard Avenue&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The architecture in our city is beautiful and artistic; open your eyes, turn on your imagination, and maybe even look into the history of your favourite buildings. The effort is so worth it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now, it is your turn to share! What’s your favourite Chicago-style building in Winnipeg?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
