<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Home - Living at 300Main Downtown Winnipeg - architecture</title>
	<subtitle>We all love 300Main</subtitle>
	<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/architecture/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2019-08-16T20:45:16+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/architecture/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Public Arts of Winnipeg: Living Living Room</title>
		<published>2019-08-16T20:45:16+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-08-16T20:45:16+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/public-arts-of-winnipeg-living-living-room/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/public-arts-of-winnipeg-living-living-room/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The arts scene is a huge part of what makes Winnipeg so special, and the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipegarts.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Winnipeg Arts Council&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has a lot to do with that. Since 2004, the Council has facilitated art displays in public spaces across Winnipeg through the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipegarts.ca&#x2F;pubart-about&quot;&gt;Public Art Program&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. While many of these stunning pieces are downtown⁠—like the “&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipegarts.ca&#x2F;wac&#x2F;artwork&#x2F;electrical-currents&quot;&gt;Electrical Currents&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;” piece at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;downtownwinnipegbiz.com&#x2F;business&#x2F;air-canada-window-park&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Air Canada Park&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;⁠—others are scattered across the city, like the “&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipegarts.ca&#x2F;wac&#x2F;artwork&#x2F;living-living-room&quot;&gt;Living Living Room&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_5750&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;720&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipegarts.ca&#x2F;wac&#x2F;artwork&#x2F;electrical-currents&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-5750&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;08&#x2F;by-D-Works-Media.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Public Arts Winnipeg, Public Arts, Arts, Living Living Room, Winnipeg Arts Council, Winnipeg Arts, Winnipeg Downtown, Downtown Winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Photo by D Works Media from Winnipeg Arts Council Website[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This incredible living art piece was created by Winnipeg artist and landscape designer &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;c2centreforcraft.ca&#x2F;gallery&#x2F;erica-swendrowski&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Erica Swendrowski&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in 2011. With the “Living Living Room”, Erica combined her landscape architecture training and her passion for sculpture with the idea to create household objects made purely of the earth. By combining a creative art display with an environmentally-conscious gardening, this piece enriches the human experience creatively and collectively. Erica made the living room garden a beautiful piece of art that people can really connect with.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_5753&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;720&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipegarts.ca&#x2F;wac&#x2F;artwork&#x2F;living-living-room&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-5753&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;08&#x2F;NI8ugsmh-720-478.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Public Arts Winnipeg, Public Arts, Arts, Living Living Room, Winnipeg Arts Council, Winnipeg Arts, Winnipeg Downtown, Downtown Winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;478&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Orioles Community Centre, living living room by Erica Swendrowski — Photo by Robert Tinker[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In her proposal for the project, Erica wrote, “For generations, community gardens have provided city dwellers with opportunities to grow healthy food close to home.” Erica’s “living living rooms” were integrated into community gardens at the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;valourcc.ca&#x2F;facilities&#x2F;orioles&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Orioles Community Centre&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;lordrobertscc.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Lord Roberts Community Centre&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and the Millennium Garden. The project’s ambitions were to connect local gardeners and to help new relationships “blossom”.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first saw the piece, I was in awe of Erica’s ability to create something that felt so familiar. Living rooms are places of comfort, where we gather with friends and family; they’re filled with memories of holidays, parties and cuddling up to watch your favourite tv shows. Building something that feels so homey encourages people to feel welcomed. I think that sense of togetherness probably made more people want to participate in up-keeping the community gardens where Erica built her creations.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_5754&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;720&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipegarts.ca&#x2F;wac&#x2F;artwork&#x2F;living-living-room&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-5754&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;08&#x2F;3BZHoy2N-720-478.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Public Arts Winnipeg, Public Arts, Arts, Living Living Room, Winnipeg Arts Council, Winnipeg Arts, Winnipeg Downtown, Downtown Winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;478&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Garden Bus Tour, West Broadway, living living room by Erica Swendrowski — Photo by Robert Tinker[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also appreciate the creative relationship between the traditionally-shaped living room “furniture” and the earthy materials and tones. As a place to spend time together, living rooms are a central part of our homes. The natural materials of these pieces remind us that ultimately, the earth is the home we all share.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Winnipeg, we’re lucky to have green spaces throughout the city. I hope these pieces helped those who saw them connect with the idea of how important it is to take care of the environment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipegarts.ca&#x2F;pubart-about&quot;&gt;learn more about the Public Art Program&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipegarts.ca&#x2F;wac&#x2F;pubart-gal&#x2F;&quot;&gt;view all the public artworks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on the Winnipeg Art Council’s website. Which piece have you loved the most?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Winnipeg As Little Chicago</title>
		<published>2019-04-02T16:00:09+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-04-02T16:00:09+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/winnipeg-as-little-chicago/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/winnipeg-as-little-chicago/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When Winnipeg finally introduced itself to me, it was not the first time I had been to the city. The very first time I had been to Winnipeg was on a cold December afternoon when my family moved from Russia to Canada. Our friends met us at the airport, and we drove straight from the airport to a small city just south of Winnipeg. Winnipeg and I didn&#x27;t get a chance to get to know each other yet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next few times when I visited Winnipeg with friends, we mainly went shopping at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cfshops.com&#x2F;polo-park.html&quot;&gt;Polo Park&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. To really get to know the city, you need to get out and explore its oldest parts. You must open your eyes to seeing history, and your ears to hearing what the city wants to tell you. That is exactly what happened to me when I came back to Winnipeg with a pile of documents to apply to college.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That morning, my sister and I had one specific mission: to explore. We got Starbucks and started our walk from the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.fairmont.com&#x2F;winnipeg&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Fairmont Hotel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on Portage Avenue, through the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.exchangedistrict.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Exchange District&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and back to Portage Avenue. I was lifting my eyes, trying to catch architectural details on buildings like the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mhs.mb.ca&#x2F;docs&#x2F;sites&#x2F;unionbankbuilding.shtml&quot;&gt;Union Bank on Main Street&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;pantagesplayhouse.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Pantages Playhouse Theatre&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on Market Street, the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mhs.mb.ca&#x2F;docs&#x2F;sites&#x2F;maltesecrossbuilding.shtml&quot;&gt;Maltese Cross Building&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on King Street, and others. I was enjoying the fresh summer morning air and a strong feeling of familiarity that was pressing on me from all sides. It was a long walk, but that morning something hit me. It was &lt;em&gt;déjà vu&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; feeling that I had already been in this place before. I felt like I&#x27;d seen it before, and not just once.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_3876&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;819&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BSe9ybtBCjl&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-3876 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;04&#x2F;by-arianneyuson-819x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;819&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; ? by @arianneyuson from Instagram[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, while studying in college and spending all my free time in the Exchange District, I found out that movies about early 20th century Chicago had been shot in Winnipeg. Puzzle pieces fell into place. That is where I had seen these streets before I fell in love with them! I&#x27;d seen the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;mbfilmmusic.ca&#x2F;en&#x2F;film&#x2F;filming-in-manitoba&quot;&gt;streets of Winnipeg in movies&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; when I still lived in Russia.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winnipeg has been called &amp;quot;Little Chicago&amp;quot; or most commonly &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Exchange_District&quot;&gt;The Chicago of the North&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&amp;quot; for good reason. At the turn of the century, Chicago and Winnipeg were rivals. Is that hard to believe? Before World War I, Winnipeg was the fastest-growing city in North America. By 1911 Winnipeg was the third-largest city in Canada. Winnipeg, like Chicago, was an international finance, industry, and transportation hub. From the late 1800s to the early 1900s, Chicago architects came to Winnipeg to practice their art and technique in buildings designs. They designed many buildings in the Exchange District. The Chicago architects&#x27; style influenced and inspired local Winnipeg architects, and the city kept growing in the Chicago style.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best examples of the Chicago style is the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mhs.mb.ca&#x2F;docs&#x2F;sites&#x2F;maltesecrossbuilding.shtml&quot;&gt;Maltese Cross Building&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; at 66 King Street. Personally, this building always made my imagination run towards early &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.imdb.com&#x2F;name&#x2F;nm0000095&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Woody Allen&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; movies about New York, love, and love in New York. (Even though we’re talking about Chicago.) The building was designed by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mhs.mb.ca&#x2F;docs&#x2F;people&#x2F;atchison_jd.shtml&quot;&gt;J.D. Atchison&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a Chicago architect who moved to Winnipeg in 1905. Atchison designed nearly 100 buildings in the Exchange District area.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also want to highlight the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mhs.mb.ca&#x2F;docs&#x2F;sites&#x2F;confederationbuilding.shtml&quot;&gt;Confederation Life Building on Main Street&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I remember walking by that building, staring at its detail and marvelling at how much effort and creativity someone had to put into it. The Confederation Life Building was designed by a Toronto architect named &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.historicplaces.ca&#x2F;en&#x2F;rep-reg&#x2F;place-lieu.aspx?id=5950&quot;&gt;Wilson Gray&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who was influenced by Chicago style. This building is such an example of power, dignity, and strength that it takes your breath just for a moment. Next time you walk downtown and turn on Main Street, pay attention to the roof of the building. I promise, the details will surprise you, and perhaps inspire you to create something beautiful yourself.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-3874&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;04&#x2F;DSC01294-2-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many locations in Winnipeg were inspired by the Chicago style. That’s why film directors do not hesitate to use Winnipeg streets as location sets when a plot includes scenes in 20th century Chicago. &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.imdb.com&#x2F;title&#x2F;tt0358135&#x2F;locations&quot;&gt;Shall We Dance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,&amp;quot; with Richard Gere and Jennifer Lopez, was shot in Winnipeg but set in Chicago. Just writing this makes me want to watch that movie again and point out all the familiar streets that now hold so many memories for me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other common links between Winnipeg and Chicago are water and wind. Chicago is located on the shores of Lake Michigan and the Mississippi River; Winnipeg was born at the cross of the Assiniboine and Red rivers. Both cities are built on an open prairie area near a fresh water source. At the beginning of 20th century, Winnipeg was a transportation hub, with access to one of the longest rivers in Canada (the Assiniboine River stretches over 1,070 kilometres).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being built on open shores of lakes and rivers explains why both cities are known as windy cities. The average wind speed in Chicago is 16.6 km&#x2F;hr, while Winnipeg wind speeds can reach 17.1 km&#x2F;hr. If you think those are not big numbers, try to stand at the intersection of Portage and Main on a cold and windy February afternoon! Winnipeg’s wind speed is the second highest of any city in Canada, after Regina, Saskatchewan (18.4 km&#x2F;hr). Chicago is also in second place, after Boston, Massachusetts (20.0 km&#x2F;hr). On November 20, 1892, the Freeborn County Standard of Albert Lea, Minnesota, had &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Windy_City_(nickname)&quot;&gt;this to say&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; about Chicago being called the Windy City:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-3880 size-large aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;04&#x2F;Portage-and-Main-683x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;683&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;“But in another sense, Chicago is actually earning the title of the ‘windy’ city. It is one of the effects of the tall buildings, which engineers and architects apparently did not foresee that the wind is sucked down into the streets. Go ahead and walk past the Masonic Temple or the Auditorium. A day that may be perfectly calm elsewhere, will meet you with a lively breeze at the base of the buildings that will compel you to put your hand to your hat.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
I’ve experienced exactly that many times while walking in downtown Winnipeg. The summer wind always tries to take my hats (but I always catch them, and lucky strangers get a laugh as I jog after my hat).
&lt;p&gt;Winnipeg, the Chicago of the North, has everything you need to take a trip back in time and land in 1905 Chicago. Chicago’s influence is all around: J.D. Atchison designed both the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cmu.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Canadian Mennonite University&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the stunning &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mhs.mb.ca&#x2F;docs&#x2F;sites&#x2F;unionbankbuilding.shtml&quot;&gt;Union Bank Building&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.virtual.heritagewinnipeg.com&#x2F;vignettes&#x2F;vignettes_039.htm&quot;&gt;Great-West Life building on Lombard Avenue&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The architecture in our city is beautiful and artistic; open your eyes, turn on your imagination, and maybe even look into the history of your favourite buildings. The effort is so worth it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now, it is your turn to share! What’s your favourite Chicago-style building in Winnipeg?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Winnipeg Presented in a New Light: Photographers Capturing the Beauty of Downtown Winnipeg</title>
		<published>2018-10-23T17:55:58+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-10-23T17:55:58+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/winnipeg-presented-in-a-new-light-photographers-capturing-the-beauty-of-downtown-winnipeg/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/winnipeg-presented-in-a-new-light-photographers-capturing-the-beauty-of-downtown-winnipeg/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_256&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignleft&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;400&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BnfSFpQAbUh&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-256&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;10&#x2F;by-Josh-Lavallee-819x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Photo by Josh Lavallee @yoshigrams[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s 5:30 am on a brisk Saturday morning in Winnipeg. Josh, better known amongst his peers as “@yoshigrams”, is dangling his feet from a rooftop in the historic Exchange District awaiting the first signs of light. His mission on this crisp September morning is to capture the first beams of sunlight as they rise to cascade over the array of brick buildings set in Chicago style. The aged brick buildings proudly display the remnants of hand painted ads and signs from years past. These ghosted-signed walls will serve as today’s backdrop. Sitting outside in the brisk weather patiently waiting for the sun’s first light is a small price to pay for the stunning photo he will capture today through the lense of his trusty and well-loved camera.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Josh is not alone in his mission to capture the city’s downtown core and the people calling it home. This group of talented and creative Winnipeg photographers, whether they know it or not, is quickly changing the way in which we view our city of just over 700,000 residents. &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many, downtown Winnipeg has become a focal point and hub for photography thanks in part to its diverse cityscapes and character. A mix of late 1800s Chicago-style architecture that inhabits the Exchange, along with sporadic growth and revitalization in the downtown core, have all played a part in this resurgence of interest. New projects and spaces like &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.truenorthsquare.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;True North Square&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;humanrights.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Museum of Human Rights&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and the renovation of the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wcc.mb.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Winnipeg Convention Centre&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; have captured the imagination of many–tourists and Winnipeggers alike. This diverse area encompasses approximately 179.18 square miles and is enjoyably explored on foot or bicycle. One can cover a large portion of the downtown area in a 15-minute bike ride or 20-minute walk from Portage and Main; that is all the distance separating the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theforks.com&#x2F;eat-and-drink&#x2F;dine&#x2F;the-common&quot;&gt;Commons at the Forks Market&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from the steps of the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.gov.mb.ca&#x2F;legislature&#x2F;visiting&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;Manitoba Legislative Building&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or the heart of the Exchange and Provencher Bridge.&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_251&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignnone&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;940&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-251 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;10&#x2F;Provencher-1024x576.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;940&quot; height=&quot;529&quot; &#x2F;&gt; Photo by Joe Lu[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To what do we attribute this influx and growth of interest in photography? We could sit around and debate the influence of good-quality and accessible entry-level camera gear, the evolution of the cell phone camera, or the popularity of photo sharing apps like Instagram and VSCO. While these all come into play, I think there’s something bigger and deeper at the heart of it all. I see a vast number of up-and-coming photographers with a yearning for adventure who are finding it all in their own backyard: Downtown Winnipeg.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_264&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignright&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;450&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BkDJcrRh9sw&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-264&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;10&#x2F;by-Mike-Peters-1024x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Photo by Mike Peters @93mp[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This growing talent pool have proven their ability to capture the same city and locations in contrasting and unique shooting and editing styles. I can’t help but think that this friendly competition is the reason we are seeing such imagery evolving. While some may choose to shoot strictly on iPhones and others prefer investing in higher-end DSLRs, the well of creativity does not run dry. From romanticized skylines to whimsical street views. the variety of ways we can view our city has never been as interesting, as beautiful, or as diverse. This wave of both established and up-and-coming artists are transforming the mundane streets and views into beautiful works of art, ready to be hung on gallery and condo walls alike. &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it is not just the aesthetic quality these photos possess, but the way in which they engage the viewer. Sometimes a familiar space is seen in a new light or a recommendation unintentional is offered. Leveraging tools like social media have forged new paths for us to journey along with photographers as they explore the downtown. Thanks to apps like VSCO and Instagram, we find ourselves consistently screenshotting images taken by some of our favourite Winnipeg photographers. It might be a simple reminder to order a print or, even more often, a reminder to add a specific location to our “To Do and See” list.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my phone amongst the clutter is an album labelled “To Do and See.” I enjoy photography, though I am far from accomplished; perhaps even labelling it a “hobby” is a statement of generosity.  But in the interests of inspiring other local, amateur photographers to grab their camera of choice and hit the pavement for adventure, I took a minute to map out one of my recent excursions.&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_280&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignleft&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;500&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BRHsmeHAepw&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-280&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;10&#x2F;by-Manny-Berkal-Sarbit-820x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;625&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Photo by Manny Berkal-Sarbit @leggrease[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the steps of 300 Main, camera in tow, I hang a right and walk the 7 minutes to Via Rail Union Station to marvel at the building interior. I have been here before, but years ago when I did not have the appreciation I do now. Not many people know that the Historic Building built in 1908 through 1909 was designed by Warren and Wetmore, architects of New York’s Grand Central Station.  A few years back, an image of this space captured by Josh helped me to appreciate the intricate workings of the inner dome-shaped ceiling. &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I keep moving. Depending on the time of year and day, it looks like I am heading west to grab a couple of photos at Upper Fort Garry Park. I have driven by on a weekly basis for many years, yet I desire to take it in first-hand.  It’s hard to believe that more than 400 feet of steel and light went into the installation that scribe three continuous lines tracing the history of western Canada and of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.upperfortgarry.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Upper Fort Garry&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time for some refreshment. I am sitting down for a drink at the Sky Lounge behind Hotel Fort Garry. Sky Lounge offers a stunning skyline view overlooking downtown and the Forks and is located just a few floors from Prairie 360, with views of the city in its entirety. If the day was still young I may rather have opted to grab a coffee at &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.foolsandhorses.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Fools + Horses&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; en route to lunch, served up on Broadway courtesy of the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theredember.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Red Ember Food&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; truck just a block west from &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.foolsandhorses.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Fools + Horses&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.  &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I have a few options. Option one, I can cross the street and do a self-guided tour of the Manitoba Legislative Building, hoping to adequately capture the extensive masonry work and do my best to make out the Hermetic Code written in stone (literally). Option two, I can walk up a block to hit the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wag.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;WAG&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;’s rooftop terrace or walk to the top of The Bay parkade across the street. These are some of the greatest vantage points of downtown and all it has to offer. Option three, I can venture North and check out the newly renovated Winnipeg Convention Centre (which has some awesome exterior textures and lighting) before sitting down in True North Square to do some skyward shooting. &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter which of these options I choose, I am then heading Northeast to continue the journey in the Exchange District. There I will capture some street scenes reminiscent of Chicago, some ghost signs that decorate the building landscape, and then stop for a bite at either &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.kingandbannatyne.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;King + Bannatyne&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.deerandalmond.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Deer + Almond&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; before seeing who or what I can capture at the the Cube Stage in Old Market Square. &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_267&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignright&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;500&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;Bj2RcGZnbR9&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-267&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;10&#x2F;by-Mike-Peters-2-819x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;625&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Photo by Mike Peters @93mp[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My last route will be Waterfront Drive, making my way Southeast to capture &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;goldeyes.com&#x2F;shaw-park&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Shaw Park&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with the arches of Provencher Street Bridge in the background. My final stop will be the ever-popular Museum of Human Rights. All said and done, I will have covered a good portion of downtown Winnipeg–Broadway–Assiniboine, South Portage, the Exchange District, Waterfront and the Forks. I will leave Central Park and Chinatown for my next adventure. All these places and spaces appeared on my timeline at some point; and it was either the lighting or composition that caught my attention in a way I had not viewed before.&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Winnipeg’s downtown continues its renaissance, city dwellers and tourists alike are rediscovering all it has to offer. A vibrant city requires an active heart; a central core. Winnipeg has always possessed this active heart, yet at some points in time the vital signs have been seemingly weak. When the city of Winnipeg refocused its vision back to making a beautiful and accessible downtown, Winnipeggers took note. And they took their cameras.&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of my favourite Winnipeg photographers capturing our great city and sharing their stories on Instagram.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Josh Lavallee &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;yoshigrams&#x2F;&quot;&gt;@yoshigrams&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simeon Rusnak &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;simeonrusnak&#x2F;&quot;&gt;@simeonrusnak&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mike Peters &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;93mp&#x2F;&quot;&gt;@93mp&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Metcalfe &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;davidmetclfe&#x2F;&quot;&gt;@davidmetcalfe&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Josh &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;snapsonsnapsonsnaps&#x2F;&quot;&gt;@snapsonsnapsonsnaps&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Mahon &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;andrewmahon&#x2F;&quot;&gt;@andrewmahon&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz Tran &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;liz.tran&#x2F;&quot;&gt;@liz.tran&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anders Homenick &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;friendshipfilms&#x2F;&quot;&gt;@friendshipfilms&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Byren Gregorchuk @fortheloveofwinnipeg&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
