<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Home - Living at 300Main Downtown Winnipeg - experience</title>
	<subtitle>We all love 300Main</subtitle>
	<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/experience/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2019-02-13T17:24:06+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/experience/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Valentine’s Day in Winnipeg’s Heart</title>
		<published>2019-02-13T17:24:06+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-02-13T17:24:06+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/valentines-day-in-winnipegs-heart/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/valentines-day-in-winnipegs-heart/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With Valentine&#x27;s day around the corner, it never hurts to plan a little something special for your darling. The typical breakfast in bed, dozen red roses and heart-shaped box of chocolates are all fine and dandy, but we can do better. This year, pump up the creativity, explore Winnipeg&#x27;s downtown and surrounding areas, and leave your partner speechless!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;manitobamuseum.ca&#x2F;main&#x2F;event&#x2F;after-hours-wild-romance&#x2F;&quot;&gt;After Hours: Wild Romance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
The &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;manitobamuseum.ca&#x2F;main&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Manitoba Museum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; isn’t the first place that comes to mind when I think romance, but throw in some sensual Argentinian tango, a signature drink, and seriously &lt;em&gt;wild&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; activities, and voilà: a modern-day Valentine&#x27;s celebration! Over the course of the evening, enjoy scavenger’s hunts, beer tastings with &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;littlebrownjug.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Little Brown Jug&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and pop-up talks. But these aren’t your average panel discussions; the talk themes are &quot;all things horn-y&quot; and &quot;plants just wanna have sex.&quot; (Get your mind out of the gutter—the talks are about wildlife, not humans!)
&lt;p&gt;This wild night is perfect for friends, couples, and singles looking for a new spin on a beloved night. It’ll be a night of unexpected fun, romance, and good bites with delicious drinks. The best part? It&#x27;s a short walk away from &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;300 Main&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. Winnipeg&#x27;s ultimate sports night&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Looking for the ultimate Winnipeg experience? What is more Winnipeg than grabbing a beer or wine and great seats to a live hockey game? On cupids chosen day, you can score yourself tickets to the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www1.ticketmaster.ca&#x2F;winnipeg-jets-vs-colorado-avalanche-winnipeg-manitoba-02-14-2019&#x2F;event&#x2F;1100550D92A2396A?dma_id=530&amp;amp;brand=nhl&amp;amp;wt.mc_id=NHL_TEAM_WIN_WEB_MIG&amp;amp;utm_source=NHL.com&amp;amp;utm_medium=client&amp;amp;utm_campaign=NHL_TEAM_WIN&amp;amp;utm_content=WEB_MIG&quot;&gt;Winnipeg Jets vs Colorado Avalanche&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. If your partner is the ultimate Jets fan, give them a gift they’ll truly cherish by spending a memorable night screaming &quot;GO JETS GO!” For some pre-game fun, think outside of the box: present your sweetie with Jets gear, stick-on tattoos and tickets to that night’s game. On your walk to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bellmtsplace.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;BellMTS Place&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, surprise your date with dinner at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.carbonecafeclub.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Carbone Cafe Club&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (who’s up for recreating &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=1nWNXO3CZkU&quot;&gt;Lady and The Tramp’s pasta kiss&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;?), or grab some apps at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;moxies.com&#x2F;restaurant-locations&#x2F;manitoba&#x2F;winnipeg-MTS-place&quot;&gt;Moxie&#x27;s&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Winnipeg&#x27;s downtown is filled with restaurants to suit everyone&#x27;s palate.
&lt;p&gt;Check out some recommendations on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;where-to-stop-for-a-nightcap-after-a-jets-game&#x2F;&quot;&gt;where to stop for a nightcap after a Jets game&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_3106&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;500&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;where-to-stop-for-a-nightcap-after-a-jets-game&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-3106&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;02&#x2F;Where-to-Stop-for-a-Nightcap-After-a-Jets-Game_v2-300x200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Where to Stop for a Nightcap After a Jets Game&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Read blog: Where to stop for a nightcap after a Jets game[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. The Classic Valentine&#x27;s day: Dinner &amp;amp; a Movie at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.themetwinnipeg.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the Met&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Is your partner the ultimate romantic that loves to be swept off their feet? The original 1942 black and white version of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.imdb.com&#x2F;title&#x2F;tt0034583&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Casablanca&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; will be showing at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.themetwinnipeg.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the Metropolitan Entertainment Center&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. One of Winnipeg&#x27;s national historic sites, originally built in 1919, the Met opened as a grand theatre to entertain the masses during cinema&#x27;s height of film. The Met now boasts a 35-foot screen—so any seat in the house is a good one—and elegant furnishings. This is not your average movie date: pre-movie, you’ll be wined and dined with the Mets’ signature buffet; during the movie, you’ll enjoy hot-off-the-press buttery popcorn. Does your average &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.urbandictionary.com&#x2F;define.php?term=netflix%20and%20chill&quot;&gt;Netflix and chill&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; session come with an intermission to delight your senses with coffee and dessert?&lt;em&gt; I don’t think so&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. Create your own “We’ll always have Paris” moment and get carried away on all the romance in the air.
&lt;h3&gt;4. A little winter &lt;em&gt;amour&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Living in Winnipeg, we’re lucky enough to have to picturesque winter backdrop that emanates that cozy, idealistic fairy-tale feeling. Valentine&#x27;s Day is smack-dab in the middle of the best part of our winters, so some of the best outdoor activities are available—including ice skating at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theforks.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Forks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theforks.com&#x2F;events&#x2F;red-river-mutual-trail&quot;&gt;The Red River Mutual Trail&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; currently &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cbc.ca&#x2F;news&#x2F;canada&#x2F;manitoba&#x2F;guinness-gives-official-nod-to-winnipeg-skating-trail-1.740139&quot;&gt;holds the Guinness record&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for the longest naturally frozen skating trail in the world.
&lt;p&gt;Share a piece of Winnipeg&#x27;s history with your special someone and capture the moment with The Forks’ many selfie-worthy spots. Picture yourself holding your date&#x27;s hand while floating down the trail under the stars, enjoying the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.warminghuts.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;warming huts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; brought to Winnipeg by architects from all over the world, hanging out under the magical lit walkway, and gliding across the historic rail bridge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little history + some fresh air + Winnipeg&#x27;s beloved pass time = authentic Winnipeg romance. Don&#x27;t end your evening on the trail: head over to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theforks.com&#x2F;attractions&#x2F;the-forks-market-plaza&quot;&gt;The Forks Market&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for some &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theforks.com&#x2F;eat-and-drink&#x2F;dine&quot;&gt;food and a drink&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to wrap up the evening.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5. Sweet Tooth delight&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
If your date has a serious sweet tooth, why not gift them with a personalized tour of Winnipeg&#x27;s sweet spots? You don&#x27;t have to venture far to satisfy their every craving! Let&#x27;s start our delightful date at &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;constancepopp.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Chocolatier Constance Popp&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with some chocolate marshmallow puffs. This no ordinary chocolate shop: Constance Popp displays each piece of decadent chocolate with beautiful artistry and creativity. Next, head over to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.chocoberrydesserthouse.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Chocoberry Dessert House&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for something savoury; my recommendation is the Salted Caramel S&#x27;mores Dip.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_3104&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;683&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-3104&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;02&#x2F;04-683x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chocolatier Constance Popp, Valentine Day, 300 Main Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;683&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt; Shot by author, Reanna Khan[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up is one of Winnipeg&#x27;s coveted gourmet doughnut shops, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ohdoughnuts.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Oh Doughnuts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Whether you try a classic Boston cream or the Valentine’s specials, each flavour is delightful and activates every taste bud on your tongue. Continue the night at local favourite cake bakery, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bakedexpectations.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Baked Expectations&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Their cake display will dazzle your eyes, satisfy your cravings—and make you unbutton the top of your jeans. This fun, sugar-filled adventure will take you and your partner to old favourites to create new memories!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winnipeg&#x27;s downtown and surrounding areas will thrill you with new events, undiscovered favourites, and romantic hot spots. Whether you’re looking for a little romance, an intense hockey game, a sweet-tooth adventure or a &lt;em&gt;wild&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; night out, downtown has it all. A little creativity and the right partner or friend are the perfect recipe for your most memorable Valentine&#x27;s Day yet! How are you spending this V-Day?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Surviving the Roommate Experience</title>
		<published>2019-01-24T11:00:15+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-01-24T11:00:15+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/surviving-the-roommate-experience/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/surviving-the-roommate-experience/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While most of us love the idea of having our own space to do exactly what we want in, the reality is that living alone can be expensive. It can also be lonely, so some of us choose to have roommates for companionship. Whatever your reasons might be, living with roommates can be a lovely—or disastrous—experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Good&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Splitting living costs means you have more money for other things. You can also create great memories with roommates. I’ve had roomies off and on in my life, particularly in my university years. One of my favourite aspects of living with others is the meshing of traditions and cultures around the holidays. One year, three of us celebrated Christmas and two celebrated Hanukkah. We decided to mash everything together and made a Chrismukkah tree. It was a traditional Christmas evergreen tree, but we covered it in blue and silver decorations (the colours of Hannukah) and used a big Star of David as a tree topper. It was fun watching the roomies who’d never had a tree try to figure out how to hang balls and baubles, as those little squeezable hooks aren’t really used for anything but Christmas decorations. We also got to teach our roommates all of the lyrics to cheesy Christmas songs. And later that school year, I learned how to celebrate Passover. We always enjoyed our combined holiday events.
&lt;p&gt;Being students, we had lots of silly drunken nights and sometimes came up with imaginative solutions to our problems. We had been given a TV by one set of parents, but it had no remote control. We were entirely too lazy to get up and change the channel, so one night we found some duct tape and taped all of our wooden spoons and spatulas together in a long line that reached from the couch to the TV. It served as a handy, and remarkably sturdy, remote control for the rest of the year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And having roommates means there is often someone there to talk to and do things with without having to schedule plans days in advance, which is a nice bonus.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Bad&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Having roomies isn’t always idyllic. Living with others is often fraught with annoyances and drama. One of the most common fights is over cleanliness, or lack thereof. I’m sure our bathrooms were teeming with germs, as no one ever wanted to clean them. We had the same problem with dishes. No one ever believed it was their turn to wash, so the dishes just piled up in the sink in ever-teetering towers.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_2955&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;900&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2955&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;01&#x2F;rawpixel-804799-unsplash-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;dirty dishes, dirty kitchen, messy kitchen. apartment living, living with roommates, roomies, winnipeg apartments, 300 Main apartments, downtown winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;612&quot; &#x2F;&gt; ? by rawpixel on Unsplash[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your best bet to avoid similar problems is to have a conversation with your roomies right at the start, to decide what is and isn’t acceptable for everyone. You may also want to create a chore schedule so everyone knows exactly who will be doing what and by when.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another issue can be sharing food or other resources. You should decide right away if you are sharing food or keeping things completely separate. This does not guarantee success, by the way. We had one roommate in university (I’m calling her Jane to protect the guilty) who never bought her own food and pilfered from everyone else when we weren’t around. It wasn’t something we were able to successfully stop, and it was one of the reasons she ended up moving out before the year was up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Ugly&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Some problems grow from small to breathtakingly bad. We had one roommate (surprisingly, not Jane) come back from summer break in second year with a large package in tow. She worked on her parents’ travelling carnival every summer. That year, she had fallen for a 6’8” carny and decided to bring him back to university with her. He was supposed to stay a few days, maybe a week or two, before finding his own place. He never left. He spent the entire year living with us, moving from job to job, and never contributed anything towards rent or utilities. It was an ongoing fight all year to get him to pay up or move out, but we didn’t get the big mooch to leave until we all moved out at the end of the school year.
&lt;p&gt;Most roommate situations don’t turn out this badly, but it’s important to know something about the person you are living with and to set clear ground rules from the start. It’s no fun if you suddenly find yourself in need of a new living situation because things have become untenable at home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;And the Downright Weird&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Some roommate situations just become weird. Like Jane, who had a revolving door of friends constantly in our apartment. It’s a little disconcerting to walk into your bathroom at 7 am and find some guy you’ve never met before passed out over your toilet. (Hello, awkward conversation.)
&lt;p&gt;In our student apartment building, people regularly set off the fire alarm with burned popcorn and toast. But when Jane decided it would be a great idea to butt a cigarette into a wastebasket full of paper, the ensuing full-fledged fire didn’t set off the alarms until our apartment was fully consumed by smoke. Most of the damage was contained to her room, but the entire apartment had a distinctly smoky smell for weeks after. I guess my tip here is to choose your roommates wisely.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bottom Line&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
[caption id=&quot;attachment_2957&quot; align=&quot;aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;900&quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2957&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;01&#x2F;kelly-sikkema-411622-unsplash-1024x678.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sticky notes, delegating, tasks, communication, assertive, apartment living, downtown Winnipeg, 300 Main Apartments&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;596&quot; &#x2F;&gt; ? by Kelly Sikkema on Unsplash[&#x2F;caption]
&lt;p&gt;There are benefits and drawbacks both to living alone and with others. You need to pick the option that best works for you. If you have roommates, spend a little time making the right choice or you could spend a lot of time regretting it. Set clear ground rules and expectations, and be prepared to have frank discussions when things don’t run smoothly. This happens sometimes, even with great roommates. And if you have some bad experiences, remind yourself they make great fodder for party stories later. (And share them below!)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
