<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Home - Living at 300Main Downtown Winnipeg - relationships</title>
	<subtitle>We all love 300Main</subtitle>
	<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/category/relationships/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-04-26T21:21:37+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/category/relationships/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>DIY Gifts for Mom</title>
		<published>2022-04-26T21:21:37+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-26T21:21:37+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/diy-gifts-for-mom/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/diy-gifts-for-mom/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mother’s Day is May 8&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;, and it seems like no matter how much we think, plan and prepare for it, it still creeps up on us too soon. Whether or not Mother’s Day is catching you off guard this year, it is still harder to be more creative as the gift-giving years go on. This Mother’s Day, don&#x27;t you get caught “giftless,” or worse, with a bad Mother&#x27;s Day gift.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, gift shopping for anyone else is getting harder. It seems like everyone has everything they need and want. When it comes to Mother’s Day, one of my go-to gift routes has always been every mother’s favorite- the DIY gift! &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7790,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;full&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;04&#x2F;pexels-elina-fairytale-3893732.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7790&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is presumably no gift your mom had ever loved more than when she was given beautiful and unique DIY gifts by you. It never mattered if she needed or wanted the things we made as kids because it was always the thought that counted.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year give Mom a thoughtful blast to the past with a DIY gift straight from your heart and hands. If you think that sounds nice but easier said than done, don&#x27;t worry. We have DIY gift ideas that any skill level can pull off and will make mom impressed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;DIY Gift Ideas&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Homemade wreaths&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you think of walking up to your mom on the holidays- there is always one sight you can count on... A warm and welcoming wreath! &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7789,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;full&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;04&#x2F;pexels-maria-rodnikova-9797607.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7789&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things about having a happy mom is knowing that she is always eagerly waiting to break out the next collection of wreaths and decor. Give her a unique and timeless gift this Mother’s Day by making her the perfect year-round wreath!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ideas out there for this one, from the more traditional to the out of the flower box ideas. This is a very versatile gift idea. These are great because you can tailor them to her taste and decor, and no one knows your mom’s style better than you!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fabric wreaths&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your mom is the fun, creative type, this is a perfect choice. Make a wreath that matches whatever space your mom is proudly going to want to display it. A great option is using handkerchiefs and pocket scarves as they are an easy-to-find, affordable, and one-of-a-kind idea when it comes to making a wreath.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Specialized Bouquets&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7788,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;full&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;04&#x2F;pexels-secret-garden-931158-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7788&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another great DIY gift idea you can customize for your mom that she will love is a flower box bouquet. Show your mom not only how much she means to you but how well you know her with a personalized bouquet. Nothing says Happy Mother’s Day like realizing their baby really does know and love them back (almost) as much as they know and love us.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Show your mom how much you with a personalized bouquet. These personalized DIY bouquets are a perfect fit for Mother’s Day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Crystal Bouquets&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you or your mom is into crystals, this is a great idea. Not only is it sentimental to put it into a bouquet, but crystals are also incredibly beautiful and personal when it comes from the right person. If your mom likes crystals, the great idea is to go to a holistic store (or order a set on amazon) and pick out a few of your favorite crystals that you know your Mom would love. This is one of the most affordable yet thoughtful ideas when it comes to the DIY gift department.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7786,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;full&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;04&#x2F;pexels-karolina-grabowska-4040644.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7786&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you aren&#x27;t sure what a crystal is or what to buy, here are some suggestions that fit the energy of Mother’s Day. It is never a bad idea to grab some dried herbs and fresh flowers to throw in and fill the spaces and really make your bouquet complete. You can go to your local metaphysical store or order them online from many holistic realters (amazon included). The great thing about these bouquets is you can make them specific to your mom&#x27;s life, needs, and personality. If you are not quite sure where to start with the crystals and do not want to ruin the surprise by asking her yourself, here are some fail-safe favorites she will definitely love:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:list --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rose Quartz&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Amethyst&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Citrine&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tigers Eye&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Turquoise&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Clear Quartz&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tigers Eye&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rainbow Fluorite&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:list --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Edible Bouquets&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another delicious bouquet idea is an edible bouquet! If you ask any mom, they would probably rather have chocolates than actual flowers. A traditional gift like flowers is a nice thought, but they wilt all too soon. Give your Mother’s Day gift a tasty appetizer with a chocolate or cookie bouquet, picked fresh for your own Mom&#x27;s taste.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7785,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;full&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;04&#x2F;pexels-andres-ayrton-6578908.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7785&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great and easy thing to pull off, no matter your DIY skill, because baking is optional. Put together some of your mom’s favorite cookies, chocolates, and other treats and arrange them in her own “snack bouquet.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Photo Bouquet&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great bouquet option that you can personalize with your mom is a photo bouquet! Print out some of your favorite photos of your mom or you and her together, and turn them into a personal bouquet! &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7784,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;full&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;04&#x2F;pexels-samer-daboul-1226721-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7784&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She will certainly love the thought and personality put behind it and the fact that she has printouts of the two of you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DIY Self Care Box&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moms work way too hard even now that we grow older; our moms are still able to grace us with their motherly wisdom at every text and call. Give your mom some designated me time (that isn&#x27;t you) with a bath box! Go to any store and pick out a cute box or bag and put together some essential bath items.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7782,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;full&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;04&#x2F;pexels-rodnae-productions-8903338.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7782&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are gifted in the DIY department, you can make her some bath and skincare products or just go to the dollar store and load up on bubbles and candles. Here are some things you don&#x27;t want to forget when making your mom&#x27;s bath box.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things to include in your bath box:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:list --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bath Salt&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bubble Bath&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Candles&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bath Bombs&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Face &amp;amp; Hair Masks&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lotion&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Essential Oils&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;DIY Candle&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:list --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making a candle is one thing that is both impressive, personal, and easier done than said. Give your mom something she can use every day and make her own personal candle. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7780,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;full&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;04&#x2F;pexels-pixabay-33197.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7780&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know what kind of scents and flavors your mom usually goes for, all you need to do is grab wicks, wax, a mason jar, and pick out two to four essential oils that smell great together. You can find fun ideas and more in-depth instructions online, but making a candle is as easy as 1-2-3-.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:4} --&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Pick out your wax, wick, and smell.&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ingredients of a candle are your wax, the wick, the essential oils, and of course, your jar. You can get these online or at any craft store.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:4} --&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Prepare&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All you have to do is melt the wax, mix, and set.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melt your wax either directly or through a double boiler system. Once the wax is melted, mix in your essential oils. Whatever method, wax, and size of candle you choose will determine how much you need.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:4} --&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Package&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that your wax and essential oils are combined, you want to get ready to fill the jar and set the wick. Slowly pour the melted wax and oil into the jar with the wick and let it set. Within 24-48 hours, you will have a personal, beautiful candle ready for your Mother’s Day gift.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:7781,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;full&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;04&#x2F;pexels-anna-shvets-5760879.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7781&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your mom is bound to love any one of these DIY gifts or any other idea you may come up with. When it comes to Mother’s Day, many of us stress about how to best show our moms just how much we appreciate everything they do. A DIY gift is not only easy on your budget but is loving, personal, and bound to show mom exactly how much her answering every little question about laundry and cooking does mean to us.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to our moms, no one means more to us. It may feel hard to express the level of gratitude you have for everything she does for you. When it comes to gift-giving to your mom, nothing says I love you more than a gift that says, &quot;I spent time on this,&quot; and a DIY gift package will scream exactly that. These DIY gifts are amazing alone, or you can mix some of them, and they can also serve you for any other occasion. No matter what you choose, here is hoping you and your mom have a beautiful Mother’s Day this year!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Landing that Loft After Love: Starting Over After a Divorce</title>
		<published>2021-07-02T19:57:56+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-02T19:57:56+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/landing-that-loft-after-love-starting-over-after-a-divorce/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/landing-that-loft-after-love-starting-over-after-a-divorce/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, divorce wasn’t exactly in your life plan. I think it’s safe to say it’s not in most of ours. But it happens. Then suddenly, your life is in upheaval and your vision for the future needs to change. It’s stressful and kind of scary. And it sucks. But, it can also be an exciting opportunity to establish the new and improved, independent you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mondo checkbox on that to-do list is finding your new home. It’s a pretty daunting task. For most of us, being at home makes us feel comfortable and safe. If you don’t have that refuge to return to, or it’s full of reminders of your past life, well, it can make a tough time even harder. But it &lt;em&gt;is &lt;&#x2F;em&gt;possible, and even manageable. &lt;em&gt;You’ve got this.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that if I can do it, you can too. It won’t be easy, but you’ll be back on your feet in no time. Remember though, every situation is unique. Assess your circumstances and then tackle those hurdles as only you can!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you do anything else, you’ve got to answer this all important question:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What’s your budget?&amp;nbsp;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A budget is &lt;em&gt;integral&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to starting things off right.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re going from living with a spouse and splitting the expenses to living on your own, you’re going to need to reassess your finances. Depending on your situation, this may drastically affect your standard of living (harsh, but true).&amp;nbsp;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Break down your monthly income and your current expenses. Which are non-negotiable? Which can be reduced? And when in doubt, round up! If you always count on socking away a little extra, the surplus will help to cover any unexpected expenses that crop up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a ballpark figure, about 30% of your monthly income is going toward rent. Depending on your earnings and your housing needs, that number might be even higher. In the quest for your new address, be sure to consider what utilities and amenities are included - a higher monthly payment might be worth it if it covers your electric bill and gym membership too!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve run the numbers and you’re going to be hard pressed to make ends meet, &lt;em&gt;don’t panic&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. There is social support in place for this situation you may qualify for. Those in Manitoba can find out more through the 2-1-1 phone line or website.&amp;nbsp;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you know how much you’re prepared to spend, it’s time to hit the bricks (or the search engine).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:6801,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2021&#x2F;06&#x2F;Divorce1-1024x693.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-6801&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finding a place&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like with any important decision: take your time!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another way of saying &lt;strong&gt;don’t take the first thing that comes along&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re anything like me, you’re eager to get out of this limbo and on with your life! But it’s worth it to look around and weigh your options (especially remembering some ‌places I considered - yikes!).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only do you want a place that fits your budget, you want something that fits your lifestyle. Somewhere you can reclaim that safe and comfortable environment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the short term, I recommend renting as opposed to buying for two main reasons:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:list {&quot;ordered&quot;:true,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;1&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexibility&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp; - Right now your future is uncertain. A lease gives you the option to adjust your plans as circumstances evolve. Plus, it’s easier to find something that fits your budget.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Convenience - &lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;You have enough to deal with without worrying about replacing appliances or building and yard maintenance! Instead, you can plunk yourself in a central location with easy access to whatever amenities you need.&amp;nbsp;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:list --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My downtown apartment was the perfect haven, with easy access to transit, restaurants, parks and entertainment. It had everything I needed to let me hunker down and put myself back together again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you’re searching the streets for vacancy signs, try not to worry about landing something&amp;nbsp; before the month closes. If possible, shack up with a friend or even your Mom for a few weeks while you get your house in order (literally and figuratively). This gets you out of your old place into a transitory state. You’ll be more motivated to find a pad of your own &lt;em&gt;and&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; it gets you out of your old place.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can check into short-term leases. If you need a place to recoup for a month or two before you sign a long-term lease, these can provide temporary asylum.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The local Rental Guide, classifieds, internet searches and prowling the pavement are all great ways to get a beat on lucrative places for rent. Check them out and see what your options are.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your new home is where you’re going to begin the next chapter of your life, it’s okay to take a bit of time to figure out something that fits you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ok, so you’ve found a place. Now what?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:list --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Out with the old in with the you!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:list --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best things about divorce? Getting to choose your own aesthetic. Now’s your chance to design your space in a way that reflects &lt;em&gt;you&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purge the items that don’t fit anymore - both emotionally and physically. Throw the wedding pictures in storage, and swap that too big, memory ridden furniture for something that fits your space and your style. Whether you’re trawling department stores or thrift shops, it’s refreshing to pick out some new pieces you love.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:list --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan for Plants!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:list --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are happier with plants around. It’s almost like we do better with other living things nearby! (We do, that’s science.) I don’t pretend to understand &lt;em&gt;why &lt;&#x2F;em&gt;exactly having plants makes you feel better, but they reduce stress and improve your mood just by being there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you’re not a plant person, you have options. Have you considered a spider plant? Even I managed not to kill that. Or, check out these out articles to find your fit:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;finding-your-houseplant-match&#x2F;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;-Finding your houseplant match&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;which-plants-grow-best-in-your-apartment-making-your-apartment-greener&#x2F;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;-Make your apartment greener&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:list --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potentially pets&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:list --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:6802,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2021&#x2F;06&#x2F;pets1-1024x688.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-6802&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it’s already you and your furry friend against the world, you’re set. But if not, you may want to take up cat-sitting, because like plants, we’re happier with animals around. You might even look into fostering or adopting a pet of your own!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caring for and having the company of animals can be rewarding and fulfilling. But think carefully before adopting a pet - it’s a big commitment. If your life is already in turmoil, heaping more responsibility onto your plate may not be the best idea. It adds extra complexity such as ensuring your new abode is pet friendly, and paying additional damage deposits.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, having an animal around is super therapeutic because, well, they’re often cuddly and adorable. Plus the previously mentioned scientifically backed benefits of other living things! You’ve got options though - there are lots of programs in need of good foster homes for animals while they wait for adoption, or you can volunteer your time at the shelters themselves.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, definitely crash your friend’s next trip to the dog park!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:list --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get to know your neighbourhood&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:list --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re in a new place with all kinds of new things to discover! It can be a little intimidating, and you may still be mourning the loss of your favorite coffee shop, but getting out and about in your neighbourhood has multiple benefits.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, it’s important that you actually get up and leave your place occasionally, even if you don’t want to. Being outside is &lt;em&gt;another &lt;&#x2F;em&gt;of those scientifically backed well-being things. Plus, how else are you going to find the local restaurant with the best patio?? (Besides on the internet - you need to go check it out!)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting familiar with your new surroundings is a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; step toward quelling that out-of-place feeling. You’ll start recognizing the local baristas and it will ‌become more and more like home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember: Everything is going to be OK&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:6803,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2021&#x2F;06&#x2F;Divorce2-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-6803&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might take a while, but over time things will begin to feel normal again. In the meantime, it’s okay &lt;em&gt;not &lt;&#x2F;em&gt;to be okay. Lean on your friends and family, talk to a therapist, dispose of that pair of your ex’s underwear you found, preferably in a needlessly spectacular and ruthless fashion. Do what you need to do to get through this.&amp;nbsp;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Divorce is cruddy, but it’s also the start of something new. Things won’t ever be the same, but there are plenty of reasons you don’t want them to be. By taking the time to prepare and find a place that provides what you need, you’ll have a new home base and foundation off which to launch. Having the comfort of a home that embodies &lt;em&gt;you&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; will provide the safety and structure you need to heal and start the next leg of your journey.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Downtown Living with Susan Ainley</title>
		<published>2019-07-10T14:37:02+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-07-10T14:37:02+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/downtown-living-with-susan-ainley/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/downtown-living-with-susan-ainley/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;embed&#x2F;_WtGqd79km4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We invited Susan Ainley (also known as &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;broken_down_chevy&#x2F;&quot;&gt;@broken_down_chevy on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) to come and tell us a story of her experience living in downtown Winnipeg! She talked about how long she&#x27;s been living in downtown, why she chose to rent, and the things she enjoy most living in downtown.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We love hearing personal stories of  downtown living. Do you have your own that you want to share with us?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>New to Networking? Start With Your Neighbours!</title>
		<published>2019-05-23T21:43:11+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-05-23T21:43:11+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/new-to-networking-start-with-your-neighbours/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/new-to-networking-start-with-your-neighbours/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Networking—a fancy term for a simple idea. Meet people, interact with them and build new relationships. We’re so used to networking through social media that the thought of physically interacting with people might sound a little bit alien. You could have 300 people on your &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ca.linkedin.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; network, another 300 on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and not know any of them well enough to know where they are from. Friendly relations between neighbours encourages real-life networking, and as old school as it may sound, it’s so valuable. Everyone has a story to tell, and you would probably miss the most interesting chapters if you had the same conversation online.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans are social by nature; we need to have meaningful conversations with other people to satisfy our natural instinct to know one another. Community meet-ups and common areas encourage networking with those around us. Networking doesn’t necessarily mean meeting with influential people who can help you professionally; it can also include people you can really connect with on an intellectual level. Many apartment buildings have common areas so people can lounge and get to know each other. Events like BBQs, pool parties, breakfasts and evening tea encourage tenants to get familiar with each other. While these events may seem like just a casual breakfast (free food!), they’re also opportunities to discuss concerns and get valuable information. For example, downtown apartment dwellers might be happy to learn about the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;downtownwinnipegbiz.com&#x2F;programs-services&#x2F;safety&#x2F;watch-ambassadors&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Downtown Watch Ambassadors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BwK8cMVg5YP&#x2F;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BwK8cMVg5YP&#x2F;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;A post shared by Downtown Winnipeg BIZ (@downtownwpgbiz)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot;font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-04-12T21:43:42+00:00&quot;&gt;Apr 12, 2019 at 2:43pm PDT&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Networking isn’t just about advancing your career; it’s also about bonds between neighbours, an important part of apartment living. Being on good terms with your neighbours means you have someone to turn to in case of an emergency, or just to call over for a cup of tea if you’re having a bad day and need someone to talk to. You can surround yourself with people you trust who can eventually become part of your support system. Good neighbours can end up feeling like family when you’re living alone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great thing about downtown Winnipeg is the strong sense of community that the area promotes. Most apartment buildings are designed to have spaces for general use. Downtown boasts wonderful cultural diversity, making networking even more fun! You can get to know people from varied backgrounds, find out first-hand details about other cultures, and learn about entirely different ways of life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My apartment building used to have the best BBQ parties for tenants where we would all just chat; it was fun to find out that I had a police officer and ballet dancer living on the same floor as me. At one BBQ, I saw a distinguished-looking gentleman hand over his business card to a student looking for an internship. It felt so good to be living in a community where people were looking out for each other and helping out where they could. These meet-ups can even help recent immigrants build their social circles and meet new people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-4665 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;05&#x2F;alexis-brown-85793-unsplash-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New to Networking? Start With Your Neighbours!&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These BBQs also gave me a unique chance to meet people from different cultural backgrounds. The chance to listen to stories about what they did and experienced “back home” was really special.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next time you’re invited to a breakfast in your apartment building, think twice before deciding you’d rather sleep in than get up early and meet new people. You might meet someone who can open your eyes to a new view of the world!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BBQs, breakfasts, and boardgame nights are just a few examples of great ways to make friends with your neighbours. What’s your favourite way to meet new people?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Why I Choose to Live Downtown</title>
		<published>2019-02-26T17:20:16+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-02-26T17:20:16+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/why-i-choose-to-live-downtown/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/why-i-choose-to-live-downtown/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The stereotypical trappings of urban living do not make downtown—the people, food and buildings do! I began my downtown living journey when I was 19, and I’ve never looked back. Something about downtown caught my interest when I was ready to move from my 130 square foot dormitory into a more grown-up apartment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a young adult, I couldn’t decide if I wanted to create a life in an urban or suburban area. The wonderful thing about downtown Winnipeg is that combines the very best parts of Winnipeg into one neighbourhood! As the years advance and I shuffle between different downtown streets, downtown feels more and more like home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you love parks, museums, music venues or creative attractions, downtown Winnipeg has something to make your heart sing. Downtown really optimizes its space with something interesting to see, eat and&#x2F;or do around every corner.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Mixture of Old and New&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Downtown mixes the old and the new, showcasing Winnipeg’s attachment to its historical buildings by preserving them, scattered between modernized high rises. The older buildings are comforting and make downtown feel like more than just another concrete jungle. These mature buildings are one of the major reasons why I moved and stayed downtown; they’re full of stories of what Winnipeg used to be like, and how my grandparents and parents lived their lives in these streets.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_3318&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;940&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-3318&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;02&#x2F;archway-1024x683.png&quot; alt=&quot;Archway at the Grain Exchange, Exchange District, Winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;940&quot; height=&quot;627&quot; &#x2F;&gt; Archway at the Grain Exchange building, Winnipeg[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;You’re Never Hungry&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Downtown serves as a melting pot, bringing together diverse people into one place—and it really shows through the food! There’s an assortment of eateries, which is great news for foodies like me. You can turn on to any street and be greeted by mom-and-pop bistros, one-of-a-kind cafes, or the familiar chain restaurants you can eat at just about everywhere (which I swear taste better downtown, for some reason). Food and I have a pretty steady relationship, and by living downtown I get the opportunity to experiment with all sorts of flavours!
&lt;h3&gt;Building Connections&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Small town living has its romance, but urban living creates intense proximity between you and the people around you. It’s a common misconception that people who live in the heart of cities don’t interact with each other, but I beg to differ! You share laughs with the people at the bus stop as you joke about how Winnipeg Transit buses never seem to arrive on time, make small talk with the folks on the bus that you’re sardined against, groan along with people as you wait in the ridiculously long line at Tim’s, and smile at the person who held the elevator door open for you. These small but meaningful interactions make up the connections of downtown dwellers. You feel that connection because frankly, you can’t help it—you’re always in close proximity to someone.
&lt;h3&gt;The People Around You&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
It goes without saying that in some cities, downtown can seem cold and unwelcoming. However, I believe that the benefits of urban living can be seen in each unique neighbourhood. Each neighbourhood tells the story of the people who live there, and my neighbourhood downtown is full of people from all walks of life. In my apartment building, my neighbours include a family from across the pond who made me fresh juice when I moved in, an elderly man who gives everyone a Christmas card each year, and a few male university students who shovel the front walkway every winter without being asked. Maybe I’m lucky to know my neighbours, but with the hustle and bustle of downtown life, these types of people really shine a light on downtown Winnipeg’s unique spirit.
&lt;center&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;Bsx_u52AA8z&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;Bsx_u52AA8z&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.w3.org&#x2F;2000&#x2F;svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.w3.org&#x2F;1999&#x2F;xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;path&gt;&lt;&#x2F;g&gt;&lt;&#x2F;g&gt;&lt;&#x2F;g&gt;&lt;&#x2F;svg&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;Bsx_u52AA8z&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Living and working downtown, I have the option to walk to work inside through the Winnipeg Walkway system. It was the perfect way to commute this morning! #finditdowntown #winnipegwalkways #tgif&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;downtownpeggy&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt; Downtown Peggy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (@downtownpeggy) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-01-18T15:37:17+00:00&quot;&gt;Jan 18, 2019 at 7:37am PST&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt; &lt;script async src=&quot;&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Other Side of Downtown&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
City life is not always relaxing, and you really need to become accustomed to the parades of cars, constant mummers of conversation and the fast-paced environment. But when you look between the lines of it all, you see the beauty of downtown.
&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re a foodie, an art enthusiast, a people-watcher or just someone who loves a fast-paced life, downtown Winnipeg welcomes you. Now you tell us: what about downtown draws you in?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Where to Find Unique Holiday Gifts Downtown and in the Exchange</title>
		<published>2018-12-12T16:00:21+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-12-12T16:00:21+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/where-to-find-unique-holiday-gifts-downtown-and-in-the-exchange/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/where-to-find-unique-holiday-gifts-downtown-and-in-the-exchange/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The holidays are just around the corner, and while some always seem to be ahead of the game and finish their Christmas shopping by the time Black Friday hits, others (like me) wait until the last minute. By then, the malls are flooded with well-intentioned but anxious people looking to nab some last-minute gifts. The entire experience becomes frenzied, and the joy of picking out gifts for your loved ones’ withers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then comes the second wave of anxiety—what do you get for your friends and family members, who are all very different from each other? What can you get them that will leave a lasting impression? If you’re like me, you pride yourself on giving thoughtful, unique gifts, making downtown the best place to find all your gifts this holiday season! Forget the headache of navigating mall parking lots and the throngs of people inside. Winnipeg’s downtown area has amazing shops, every one of them specialised in merchandise you can’t find at the mall.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;For the Lover of the Outdoors: &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mec.ca&#x2F;en&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;MEC&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;em&gt;303 Portage Ave&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h6&gt;
[caption id=&quot;attachment_2402&quot; align=&quot;aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;404&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BqVUGcLBRTO&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2402&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;12&#x2F;by-MEC-828x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MEC, Mountain Equipment Coop, Gift Ideas, Unique, Outdoor, Travel Light, Downtown Winnipeg, Carry-On, Holidays, Packing&quot; width=&quot;404&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; ? by @haehanna from @mec Instagram[&#x2F;caption]
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mec.ca&#x2F;en&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Mountain Equipment Co-op&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has long been the go-to place for travellers and naturists. It’s the best place to find weather-related essentials, sturdy backpacks, comfortable footwear, books on the outdoors, and even advanced gear for the true adventurers amongst us. On the main floor, there’s a wide selection of accessories that would make the perfect little gift for the outdoorsy adventurer in your life. Unbreakable &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.nalgene.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Nalgene&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; bottles, water purifying tablets, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.swissarmy.com&#x2F;ca&#x2F;en&quot;&gt;Swiss Army&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; knives, wool socks, and sweat-wicking clothes are but a few products that would go a long way for someone who’s planning a trip. You can even pick up a cool &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mec.ca&#x2F;en&#x2F;article&#x2F;a-gift-guide-for-adventure-dogs-by-an-adventure-dog&quot;&gt;gift for your four-legged hiking partner&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;For the Stationery Lover: &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.tinyfeast.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tiny Feast&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;em&gt;217 McDermot Ave&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h6&gt;
[caption id=&quot;attachment_2403&quot; align=&quot;aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;421&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BpUX9VvHbiK&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2403&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;12&#x2F;by-TinyFeast-863x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tiny Feast, The Exchange District, Downtown Winnipeg, Unique Gift Ideas, Christmas, Holidays, Stationery&quot; width=&quot;421&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; ? by @tinyfeast on Instagram[&#x2F;caption]
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.tinyfeast.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Tiny Feast&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a stationery-lover’s dream. The store is well-known for keeping its shelves stocked with beautiful stationery goods and charming gifts, so you’re sure to find a little something for everyone. Tiny Feast curates a fabulous selection of high-quality journals, paper, pens, high-end office accessories, handmade cards for every occasion, and beautiful prints. They even carry stylish accessories you didn’t know you needed in your life, like sleek water bottles, mugs, enamel pins, and jewellery.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;For Someone Special: &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.hilarydruxman.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hilary &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Druxman&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;em&gt;258 McDermot Ave &lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h6&gt;
[caption id=&quot;attachment_2404&quot; align=&quot;aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BqNmrhvgpqH&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2404&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;12&#x2F;by-hilarydruxmanjewelry-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jewellery, Jewelry, Unique Finds in Downtown, Downtown Winnipeg, The Exchange District, Holidays, Christmas, Accessories&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; ? by hilarydruxmanjewelry on Instagram[&#x2F;caption]
&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for a gift to celebrate an occasion or a special person, do yourself a favour and take a gander inside &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.hilarydruxman.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Hilary Druxman’s&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; studio boutique. She handcrafts each piece of jewellery so they’re easy to wear with any outfit—be it rings, bracelets, necklaces or earrings. You can even get your piece customised! Everything is simple, beautiful, and definitely special.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;For the Cinephile: &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.winnipegfilmgroup.com&#x2F;cinematheque&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cinematheque&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;em&gt;304-100 Arthur St &lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h6&gt;
[caption id=&quot;attachment_2411&quot; align=&quot;aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;413&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BpkoP2KgBuu&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2411&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;12&#x2F;by-wfgcinematheque-845x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Winnipeg Cinematheque, The Exchange District, Downtown Winnipeg, Winnipeg Films, Unique Finds&quot; width=&quot;413&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; ? by wfgcinematheque on Instagram[&#x2F;caption]
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.winnipegfilmgroup.com&#x2F;cinematheque&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Cinematheque&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, located in the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;art-space.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Artspace&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; building, is the movie theatre for true film aficionados. This small cinema offers a diverse program of foreign and award-winning films, world documentaries, and local premieres. Kevin McDonald also curates a selection of classic comedies, presented monthly. For the gift that keeps on giving, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.winnipegfilmgroup.com&#x2F;product&#x2F;cinematheque-annual-pass-2&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Cinematheque’s annual pass&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; lets the movie lover in your life enjoy unlimited regular admission screenings for an entire year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;For the New Homeowner: &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;hutk.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;HUT K&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;em&gt;200 Princess St &lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h6&gt;
[caption id=&quot;attachment_2412&quot; align=&quot;aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;667&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BpsDDEJgcQu&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2412&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;12&#x2F;by-hutkshop.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Interior Design, Furniture, Downtown Winnipeg, The Exhchange District, Apartment Living, Downtown Living&quot; width=&quot;667&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; ? by @hutkshop on Instagram[&#x2F;caption]
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;hutk.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;HUT K&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is primarily a furniture store, but it’s also a must-stop for those who appreciate architecture and timeless style. If you’re looking to buy for someone who cares about their space – whether they’re a twenty-something who just got their own place, or just looking to revamp their home—don’t miss HUT K’s curated showroom. The staff of architecture grads carefully selects every piece, so each item is chic, modern, and can complement any space. I know gifting someone with a sofa is a little extra, so be sure to check out their selection of home accessories.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;For the Frequent Traveller: &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;unluggage.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;U.N. L&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;uggage&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;em&gt;175 McDermot Ave &lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h6&gt;
[caption id=&quot;attachment_2413&quot; align=&quot;aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;554&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BqA93agAi-y&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2413&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;12&#x2F;by-unluggage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Luggage Store, Travelling, Traveller, Unique Finds in Downtown, Downtown Winnipeg, The Exchange District, Christmas, Holidays&quot; width=&quot;554&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; ? by @unluggage on Instagram[&#x2F;caption]
&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to buy for a globetrotter who always travels in style, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;unluggage.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;U.N. Luggage&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is the perfect place to shop. They have a wonderful selection of bags (including backpacks, handbags, toiletry bags, and laptop bags), passport covers, wallets, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ca.moleskine.com&#x2F;classic-notebook-black&#x2F;p0460&quot;&gt;Moleskine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; notebooks, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;corkcicle.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Corkcicle&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; canteens and tumblers, and beautiful fountain pens. Many of their products are made of leather, so they make very sleek, very stylish gifts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;For Your Quirky Friends: &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.taradavis.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tara Davis&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt; Studio Boutique&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;em&gt;246 McDermot Ave &lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h6&gt;
[caption id=&quot;attachment_2414&quot; align=&quot;aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;Bn1ROwGnmO5&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2414&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;12&#x2F;by-taradavisstudioboutique-819x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Boutique in Exchange District, Downtown Winnipeg, Unique Finds, Christmas Gifts, Holiday&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; ? by @taradavisstudioboutique on Instagram[&#x2F;caption]
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.taradavis.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Tara Davis&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a beautiful, colourful, whimsical shop and gallery. It focuses on handmade items from all over Canada. The store sells jewellery, clothing, ceramics, pillows, candles, soap, baby items, and so much more. You can also find the cutest Winnipeg-related items from local makers, including tea towels, cards, and coin purses. There’s also a gallery in the back of the shop, where art by local artists rotates every month. Everything in the boutique is quirky and lovely, and you can easily buy gifts for everyone on your list in a single stop.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;For the Little Ones: &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.toadhalltoys.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Toad Hall Toys&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;em&gt;54 Arthur St &lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h6&gt;
[caption id=&quot;attachment_2415&quot; align=&quot;aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BqX2UE9AEpW&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2415&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;12&#x2F;by-toadhalltoys-1024x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Toys, For All Families, The Exchange District, Toys Store, Downtown Winnipeg, Christmas Gifts, Unique Finds, Holidays&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; ? by @toadhalltoys on Instagram[&#x2F;caption]
&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to buy for a little one (or a grown-up who’s just a child at heart!) this holiday season, look no further than &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.toadhalltoys.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Toad Hall Toys&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. A Winnipeg staple since 1977, they carry books, miniatures, trains, puzzles, games, and much more from over 50 countries. Whether you’re buying supplies for an aspiring magician or a small scientist’s first microscope, their selection is massive! You can easily spend a nostalgic afternoon at Toad Hall Toys, lost in your own childhood memories.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;For Everyone: &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sogasoap.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;SoGa&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt; Artisan &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Soaperie&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;em&gt;84 1&#x2F;2 Albert St &lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h6&gt;
[caption id=&quot;attachment_2416&quot; align=&quot;aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;Bp-KN5AHyrb&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2416&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;12&#x2F;by-sogasoap.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Unique Finds in Exchange District, Downtown Winnipeg, Christmas Gifts, Soaperie&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; ? by @sogasoap on Instagram[&#x2F;caption]
&lt;p&gt;Everyone can benefit from &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sogasoap.com&#x2F;?v=3e8d115eb4b3&quot;&gt;SoGa&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the artisan soaperie where everything is handmade, vegan, and cruelty-free. It all smells good, looks good, and feels so, so good. They have beautiful soap slices of all scents and colours, activated charcoal bars, shower smoothies, gelato mini bubble scoops, and amazing bath snowballs. They even have a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sogasoap.com&#x2F;product&#x2F;go-jets-go-artisan-bar&#x2F;?v=3e8d115eb4b3&quot;&gt;soap for Jets fans&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;! All the products at SoGa make the perfect holiday gift: they’re small, smell lovely, and say, &lt;i&gt;hey, relax this holiday season—you deserve it&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:120,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:360}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re looking to buy for a friend, a family member, a loved one, or a colleague, skip the stress of going to the mall and head downtown for some of the most unique gifts in the city. I promise you’ll find something memorable for everyone on your list. Tell us—are you shopping local this holiday season?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
