<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Home - Living at 300Main Downtown Winnipeg - art-scene</title>
	<subtitle>We all love 300Main</subtitle>
	<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/art-scene/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2019-09-25T19:54:01+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/art-scene/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>White Night: A Tale of Nuit Blanche</title>
		<published>2019-09-25T19:54:01+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-09-25T19:54:01+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/white-night-a-tale-of-nuit-blanche/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/white-night-a-tale-of-nuit-blanche/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last summer, when whiteout parties were taking over whole blocks of downtown Winnipeg and all I saw were people in stylized white outfits, I knew there would be a white night I&#x27;d enjoy more in a few months. As an artist, poet and photographer, my favorite night of the year is always &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;nuitblanchewinnipeg.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Nuit Blanche&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-event&#x2F;nuit-blanche-2019&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often wonder where I’ll end up when Nuit Blanche finally arrives. There are a lot of options, and I find myself wondering where I should go on the longest night of art exhibitions in the city. Luckily, I didn&#x27;t have to worry about that for very long this year because friends of mine already had plans in place to start off the night.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Slam! All-Star Poets Compete For Your Scores!&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thombargen.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Thom Bargen Coffee and Tea&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having been a member of the spoken word community for a long time, I was pleased to be asked to perform at Winnipeg Poetry Slam’s Nuit Blanche event. I was also part of the Winnipeg Poetry Slam team for 2018, which later competed in the National Poetry Slam in Guelph, part of the Canadian Festival of Spoken Word.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Nuit Blanche, seven of us poets got together, and we gave art lovers a show to start off the night! It was a great opportunity for me because I was able to introduce new friends of mine to the spoken word community; they&#x27;d never been to a poetry slam before and had no idea what to expect. I find that these are often the best minds to have at a poetry slam, as they&#x27;re the most receptive and will get the most out of the poetry itself. With a small group of artists, poets, and other art enthusiasts in tow, I started us off on our journey through Nuit Blanche. Here are a few of the installations we saw as we ventured forth into the night.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: none; overflow: hidden;&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;plugins&#x2F;video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fnuitblanchewinnipeg%2Fvideos%2F171998770396697%2F&amp;amp;show_text=0&amp;amp;width=560&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.winnipegfreepress.com&#x2F;our-communities&#x2F;metro&#x2F;Whimsical-art-piece-a-first-for-Wolseley-artist-493489791.html&quot;&gt;&quot;Hand of the Machine&quot; by Solmund MacPherson&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wpl.winnipeg.ca&#x2F;library&#x2F;branchpages&#x2F;branch.aspx?mill&quot;&gt;Millennium Library&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Courtyard&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo courtesy of Nuit Blanche Winnipeg. Situated next to another installation (“&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipegarts.ca&#x2F;wac&#x2F;artwork&#x2F;emptyful&quot;&gt;emptyful&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;”) in the courtyard behind the Millennium Library was our first installation of the night: a massive and well-lit hand stretching out into the night air, with control levers that moved the fingers. In some cases, interactive art installations are built to last. But by the time we arrived, about an hour and a half into Nuit Blanche, the middle finger was broken and hanging limp in the middle of the palm. While we were there, I also saw the installation fall forward more than once, like a wrestler trying to tap out. Instead, someone picked it up and put it back into the fight. Before leaving we grabbed a few free books from the assortment the library had set up, and I played a game of oversized Connect 4.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&quot;No, I&#x27;ve never herd of bison&quot; by Kale Bonham and Todd Scott&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.upperfortgarry.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upper Fort Garry Provincial Park&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: none; overflow: hidden;&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;plugins&#x2F;post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fnuitblanchewinnipeg%2Fphotos%2Fa.1673473746070347%2F2146671585417225%2F%3Ftype%3D3&amp;amp;width=500&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;535&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I don&#x27;t think I appreciated this installation enough. It was a group of sound-activated bison next to the illumination board that lines the back side of Upper Fort Garry Park. When we got there, there wasn&#x27;t much noise to trigger the bison to react, so we moved on quickly. However, I&#x27;ve since seen images of the installation reacting to crowds of people, and it looks quite interesting!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;woodanchor.com&#x2F;img_0496&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&quot;Run For Your Lite&quot; by Wood Anchor and Cloverdale Forge&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.tourismwinnipeg.com&#x2F;things-to-do&#x2F;attractions&#x2F;display,listing&#x2F;05735&#x2F;esplanade-riel-pedestrian-bridge&quot;&gt;Esplanade Riel bridge&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; landing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a stop in &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theforks.com&#x2F;attractions&#x2F;the-forks-market&quot;&gt;The Forks Market&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to grab a bite to eat and a coffee, we moved on to the next few installations, but none caught my eye like this one. You could see the installation for what it was: Free energy. It took the form of a large wooden &amp;quot;hamster wheel&amp;quot; with a handle bar to grip, covered with lights and connected to turbines that would not only illuminate the installation but also power a nearby forge. The crowd was as loud as the machine itself, shouting support to friends who decided to try their hand at powering the forge!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: none; overflow: hidden;&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;plugins&#x2F;post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fnuitblanchewinnipeg%2Fposts%2F1895361463881573%3A0&amp;amp;width=500&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;622&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We sat and watched people compete to see who could keep running the longest, all the while drawing cheers of support from onlookers. It seemed like 5 to 8 minutes was the best folks could handle before the momentum started making them slip or lose their balance. It was definitely entertaining to watch as we ate the food we bought (seating inside was impossible to find) before walking up to Waterfront to move on to the Exchange District.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;connectingcities.net&#x2F;project&#x2F;control-no-control&quot;&gt;&quot;Control No Control&quot; by Daniel Iregui&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.winnipegarchitecture.ca&#x2F;shipping-container-exhibit&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&quot;Container Architecture&quot; by Winnipeg Architecture Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Bijou Park, East of Old Market Square&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;iframe title=&quot;vimeo-player&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;player.vimeo.com&#x2F;video&#x2F;57144334&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setup alongside Old Market Square, Bijou Park (which hosts Kids Fringe activities during the summer festival) hosted two displays during this year&#x27;s Nuit Blanche. On one side of the park, &amp;quot;Control No Control&amp;quot; featured a massive LED panel that reacted to both touch and sound input from the ever-growing crowd around it. On the other side of the park, nestled up to the side of Smoke&#x27;s Poutinerie, the Winnipeg Architecture Foundation set up a converted shipping container. It featured various other architectural projects around the world, showcasing the use of shipping containers as raw materials to build sustainable structures and housing. As a big supporter of sustainable living initiatives, this struck home with me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipegarts.ca&#x2F;wac&#x2F;artwork&#x2F;impulse&quot;&gt;&quot;Impulse&quot; presented by The Winnipeg Arts Council&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Old Market Square&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;embed&#x2F;ZRG4PMlY38Y&quot; width=&quot;324&quot; height=&quot;415&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest installations I’ve seen, &amp;quot;Impulse&amp;quot; was a collection of massive light-beam seesaws for riders of all ages. No matter how many videos or pictures I tried to take of this spectacle, none could do it justice. Every face in Old Market Square that night was filled with excitement and exhilaration!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were many other ways for everyone to enjoy Nuit Blanche last year, including community events, gallery shows, and live exhibitions throughout the night. I hope my memories of Nuit Blanche have inspired you to make some memories of your own this year!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark September 28 in your calendar, and share your favourite Nuit Blanche memories in the comments!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Exploring First Fridays in the Exchange</title>
		<published>2019-01-03T11:00:14+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-01-03T11:00:14+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/exploring-first-fridays-in-the-exchange/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/exploring-first-fridays-in-the-exchange/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the first Friday of every month, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.exchangedistrict.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Winnipeg’s Exchange District&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; comes alive as galleries, restaurants, and boutiques open their doors after-hours to welcome art and culture lovers. In December, I left the comfort of my warm couch to venture out for the last &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.firstfridayswinnipeg.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;First Fridays&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of 2018.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met up with a friend at 7 pm and started my night with a warm beverage and a snack at the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;amsterdamtearoom.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Amsterdam Tea Room&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (211 Bannatyne Avenue). Their recently-launched &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;amsterdamtearoom.com&#x2F;dinner-menu&#x2F;&quot;&gt;new menu&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; had popped up in several of my friends’ Instagram stories, and I was eager to try it myself. The last time I’d been there, it was a quaint little tea room; it’s since transformed into a busy, hip tea bar. We grabbed seats at the bar and I ordered a hot toddy and a small plate with crispy fingerling potatoes, charred onion, cucumber, celery, ketchup aioli, mustard seeds, sesame, and pecorino cheese. The server told me that if I took a little bit of all the components of the dish in one big bite, it would taste like a Big Mac—yum!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_2564&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;940&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2564 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;01&#x2F;IMG_5710-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Derek McCandless, Live Music, Amsterdam Tea Room, Exchange District, First Fridays in the Exchange, Downtown Winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;940&quot; height=&quot;627&quot; &#x2F;&gt; Winnipeg Folk Fest performer, Derek McCandless performing at Amsterdam Tea Room on First Fridays in the Exchange on December 7, 2018. Photo credits to the author[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live music from &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.derrickmccandless.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Derek McCandless&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; gave us a “Folk Fix” to get the evening started while we enjoyed our drinks. The bar was buzzing with people, the chatter blending seamlessly into his soothing voice and guitar notes. We made a game plan and left with our bellies full, ready to take on the night.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our next stop was at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.graffitigallery.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Graffiti Gallery&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (109 Higgins Avenue) for the opening reception of WOMAN GOOD BAD BAD: a series of all-new work by Winnipeg artist &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;gabriellewmfunk.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Gabrielle Funk&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The gallery floor was deliciously pink, and I fell in love instantly. Abstract pastel graphics on the walls seemed to blend in with the artwork. I later learned that the gallery is modified before every exhibition to match the artwork and create a cohesive experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People milled about the gallery with wine glasses and kombucha bottles, bobbing their heads to music from the DJ in the corner. There were free appetizers and a cash bar, and the artwork itself was beautiful. Most of the paintings were based on friends and family members of the artist, and the faces look extremely realistic yet surreal. Through this show, Funk explores the duality of the conventional representation of women in religion, art, and the media.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_2566&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignright&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;500&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2566&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;01&#x2F;IMG_5741-e1546452983620-683x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tara Davis Studio Boutique, First Fridays in the Exchange, Exchange District, Downtown Winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; &#x2F;&gt; A collection of painting by artist, Joshua Wilson at tara davis studio boutique. Photo credits to the author.[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We moved on to something lighter, heading over to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.taradavis.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Tara Davis Studio Boutique&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; next. It’s an eclectic and charming boutique at 246 McDermot Avenue, carrying womenswear, art, accessories, and home décor. The exhibit was called “12”—the 7th annual exhibition of 12 local artists showing 12 small works no larger than 12x12”. One of the collections that caught my attention was by Joshua Wilson, an artist who paints quirky pictures of animals with cigarettes. I really wanted to take home a painting of a crab with a cigarette, but I settled for a pair of mismatched purple socks with cacti on them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend and I parted ways, and I walked over to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.winnipegfilmgroup.com&#x2F;cinematheque&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Cinematheque&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (304-100 Arthur Street) for my last stop of the night: a screening of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;streamingmoviesright.com&#x2F;us&#x2F;movie&#x2F;sorry-to-bother-you&quot;&gt;SORRY TO BOTHER YOU&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, presented by Black Space Winnipeg. I was a little wary of going to this with just my popcorn for company, but in Winnipeg, six degrees of separation is a very real thing. I ran into friends from work and someone I went to school with, so I joined them for the movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cinematheque is one of those old-school movie theaters that brings back the romance of movie watching. The architecture of the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;art-space.ca&#x2F;artspace-building&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ArtSpace&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; building is stunning and the theatres are small and intimate. Before heading into the showing, I stopped at the bar for a glass of wine to go with my popcorn.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie started a little late, but no one seemed to mind. Written and directed by Boots Riley and starring &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.imdb.com&#x2F;name&#x2F;nm3147751&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Lakeith Stanfield&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Sorry to Bother You is a dystopian comedy that addresses societal issues like racism and commercialism. (The ending will leave you feeling unsettled in the best way possible.) It’s both thoughtful and hilarious, with tremendous actors.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was almost midnight by the time the movie ended. Over at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thetallestpoppy.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Tallest Poppy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (103 Sherbrook Street), &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.synonymartconsultation.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Synonym&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;’s First Friday After Party would be just starting to heat up. But after a full evening of soaking up culture and art, I was ready to head back home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By midnight, I had only managed to fit in four of the 36 great events happening that night. I hope to go back this week to catch some of the venues I missed. To stay up to date on all the amazing things happening on First Fridays in the Exchange, check out their website &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.firstfridayswinnipeg.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;firstfridayswinnipeg.org&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a few days before the monthly event.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have you explored First Fridays yet?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
