<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Home - Living at 300Main Downtown Winnipeg - jewelry-store-winnipeg</title>
	<subtitle>We all love 300Main</subtitle>
	<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/jewelry-store-winnipeg/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2018-10-28T11:00:54+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/jewelry-store-winnipeg/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Hidden Fashion Boutiques—Downtown and in the Exchange</title>
		<published>2018-10-28T11:00:54+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-10-28T11:00:54+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/hidden-fashion-boutiques-downtown-and-in-the-exchange/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/hidden-fashion-boutiques-downtown-and-in-the-exchange/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-71&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;10&#x2F;DSC01179-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;780&quot; height=&quot;520&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winnipeggers know the best boutique shopping is on Academy Road or in Osborne Village. But as the gentrification of downtown Winnipeg and the Exchange District gains momentum, more and more small businesses are popping up. Quaintly nestled within the large historic buildings of the downtown area, some of these shops are easy to miss if you don’t know where to look. Those with an eye for fashion might want to keep an eye out for these hidden fashion boutiques downtown and in the Exchange District.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lennard Taylor&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
246 McDermot Avenue
Since 2015
&lt;p&gt;This clothing store bears the name of its young designer. A boutique fashion house that designs and produces its own high-quality clothing for women, there is even opportunity at the back of the store for interested shoppers to watch how the clothing is produced. The style is both classic and modern at the same time; comfortable business wear or elevated casual wear. Lennard Taylor invites custom work and offers pieces of original art for sale.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;lennardtaylor.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;www.lennardtaylor.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Flaunt Boutique&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
106-270 Waterfront Drive
Since 2014
&lt;p&gt;This store is located on the first floor of one of the condo buildings on Waterfront Drive and is a worthwhile destination for those who value a unique fashion find. Flaunt Boutique is a new business venture for De Luca’s co-owner Kate Holden, showcasing clothing, shoes, handbags, and accessories for women. Every piece of merchandise is exclusive to their shop; these products are not available at any other location in&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winnipeg. It’s a compelling stop for evening and party wear, or to reinvent your look with a unique accessory or piece of jewellery.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;www.shopflaunt.ca&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Livestock Winnipeg&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
407 Graham Avenue
Since 2017
&lt;p&gt;On my first attempt to check out this shop, I completely missed it and kept walking. That’s a tribute to how hidden it is. This store is located at 407 Graham Avenue and is the thirds of its chain to open in Canada, following a store in Vancouver and another in Toronto. Livestock specializes in sneakers and modern streetwear. It’s unquestionably a top stop for the sneakerhead, or for anyone on a serious hunt for a pair of fashionable sneakers. Livestock Winnipeg carries men’s&#x2F;unisex clothing in-store and a smaller selection of women’s clothing online.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.deadstock.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;www.deadstock.ca&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Boutique Anya&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
88 Albert St.
Since 2015
&lt;p&gt;This little shop is locally owned and operated by designer Alicja Dalecki. It carries a curated collection of contemporary women’s clothing, housewares, statement jewelry, and environmentally-aware cosmetics. Created by both local and international designers, Boutique Anya’s products favour a minimalist design crafted from natural materials. You’ll find something unique, natural and beautiful here...and off the beaten track&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.boutiqueanya.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;www.boutiqueanya.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So forget the congestion of the mall and the monotony of shopping at another box store. Grab your fancy coffee downtown and make an afternoon of checking out these hidden gem boutiques with a friend. The chances are good it will be worth your while.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
