<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Home - Living at 300Main Downtown Winnipeg - culture</title>
	<subtitle>We all love 300Main</subtitle>
	<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/category/culture/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2019-06-20T10:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/category/culture/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>300 Main, Where the Future of Winnipeg Wants to Be</title>
		<published>2019-06-20T10:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-06-20T10:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/300-main-where-the-future-of-winnipeg-wants-to-be/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/300-main-where-the-future-of-winnipeg-wants-to-be/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Not only is downtown Winnipeg—home of arguably the best restaurants, historical architecture, and free live entertainment in the city—the future of Winnipeg and its economy, soon it will be home to the people that will help create that future!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve lived all over Winnipeg with over 30 moves, and I&#x27;ve experienced most of the lifestyles our city has to offer. Quite honestly, downtown is the only neighbourhood that really captures the magic of Winnipeg while sidestepping any of the inconveniences, and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;300 Main&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; snagged the perfect spot.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Winnipeg: Chicago of the North!&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
By now we’re all familiar with Winnipeg’s claim to fame but unfortunately, people are starting to wonder if that’s still relevant. I&#x27;m here to tell you why that reputation is more relevant than ever, and why you want to be at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;300 Main&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the building to kick it all off!
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: none; margin: 10px 0 0 0; overflow: hidden;&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;plugins&#x2F;post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2F300MainWinnipeg%2Fposts%2F1415526985256497&amp;amp;width=500&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;611&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;Chicago is a little bit ahead of us architecturally, aren’t they? The good news is, Winnipeg’s architects seem eager to catch up—and quick. The city’s center is rapidly expanding, and Winnipeggers are determined to show their southern sister that the cold doesn’t slow us down!
&lt;p&gt;You just can&#x27;t beat the convenience of living at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;300 Main&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, right at the underground mall that connects all the way down to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;portageplace.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Portage Place&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; via the skywalk system. You’ll never have to bear that true north wind, from your apartment door to your seat for the game at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bellmtsplace.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;BellMTS Place&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Just steps away, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cityplacewinnipeg.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;City Place&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is full of food, convenience stores, a liquor mart, and an indoor farmers market; it even connects to Winnipeg&#x27;s famous &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.sharkclub.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Shark Club&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for an affordable lunch special and maybe the occasional hand of cards between laundry flips.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if the skywalk system to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;portageplace.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Portage Place Mall&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; isn’t long enough, almost every main bus route in the city connects within a block from your front door. With all of Winnipeg&#x27;s top lounges and patios as your neighbors, you&#x27;ll never miss happy hour (or pay for parking) again!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;True North Strong &amp;amp; Your Neighbor&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
I noticed that in Chicago, the people who work downtown live in luxury high-rises nearby. As a tourist, I felt that it created a very safe environment and an exciting downtown nightlife. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.truenorthsquare.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;True North Square&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; will add yet another element to downtown’s exciting energy.
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: none; margin: 10px 0 0 0; overflow: hidden;&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;plugins&#x2F;post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Ftruenorthsquare%2Fposts%2F982376771934575&amp;amp;width=500&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;688&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;Think of it as a (new) central park for Winnipeg. Set to be 2 acres, with retail, restaurants, and a stage for live entertainment, no matter what you like doing, or who you&#x27;ll be there with, there will be something for everyone!
&lt;h3&gt;The sky’s the limit&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
But there&#x27;s one last reason why I and many others are particularly excited about &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;300 Main&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;; it&#x27;s really going to shake things up for our city! Coming in at 42 stories, it&#x27;ll be Winnipeg&#x27;s tallest building and I’m sure the city will soar just as high.
&lt;p&gt;With construction of Winnipeg’s most anticipated accommodations underway at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;300 Main&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, downtown is where the future of the city is literally being built. I believe that &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;300 Main&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is bringing culture and condos together, and I can’t wait to see what the future looks like in downtown Winnipeg.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>New to Networking? Start With Your Neighbours!</title>
		<published>2019-05-23T21:43:11+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-05-23T21:43:11+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/new-to-networking-start-with-your-neighbours/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/new-to-networking-start-with-your-neighbours/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Networking—a fancy term for a simple idea. Meet people, interact with them and build new relationships. We’re so used to networking through social media that the thought of physically interacting with people might sound a little bit alien. You could have 300 people on your &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ca.linkedin.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; network, another 300 on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and not know any of them well enough to know where they are from. Friendly relations between neighbours encourages real-life networking, and as old school as it may sound, it’s so valuable. Everyone has a story to tell, and you would probably miss the most interesting chapters if you had the same conversation online.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans are social by nature; we need to have meaningful conversations with other people to satisfy our natural instinct to know one another. Community meet-ups and common areas encourage networking with those around us. Networking doesn’t necessarily mean meeting with influential people who can help you professionally; it can also include people you can really connect with on an intellectual level. Many apartment buildings have common areas so people can lounge and get to know each other. Events like BBQs, pool parties, breakfasts and evening tea encourage tenants to get familiar with each other. While these events may seem like just a casual breakfast (free food!), they’re also opportunities to discuss concerns and get valuable information. For example, downtown apartment dwellers might be happy to learn about the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;downtownwinnipegbiz.com&#x2F;programs-services&#x2F;safety&#x2F;watch-ambassadors&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Downtown Watch Ambassadors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BwK8cMVg5YP&#x2F;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BwK8cMVg5YP&#x2F;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;A post shared by Downtown Winnipeg BIZ (@downtownwpgbiz)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot;font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-04-12T21:43:42+00:00&quot;&gt;Apr 12, 2019 at 2:43pm PDT&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Networking isn’t just about advancing your career; it’s also about bonds between neighbours, an important part of apartment living. Being on good terms with your neighbours means you have someone to turn to in case of an emergency, or just to call over for a cup of tea if you’re having a bad day and need someone to talk to. You can surround yourself with people you trust who can eventually become part of your support system. Good neighbours can end up feeling like family when you’re living alone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great thing about downtown Winnipeg is the strong sense of community that the area promotes. Most apartment buildings are designed to have spaces for general use. Downtown boasts wonderful cultural diversity, making networking even more fun! You can get to know people from varied backgrounds, find out first-hand details about other cultures, and learn about entirely different ways of life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My apartment building used to have the best BBQ parties for tenants where we would all just chat; it was fun to find out that I had a police officer and ballet dancer living on the same floor as me. At one BBQ, I saw a distinguished-looking gentleman hand over his business card to a student looking for an internship. It felt so good to be living in a community where people were looking out for each other and helping out where they could. These meet-ups can even help recent immigrants build their social circles and meet new people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-4665 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;05&#x2F;alexis-brown-85793-unsplash-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New to Networking? Start With Your Neighbours!&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These BBQs also gave me a unique chance to meet people from different cultural backgrounds. The chance to listen to stories about what they did and experienced “back home” was really special.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next time you’re invited to a breakfast in your apartment building, think twice before deciding you’d rather sleep in than get up early and meet new people. You might meet someone who can open your eyes to a new view of the world!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BBQs, breakfasts, and boardgame nights are just a few examples of great ways to make friends with your neighbours. What’s your favourite way to meet new people?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Getting Around Winnipeg without a Car (Yes, it’s Possible!)</title>
		<published>2019-05-17T15:04:28+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-05-17T15:04:28+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/getting-around-winnipeg-without-a-car-yes-its-possible/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/getting-around-winnipeg-without-a-car-yes-its-possible/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever considered the best ways to get around Winnipeg without a car? You might scoff and think there’s no way you want to move around this frigid city without one, but not everyone has access to a vehicle. Others are also worried about the environmental damage cars do.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone who doesn’t drive, I’ve spent all of my adult life trying to move around cities without a vehicle. And I promise you, you can do it. Let’s look at your options.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipegtransit.com&#x2F;en&quot;&gt;Winnipeg Transit&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
You can ride the good ol’ bus to move around our city. The service isn’t great from some outlying suburban areas, but you can reach most everywhere by bus. And it’s easy to figure out, too. There’s a Winnipeg Transit app you can download onto your phone. You can also use the Winnipeg Transit &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;m.winnipegtransit.com&#x2F;navigo&quot;&gt;Navigo website&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_4648&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;1024&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-4648&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;05&#x2F;IMG_2416-1024x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Winnipeg Transit, Downtown Winnipeg, Winnipeg, 300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt; Very Canadian[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With either version, you enter your departing address, your destination, and the time you need to arrive or leave. Navigo will then show you all your options to get where you are going, including walking time and time between transfers. You can also monitor a particular stop if you want to see when buses will arrive. The app&#x2F;website shows where buses are in real time by tracking the fleet with GPS. This takes the guesswork out of knowing when your bus will arrive, which is particularly helpful on nasty weather days. The city could do better with transit, and we need more rapid transit routes, but this is one way you can get around Winnipeg.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need to get around downtown, you can hop aboard one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipegtransit.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;service&#x2F;downtownspirit&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Downtown Spirit buses&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. They take a couple of different routes through the downtown area. The best part? &lt;strong&gt;The Downtown Spirit is always free!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Your Bike&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
If you want to stay in shape and avoid all carbon emissions, cycling might be the way to go. And yes, you can cycle here year-round. (At least if you’re the hardy type.) The advent of fat bike tires can help you with winter cycling.
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BbiIIHEBsQ_&#x2F;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin: 8px 0 0 0; padding: 0 4px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #000; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none; word-wrap: break-word;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BbiIIHEBsQ_&#x2F;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;In Winnipeg, we never put our bikes away... we just let some air out of the tires and go about our day!! . . . #canon60D #donsaction #Winnipeg #exploremb #explorecanada #artofvisuals #visualsgang #royalsnappingartist #way2ill #gramslayers #cityscape #paradisecanada #TrailsManitoba #exploreeverything #onlyinthepeg #allthingswinnipeg #visualscollective #world_great #discoverearth #discoverglobe #imagesofcanada #tourcanada #paradisecanada #moodygrams #agameoftones #vscogram #visualambassadors #visualcreators #canadagram #winteriscoming&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;joshuaa_blade&#x2F;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt; Josh&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (@joshuaa_blade) on &lt;time style=&quot;font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-11-15T22:49:05+00:00&quot;&gt;Nov 15, 2017 at 2:49pm PST&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you can cycle all city streets in Winnipeg, not everyone loves sharing the road with larger, faster moving cars. The city does have a series of dedicated bike routes, including downtown bike lanes. If you aren’t sure where to find these, the city provides a number of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipeg.ca&#x2F;publicworks&#x2F;pedestriansCycling&#x2F;maps&#x2F;default.stm&quot;&gt;bike maps to help you plan your trip&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biking is a great way to see Winnipeg, particularly many of our downtown parks and pretty spaces!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Your Feet&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Another great way to get in your daily exercise and protect the environment is by simply using your feet to move you from point A to point B. I used to live in &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.osbornevillage.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Osborne Village&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and walked to work downtown every day, even in -35 degree weather.
&lt;p&gt;You can’t walk everywhere, but consider walking for your shorter trips. You will need good shoes (or good winter boots with grip) to stay comfortable, but those are far cheaper than a car. Wearing a good base layer or snow pants with your coat, hat and mitts can keep you nice and toasty in the winter. You also generate a fair amount of body heat when you’re moving around. Just make sure you invest in good quality gear; the super-cheap stuff might leave you too cold or too sweaty under your coat.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walking is great for your health, as is spending time outdoors in general. It can be difficult to walk down sidewalks in winter before the plows come up, but you can use the street instead (in residential areas). Or, you could truly embrace our winters and pull out your snowshoes!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downtown is a great place to walk, particularly around &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theforks.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Forks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mhs.mb.ca&#x2F;docs&#x2F;sites&#x2F;jubapark.shtml&quot;&gt;Stephen Juba Park&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. You will find many pretty things to see as you promenade along the water. In the winter, you can walk on the Red or Assiniboine and see all of the delightful &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.warminghuts.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;warming huts near the Forks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.tappcar.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Tapp Car&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
There might be times when you need to get somewhere that isn’t easily accessible except by car. You can use our local taxi services, but I quite enjoy Tapp Car, Winnipeg’s answer to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.uber.com&#x2F;ca&#x2F;en&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Uber&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.lyft.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Lyft&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. We have a few other rideshare services in the city, but I can only vouch for Tapp Car, which was the first player here.
&lt;p&gt;They have an easy-to-use app that shows how long it will take your car to get to you, and shows the car make, model, colour and license plate, along with your driver’s name. This is nice to know for safety reasons. The cars are always clean, and the drivers are generally friendly. You set up payment directly in the app, so you don’t have to fuss with cash or a debit machine when you arrive at your destination. You can step out of the car as soon as you’ve arrived.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BftJZrshPAO&#x2F;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin: 8px 0 0 0; padding: 0 4px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #000; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none; word-wrap: break-word;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BftJZrshPAO&#x2F;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Excited?! They&#x27;ll be on Winnipeg streets as of Friday. -Scott (Tom &amp;amp; Kerri) #TappCar @tappcar #winnipeg #manitoba #canada #ridesharing #friday #943thedrive #tomandkerri #uber #lyft&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;943thedrive&#x2F;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt; 94-3 The Drive&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (@943thedrive) on &lt;time style=&quot;font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-02-27T15:37:26+00:00&quot;&gt;Feb 27, 2018 at 7:37am PST&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rates are similar to what you’d pay for a taxi, so it’s not going to cost you any more of your hard-earned cash. Tapp Car has a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.tappcar.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;website&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and an app you can download to your phone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tapp Car is also a great option if you are going out but want to do some drinking. You won’t have to worry about imbibing too much to drive yourself safely home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bottom Line&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Having your own car can be great, but it’s not the only way to move around. If you want or need other options, you’ve got them. You don’t need to stay at home hibernating! Get out and see more of our fair city.
&lt;p&gt;If you have tips about getting around Winnipeg without a car, share them in the comments!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Spring in Downtown: Events You Won’t Want to Miss</title>
		<published>2019-04-23T17:17:27+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-04-23T17:17:27+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/spring-in-downtown-events-you-wont-want-to-miss/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/spring-in-downtown-events-you-wont-want-to-miss/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As the snow begins to melt and the weather turns itself up a notch, it’s finally time for Winnipeggers to celebrate spring! What better way then attending some of Winnipeg’s most talked-about spring events?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theforks.com&#x2F;events&#x2F;calendar-of-events&#x2F;event&#x2F;248&quot;&gt;UnCommon Pours V05: Spring Wine List Launch&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;April 26, &lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5-7 pm&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_4377&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;1024&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theforks.com&#x2F;events&#x2F;calendar-of-events&#x2F;event&#x2F;248&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-4377 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;04&#x2F;FOR-7479-Uncommon-Pours-V5-ΓÇô-April-25_26Facebook-Event-Header-ΓÇô-April-25-26-1024x536.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;UnCommon Pours V05, Spring Wine List Launch, The Common, The Forks, Downtown Winnipeg events, 300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;536&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; UnCommon Pours V05: Spring Wine List Launch with Sommelier Veronique Rivest[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking for a casual night out spent sipping wine and chatting with friends? &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theforks.com&#x2F;eat-and-drink&#x2F;dine&#x2F;the-common&quot;&gt;The Common at the Forks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; will be updating their wine list for spring, and they’re inviting Winnipeggers to join them in a tasting. Sommelier Veronique Rivest will also incorporate a bit of “schooling” on wine vocabulary and what characteristics make a good wine. There will be seatings at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.eventbrite.ca&#x2F;e&#x2F;uncommon-pours-v05-spring-wine-list-launch-with-sommelier-veronique-rivest-tickets-59248979292&quot;&gt;5 pm&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.eventbrite.ca&#x2F;e&#x2F;uncommon-pours-v05-spring-wine-list-launch-with-sommelier-veronique-rivest-tickets-59249423621&quot;&gt;6 pm&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, with different tasting selections at each seating.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tickets&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
$20 (includes flight and guided tasting)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Venue&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
The Commons (located at the Forks)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;downtownwinnipegbiz.com&#x2F;programs-services&#x2F;events&#x2F;earth-day-clean-up&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Earth Day Clean-Up&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;April 29&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_4379&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;1024&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;downtownwinnipegbiz.com&#x2F;programs-services&#x2F;events&#x2F;earth-day-clean-up&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-4379&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;04&#x2F;DWB_EarthDay_web-banner_2018-1024x512.png&quot; alt=&quot;2019 Earth Day Cleanup, Downtown Winnipeg Biz, Downtown Winnipeg Events, 300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;512&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; 2019 Earth Day Cleanup[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winnipeg can take a real beating over the course of the winter. Trash accumulates under layers of snow and ice, and once the melt starts it’s a real bummer to look at! Winnipeg will be holding its annual Earth Day Cleanup, with volunteers picking up trash in the downtown area with the help of reusable bags, gloves and garbage bags. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;downtownwinnipegbiz.com&#x2F;programs-services&#x2F;events&#x2F;earth-day-clean-up&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Register online&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to receive a free Earth Day Cleanup reusable bag, gloves, garbage bags, and a garbage picker to use for the event.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Venue&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
9-11 am at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;thunderbirdhouse.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Circle of Life Thunderbird House&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (715 Main Street)
2-4 pm at &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipeglibraryfoundation.ca&#x2F;tour-the-park&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Millennium Library Park&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;thirdandbirdevents.com&#x2F;spring-market&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Third + Bird Spring Market&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;May 4, &lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 am-6 pm
&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 5, &lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11 am-4 pm&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_4381&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;1024&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;thirdandbirdevents.com&#x2F;spring-market&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-4381&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;04&#x2F;51991349_2424267004267383_2651302536094416896_o-1024x390.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Third + Bird Spring Market, Shop Local, Downtown Winnipeg Events, 300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; 2019 Third + Bird Spring Market[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;thirdandbirdevents.com&#x2F;spring-market&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Third + Bird&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; should be at the top of your list of things to check out this spring! This market showcases over 150 &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;thirdandbirdevents.com&#x2F;our-vendors&#x2F;&quot;&gt;vendors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for Winnipeggers to check out.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Located in Hudson’s Bay Downtown, Third + Bird’s spring market also includes a café and a cocktail bar to help you maintain your energy while you shop. The market is known for not only its unmatched shopping experience but it’s creative visuals, top-end food and drink selection, and the infectious energy that greets you as soon as you walk through the doors. Pro tip: If you’re serious about shopping, consider buying a ticket to the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.eventbrite.ca&#x2F;e&#x2F;earlybird-preshop-tickets-58465507908&quot;&gt;preshop on May 3&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. You’ll get early access to the market, and it also includes entry for May 4 and 5.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tickets&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
$8 &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.eventbrite.ca&#x2F;e&#x2F;third-bird-general-admission-tickets-58317443042&quot;&gt;online&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; | $10 at the door&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Venue&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;locations.thebay.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;hudsons-bay-winnipeg-downtown&quot;&gt;Hudson’s Bay Downtown&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; ((450 Portage Avenue)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;dtwpgfarmersmkt&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Downtown Farmers’ Market&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;April 25 and Thursdays all summer, &lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 am-3 pm&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_4382&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;851&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;dtwpgfarmersmkt&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-4382&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;04&#x2F;50337815_774326066280925_5468007694436663296_n.png&quot; alt=&quot;Downtown Winnipeg events, Downtown Winnipeg Farmers&#x27; Market, Shop Local, &quot; width=&quot;851&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; 2019 Downtown Winnipeg Farmers&#x27; Market[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find some of Winnipeg’s finest vendors, makers and bakers at the downtown farmers’ market, which showcases the best of what’s made in Manitoba.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tickets
&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;Free&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Venue&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cityplacewinnipeg.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Cityplace&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (333 St. Mary Avenue)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.manitoahbee.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Manito Ahbee Festival&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;May 15-19&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_4384&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;851&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.manitoahbee.com&#x2F;events&#x2F;schedule&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-4384&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;04&#x2F;44677351_1970720492966939_3939445262040170496_n.png&quot; alt=&quot;Manito Ahbee Festival, Spring Downtown events, Downtown Winnipeg events, 300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments&quot; width=&quot;851&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; 2019 Manito Ahbee Festival[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Celebrate Indigenous art, culture and music in Winnipeg with the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.manitoahbee.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;2019 Manito Ahbee Festival&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Join the crowds soaking in the music, watch talented dancers, and learn something about Indigenous culture and heritage.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 15&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Kick off and Lighting of the Sacred Fire&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 16 and 17&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Indigenous Music Conference&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 17&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Youth Education Day and Indigenous Music Awards&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 18&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Get Jiggy with It&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 18-19&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Indigenous Marketplace &amp;amp; Trade Show, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.manitoahbee.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Manito Ahbee Pow Wo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;w&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tickets&#x2F;Venue&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
Various; visit &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.manitoahbee.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;manitoahbee.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for details.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.doorsopenwinnipeg.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Doors Open Winnipeg&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;May 25 and 26&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_4385&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;851&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.doorsopenwinnipeg.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-4385&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;04&#x2F;36815690_1735172059896251_2752655728396206080_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Doors Open Winnipeg, Downtown Winnipeg events, 300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments&quot; width=&quot;851&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; 2019 Doors Open Winnipeg[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking for a spring weekend activity with a bit of light exercise? The 16th annual Doors Open Winnipeg event by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.heritagewinnipeg.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Heritage Winnipeg&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; might be just the ticket—without requiring a ticket. Explore over 90 of Winnipeg’s most fascinating buildings on a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.doorsopenwinnipeg.ca&#x2F;walkingtours&#x2F;&quot;&gt;walking tour&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or get pedalling and join a bike tour! If you love history or are just curious about what remarkable buildings Winnipeg has to offer, this is the event for you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tickets&#x2F;Venue&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
Various; visit &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.doorsopenwinnipeg.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;doorsopenwinnipeg.ca&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for details.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spring is looking jam-packed for Winnipeg! Tell us: what event you are most excited to check out?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Finding the One: Choosing an Apartment in Winnipeg</title>
		<published>2019-02-07T11:00:16+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-02-07T11:00:16+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/finding-the-one-choosing-an-apartment-in-winnipeg/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/finding-the-one-choosing-an-apartment-in-winnipeg/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finding a new space to call home is an undertaking that can require serious time and energy. But apartment hunting can also be fun and exhilarating! With a bit of planning, you can avoid a headache and find a home you’re ready to commit to—at least until the lease is up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Scope out the Neighbourhood&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
Your neighbourhood has an enormous influence on your life, and there are a few very important things to consider when picking your perfect downtown neighbourhood.
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you research what sort of neighbourhood you seek to best fit your lifestyle. For example, if you like being in the center of everything, consider streets in the core of downtown Winnipeg. Streets like Graham, Garry and some areas of Portage Avenue are a five-minute walk from popular bars, restaurants and Bell MTS Place.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for somewhere more cosmopolitan, right in the middle of a richly varied area—the Exchange District may be your perfect match! This vibrant neighbourhood boasts many of Winnipeg’s one-of-a-kind boutiques, coffee shops, bars and restaurants. Also, it’s near the Centennial Concert Hall and Winnipeg’s own China Town.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BtNESe3AwDL&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BtNESe3AwDL&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;A post shared by @andrewmahon&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot;font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-01-29T03:56:35+00:00&quot;&gt;Jan 28, 2019 at 7:56pm PST&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in a more laid-back neighbourhood that’s still close to entertainment, check out West Broadway. It’s known for being an unofficial boundary between the hustle bustle commercial parts of downtown and the residential areas, so you get the best of both worlds. Backing onto the Assiniboine River, it’s a picturesque area with elm tree canopies over streets and beautiful historic buildings.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do some extra exploring around the area to make sure it has your must-haves for a neighbourhood. Keep an eye out for nearby grocery stores, drugstores, and bus stops.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When walking around the streets outside a potential apartment, do you feel at home? Can you picture yourself showing your friends and family around the streets near the building? That’s a good sign.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Size Does Matter&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
When looking for somewhere to call home, you might start to feel like Goldilocks trying to find just the right size. Starting your apartment hunt with your basic space needs figured out will make a world of difference. Consider the following for determining the square feet of your future living space.
&lt;p&gt;Do you own a lot of larger-scale furniture that needs to be accommodated—such as a pool table, a piano or a bulky sectional sofa? How many bedrooms and bathrooms do you want? Are you the type to spend a ton of time in your bedroom, or do you need a spacious living room? Do you love to host parties and need seating for your entourage?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re moving from one place to another, you might want to look for something close to the same size. If you are moving into a larger place remember that you’ll have to shell out money to fill it with furniture—an empty apartment just doesn’t feel homey!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And don’t forget about storage: how much stuff do you need to store? When touring a place or even just looking at a listing on Kijiji, pay attention to the number and size of closets. Look for a bathroom closet, kitchen storage (like cupboards or a pantry) and a coat closet. A lack of storage space can go unnoticed until move-in day when you don’t know where you’re going to store your cleaning supplies or winter coats.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Nancy Drew that Apartment&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
There’s nothing worse than moving into an apartment and finding unpleasant surprises in the crooks and crannies, so put on that detective hat. When you view a potential apartment, look closely at ceilings, walls and floors for any cracks, stains or other damage. Check the appliances: open the refrigerator and the oven and try out the sink faucets. Look for signs of wear and tear; these may not be necessarily deal-breakers for you, but something to alert the landlord about so you don’t get dinged on your security deposit.
&lt;p&gt;Also, check the cellphone reception in every room! Cellphones are a huge part of our lives so make sure you walk around the apartment checking your service bars or sending a quick text or two.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scope out the Neighbours&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
If you pass someone living inside the apartment building you’re touring, say hello! Whether they say hello back, stop to chat or just walk right by will give you an idea of what your potential neighbours are like.
&lt;p&gt;The perfect neighbours only exist in Hallmark movies, but you do want to feel comfortable with the people around you. It depends on the type of person you are but having neighbours that you can at least smile at in the hallways might be important to you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Identify Must-Have Amenities&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
These are different for everyone, but here are three that we consider deal-breakers:
&lt;p&gt;A dishwasher: You can theoretically live without a dishwasher—but for the sake of your sanity and the environment, look for an apartment with one.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An elevator: Stairs may help you with your step counter on your FitBit, but on move-in day, when you’re trying to move your couch up three flights of stairs, you’ll be kicking yourself for renting the place!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laundry facilities: Take it from someone who is a serial renter: an on-site laundry room is the holy grail of apartment living. Having to lug all your dirty clothes back and forth from a laundromat is a pain. Do yourself a favour and put a laundry room on your list of non-negotiables.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Trust Your Instincts&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
We don&#x27;t call the places where we live home without a reason. If the price is right but something just feels wrong—even if you can’t pinpoint what—trust that feeling and keep searching. The right apartment should be your home base, your personal launchpad for taking on the day and where you can cozy up to recharge.
&lt;p&gt;Have some pro tips for scoring the perfect apartment? Share your wisdom with us in the comments!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Making Downtown Your First Home in Winnipeg</title>
		<published>2019-01-17T11:00:52+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-01-17T11:00:52+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/making-downtown-your-first-home-in-winnipeg/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/making-downtown-your-first-home-in-winnipeg/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Henry glanced at his watch as he gulped down his coffee, standing outside the Tim Hortons on Portage Avenue. He would be on time for his career counselling session at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;manitobastart.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Manitoba Start&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, just a few blocks away. This was his first session, and he breathed an inward sigh of relief that such a great resource was so close to his apartment building. He had just arrived last week and was eager to get settled. Securing a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.gov.mb.ca&#x2F;health&#x2F;mhsip&#x2F;mbcard.html&quot;&gt;Manitoba Health Card&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and finding a family doctor had been fairly easy. He had even been able to use the free services of the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipegtransit.com&#x2F;service&#x2F;downtownspirit&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Downtown Spirit&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; bus since everything was within a few blocks of his new apartment in downtown.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BhrT9cyHBbK&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BhrT9cyHBbK&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;A post shared by Downtown Winnipeg BIZ (@downtownwpgbiz)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot;font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-04-17T15:34:01+00:00&quot;&gt;Apr 17, 2018 at 8:34am PDT&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As he walked to his destination, Henry cast a cursory glance around him. He was amazed at the diversity; people of all ethnicities and ages walked past him, in harmony with each other yet comfortably oblivious to their own surroundings. He noticed people rushing to work, too rushed to drink their coffee yet taking the time to hold open doors for others. He was falling in love with his new home! He felt a sense of belonging and was already looking forward to the weekend. He had seen posters for &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.manyfest.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ManyFest&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and was excited to be living a short walk from where all the action would be. As he rushed across the cross walk, he thought about his plans for the coming weekend: the festival, a visit to the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wpl.winnipeg.ca&#x2F;library&#x2F;&quot;&gt;public library&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to check out their collection and perhaps some Indian cuisine at a nearby restaurant. He realized he was talking to himself as he entered the the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;downtownwinnipegbiz.com&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2013&#x2F;06&#x2F;downtown_winnipeg_indoor_walkway_map_2013.pdf&quot;&gt;Downtown Winnipeg Indoor Walkway (lovingly known as the skywalk by locals)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to escape the gust of wind that threatened to sweep away the documents that he had been carrying. He shook his head, smiling. He couldn’t wait to get back to his apartment to finish settling in. His days now began with sipping his morning tea while waiting for the sun to light up the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.gov.mb.ca&#x2F;legislature&#x2F;visiting&#x2F;docs&#x2F;goldenboy_factsheet.pdf&quot;&gt;Golden Boy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as it serenely overlooked downtown. For the tenth time that day, he made a mental note to thank the friend who had suggested he find a place downtown to start his new life in Winnipeg.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BrMdU1xga5f&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BrMdU1xga5f&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;A post shared by Heather’s iPhotos (@heathers.iphotos)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot;font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-12-10T05:13:20+00:00&quot;&gt;Dec 9, 2018 at 9:13pm PST&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting a new life in an unfamiliar city can be unnerving. Resources are limited, expectations are high and there is always too much to do. That’s why it is important to choose a location that can help you get things done on the fast track. Living at the heart of the city and near all the major institutions not only saves precious time, but also gives the added advantage of being mobile even if you’re not ready to own a vehicle. It’s cost-effective to be able to walk to most places which is exactly what you’re looking for when starting your life in a new city. Better to burn calories than cents when you’re relying on your savings!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downtown Winnipeg is also a great place to network, which is invaluable when you’re adjusting to a new culture and looking for a job in your field. You need to be at the right place at the right time. Fortunately, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.canada.ca&#x2F;en&#x2F;employment-social-development&#x2F;corporate&#x2F;portfolio&#x2F;service-canada.html&quot;&gt;Service Canada&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;portageplace.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Portage Place&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; offers free resources for job seekers. If you need to focus, search for a job and print a few resumes, make use of their free computer and printing services.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 540px; min-width: 326px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;Bdm6jzJA_3Y&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; height: 50px; margin: 0 auto 12px; width: 50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #3897f0; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 550; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #f4f4f4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;Bdm6jzJA_3Y&#x2F;?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_medium=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;A post shared by @simplicityshots&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot;font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-01-06T12:29:31+00:00&quot;&gt;Jan 6, 2018 at 4:29am PST&lt;&#x2F;time&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
And in case you’re wondering, downtown Winnipeg is definitely not an “all work and no play” kind of place. Looking to relax after a long working week? That’s the beauty of downtown: it’s home to a lot of tourist attractions and entertainment spots. Whether it’s a stroll through the beautiful grounds at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theforks.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Forks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;downtownwinnipegbiz.com&#x2F;programs-services&#x2F;events&#x2F;movies-on-memorial&#x2F;&quot;&gt;movie in Memorial Park&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, everything is within reach. If you need to use &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipegtransit.com&#x2F;en&quot;&gt;Winnipeg Transit&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, most major bus routes run right through downtown, making it easy to get around! There are convenient options for grocery shopping, and a plethora of ethnic stores makes for a diverse retail environment that caters to a multicultural community.
&lt;p&gt;And downtown Winnipeg is exceptionally multicultural. You’ll see Diwali celebrations happening amidst decorations waiting for the Christmas season to gain momentum, and people rushing for Eid prayers right after Easter wraps up. There is something for everyone here: the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wag.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Winnipeg Art Gallery (WAG)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for the art enthusiast who wants to analyse each piece, free yoga classes in Memorial Park for the fitness freak, and tons of delectable dining options for the foodie. And in case you’re all three, everything is always only a few blocks away! &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.downtownwinnipegbiz.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Downtown Winnipeg Biz&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a great resource for finding ways to experience the best Winnipeg has to offer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about starting a new chapter of your life in Winnipeg, look no further than downtown—and I mean literally! Be where the government services are, where the action is and where breakfast meets business.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re new to Winnipeg or considering relocating, what else would you like to know? Tell us in the comments!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Three Hidden Cultural Gems Downtown</title>
		<published>2018-11-29T11:00:48+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-11-29T11:00:48+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/three-hidden-cultural-gems-downtown/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/three-hidden-cultural-gems-downtown/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every Winnipegger knows about the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wag.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Winnipeg Art Gallery&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;humanrights.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Canadian Museum for Human Rights&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;manitobamuseum.ca&#x2F;main&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Manitoba Museum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, right? They are all lovely places to visit alone or with out-of-town guests, but your downtown options don’t end there! Once you&#x27;ve toured these greats, what other cultural gems can you visit? Here are three you may not know about.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;oseredok.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Oseredok&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;—A Chance to Witness Some Ukrainian Cultural Heritage&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-610 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;11&#x2F;IMG_3696-2-300x300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Outside of Oseredok&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-608 aligncenter&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: 20px;&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;11&#x2F;IMG_3680-2-300x300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ukranian couch, Ukranian throw pillows, Ukranian museum&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone in Winnipeg seems to either have Ukrainian heritage or knows somebody who does. Did you know we’ve got our own Ukrainian cultural centre and museum at the edge of downtown? Oseredok has two floors of changing exhibits and a gift shop. The exhibits change every four to six weeks, so you can go back frequently to see new things. During my visit, the second floor held a charming array of quilts, pillows and other stitched items of art.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The staff members I spoke to were friendly and answered all of my questions. The museum is small, so it’s a great place to go when you want a quick visit. And if you’re trying to save your pennies, good news: visiting Oseredok is free of charge!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The centre also offers a few public workshops each year, including a chance to learn the art of egg painting at Easter time and how to cook food for Ukrainian Christmas.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;If You Go&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oseredok is located at 184 Alexander Avenue East. Admission is free. Current visiting hours are Monday to Saturday, 10 am to 4 pm. You can check out the museum online at &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;oseredok.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;oseredok.ca&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.sportmanitoba.ca&#x2F;canada-games-centre&quot;&gt;Manitoba Sports Hall of Fame&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
If you decide to visit Oseredok, you might as well make it a two-for-one day! The
&lt;p&gt;Manitoba Sports Hall of Fame is just steps away, located in the sparkly new &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.sportmanitoba.ca&#x2F;canada-games-centre&quot;&gt;Canada Games Sports for Life Centre&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, you can see some of Manitoba’s sports history and learn about our greatest athletes and sporting achievements. This is another small museum that’s perfect for an afternoon visit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current exhibit looks at Manitoba sports through the decades, with a focus on athletes who also served in Canada’s military. This exhibit is to honour the 100th anniversary of the end of the Great War. You’ll get the chance to read about our athletes (including Bobby Hull), view a nice array of sports memorabilia, and watch a video or two. The exhibits change about once per year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-623 size-full&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;11&#x2F;IMG_3702.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sport Manitoba, Sport for Life Centre&quot; width=&quot;710&quot; height=&quot;994&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;If You Go&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The museum and the Canada Games Sports Centre for Life are located at 145 Pacific Avenue at the edge of downtown. (Note: there is no entry from Alexander Street)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current visiting hours are:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday, Friday and Saturday from 10 am to 4 pm&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday and Thursday from 12 pm to 8 pm&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admission is $5 for adults, $3 for teens and seniors, and just $2 for children 12 and under. You can visit their website at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.sportmanitoba.ca&#x2F;hall-of-fame&quot;&gt;sportmanitoba.ca&#x2F;hall-of-fame&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.friendsofdalnavert.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Dalnavert Museum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
My favourite of the three museums I visited is Dalnavert Museum. It’s a Victorian house built in 1895 that was occupied by one-time Manitoba premier &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.friendsofdalnavert.ca&#x2F;hugh-john-personal-and-career&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Hugh John Macdonald&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who was also known for his family relations. (His father was Canada’s first prime minister, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.canadahistory.com&#x2F;sections&#x2F;politics&#x2F;pm&#x2F;johnmacdonald.htm&quot;&gt;John A. Macdonald&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.) Hugh’s family lived in the home until 1929. It was taken over and turned into a museum in the 1970s.
&lt;p&gt;You can take guided tours through the building, which shows off Victorian architecture and furnishings. It’s a great spot for history and architecture buffs, and the guides are knowledgeable and always willing to answer questions. (Guided tours take 45 minutes to an hour)&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-637&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;11&#x2F;IMG_3756.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dalnavert Museum, Historic Site, Ancient, Classic Interior&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;571&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourite reason for visiting Dalnavert is for the events they run throughout the year, especially at Christmas time!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The museum has done &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.friendsofdalnavert.ca&#x2F;new-events&#x2F;2018&#x2F;12&#x2F;20&#x2F;a-christmas-carol-reading&quot;&gt;readings of A Christmas Carol&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.friendsofdalnavert.ca&#x2F;new-events&#x2F;2017&#x2F;12&#x2F;15&#x2F;its-a-wonderful-life-a-live-radio-play&quot;&gt;radio play version of It’s a Wonderful Life&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. You can enjoy the festivities while nibbling baked treats and imbibing hot cider, mulled wine or hot chocolate. This year, they’re hosting several lecture series covering topics including &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.friendsofdalnavert.ca&#x2F;new-events&#x2F;2018&#x2F;11&#x2F;4&#x2F;lecture-series-jane-austen-reading-series&quot;&gt;Jane Austen&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.friendsofdalnavert.ca&#x2F;new-events&#x2F;2018&#x2F;12&#x2F;16&#x2F;charles-dickens-the-man-behind-the-carol&quot;&gt;Charles Dickens&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.friendsofdalnavert.ca&#x2F;new-events&#x2F;2018&#x2F;12&#x2F;2&#x2F;victorian-ghost-stories&quot;&gt;Victorian ghosts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I attended a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.friendsofdalnavert.ca&#x2F;new-events&#x2F;2016&#x2F;12&#x2F;12&#x2F;clue-at-the-museum&quot;&gt;Clue&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; board game night there last year, which featured talented actors playing out the murder scene in different rooms of the mansion!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If You Go&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dalnavert is located at 61 Carlton Street (south of Broadway). Winter visiting hours are Wednesday to Sunday, 12 pm to 4 pm. The hours change throughout the year, so check their website before you go. Admission is $6 for adults, $5 for students and seniors, and&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$4 for children. To find out what intriguing events they have coming up next, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.friendsofdalnavert.ca&quot;&gt;friendsofdalnavert.ca&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Important note: because they haven’t changed the original structure of the building, the second and third floors are not wheelchair accessible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;These Aren’t The Only Museums Downtown!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
Oseredok, the Sports Hall of Fame and Dalnavert are just three of downtown Winnipeg’s lesser-known museums. There are others you can visit, such as the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wpgrailwaymuseum.com&#x2F;home.html&quot;&gt;Winnipeg Railway Museum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;winnipeg.ca&#x2F;police&#x2F;Museum&#x2F;default.stm&quot;&gt;Winnipeg Police Museum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;Winnipeg is so full of history, we pass by so many of these cultural gems each day without giving them a second glance. If you want to enjoy everything your downtown home has to offer, make sure to visit them!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Is your personal favourite missing from this list? Let us know in the comments!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo credits to the author&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>East vs. West Exchange</title>
		<published>2018-11-15T11:00:13+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-11-15T11:00:13+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/east-vs-west-exchange/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/east-vs-west-exchange/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Winnipeg’s world-famous Exchange District has more to offer than just great architecture. This vibrant, eclectic area is our hub of arts and culture, and it’s only a few blocks from your doorstep.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Exchange is known by Winnipeggers as one neighbourhood, it’s split down the middle by Main Street; and each side has its unique handful of interesting, artsy or tasty experiences.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The East Exchange is home to live theatre, the museum and the symphony, while the West Exchange is home to art galleries, shopping and movies you can’t see anywhere else in the city. Both have cozy cafes promising your favourite latte, and moody bars serving creative and delicious cocktails. This is just a small taste of what the Exchange has to offer. To get you started, I’ve put together my own list of great things to see and do on both sides of the Exchange.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;East Exchange Highlights&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Royal Manitoba Theatre Centre&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
174 Market Avenue
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;royalmtc.ca&#x2F;home.aspx&quot;&gt;royalmtc.ca&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_534&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;800&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BpXpUM7n88L&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-534 size-full&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;11&#x2F;Sense-and-Sensibility-by-mtcwinnipeg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sense and Sensibility, Royal Manitoba Theatre Centre, Winnipeg, Manitoba, Winnipeg Downtown, Show, Entertainment&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Sense and Sensibility ? by @leifnorman[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the red neon light installation (it’s a Winnipeg landmark!) guide you to the Royal Manitoba Theatre Centre (Royal MTC). The Royal MTC was Canada’s first English Language regional theatre. It was created in 1958 by (then) Artistic Director &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.canadiantheatre.com&#x2F;dict.pl?term=Hirsch%2C%20John%20Stephen&quot;&gt;John Hirsch&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and General Manager &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mhs.mb.ca&#x2F;docs&#x2F;people&#x2F;hendry_tb.shtml&quot;&gt;Tom Hendry&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;—the two guys immortalized in the statue out front.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every season there are ten plays offered at either the Tom Hendry mainstage or the John Hirsch Warehouse.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Centennial Concert Hall&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
555 Main Street
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.winnipegarchitecture.ca&#x2F;centennial-concert-hall&#x2F;&quot;&gt;winnipegarchitecture.ca&#x2F;centennial-concert-hall&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Centennial Concert Hall&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.flickr.com&#x2F;photos&#x2F;loriwhelan&#x2F;18158613780&#x2F;in&#x2F;photolist-tEBDeW-99y29b-99uRRp-99uSUx-99uRuM-99xZwY-99uU1V-99y1KS-99y2hs-99y2P5-99xZ9m&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;farm1.staticflickr.com&#x2F;491&#x2F;18158613780_147200b81f_c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Centennial Concert Hall&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;534&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;&#x2F;&#x2F;embedr.flickr.com&#x2F;assets&#x2F;client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
While it’s true the Brutalist architectural style makes the Centennial Concert Hall a divisive landmark, there’s no denying the importance of this building. The decadent interior hosts not only the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wso.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Winnipeg Symphony Orchestra&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wnmf.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;New Music Festival&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, concerts, and a variety of speakers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Manitoba Museum&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
90 Rupert Avenue
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;manitobamuseum.ca&#x2F;main&#x2F;&quot;&gt;manitobamuseum.ca&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;center&gt;[video width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;428&quot; mp4=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;11&#x2F;by-Manitoba-Museum.mp4&quot;][&#x2F;video]&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;Have you been to the museum lately? It’s changed since your elementary school field trip (though the bison diorama is still there to greet you). The Manitoba Museum offers a variety of exhibits and displays that appeal to kids and adults alike. The Science Gallery on the lower level invites hands-on experiments and race-car construction for kids. Take in a show at the Planetarium while you’re there. Even better, the museum now hosts after-hours events for adults. (Think tours with cocktails!)
&lt;h3&gt;The Mitchell Block&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
173 McDermot Avenue
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.themitchellblock.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;themitchellblock.ca&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start off your night on a tasty note with dinner at the Mitchell Block. The menu changes frequently, but one thing you can count on is delicious homemade pastas and a warm ambience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re wanting something lighter and more casual, the sister restaurant upstairs (&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wetanddrydept.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Wet &amp;amp; Dry Dept.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) offers cocktails and appetizers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Forth&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
171 McDermot Avenue
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.forth.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;www.forth.ca&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right next door from The Mitchell Block is Forth. This historic building was carefully renovated and has become one of the nicest spots in Winnipeg since it opened.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main floor has a café offering a well-curated menu of small bites to complement the coffee and drink menu. The basement has one of the coziest&#x2F;moodiest bars in the city and there’s even a rooftop bar open in the evenings (weather permitting). You’ll find a cocktail list that’s more creative than what you might be used to.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Waterfront Drive and Stephen Juba Park&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Sometimes going for a walk is the best way to fall in love with an area. Waterfront Drive and Stephen Juba Park bookend the East Exchange and offer lush greenspace and a way to “get away” without really going anywhere.
&lt;h2&gt;West Exchange Highlights&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Artspace Building&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
100 Arthur Street
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;art-space.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;art-space.ca&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like an apartment building with a bunch of cool tenants, this building is home to a diverse group of arts and culture organizations that make Winnipeg a better place.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;platformgallery.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;PLATFORM: Centre for Photographic + Digital Arts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.videopool.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Video Pool&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, you could spend a lot of time wandering Artspace’s halls.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to check out what &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.winnipegfilmgroup.com&#x2F;cinematheque&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Cinematheque&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is showing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Old Market Square&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;tribe-street-address&quot;&gt;133 Albert Street&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.exchangedistrict.org&#x2F;the-cube-stage-and-old-market-square&#x2F;&quot;&gt;exchangedistrict.org&#x2F;the-cube-stage-and-old-market-square&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_556&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignright&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;500&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;BoXeHtRHBDs&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-556&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;11&#x2F;Nuit-Blanche-Old-Market-Square-by-Liz-Tran-820x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nuit Blanche, Old Market Square, The Cube, Exchange District, Downtown&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;625&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Nuit Blanche at the Cube, Old Market Square by Liz Tran[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem like this patch of greenspace in the middle of the Exchange is too small to be a destination, but during the summer it&#x27;s a hub for music, drama and the arts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June, the TD Winnipeg International &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.jazzwinnipeg.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Jazz Festival&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; hosts free outdoor stage concerts. In July, the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.winnipegfringe.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Winnipeg Fringe Festival&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;srfwpg.blogspot.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Soca Reggae Festival&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; take the stage. In August you can enjoy the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.memefest.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Manitoba Electronic Music Festival&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Between these events you’ll see plenty of people making use of the space and making Old Market Square a central location for hanging out downtown.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Boutique Anya&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
88 Albert Street
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.boutiqueanya.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;boutiqueanya.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop by this stylish and minimalist boutique to pick up something to wear for your night out. Anya has pieces you won’t find anywhere else in Winnipeg.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tiny Feast&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
217 McDermot Avenue
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.tinyfeast.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;tinyfeast.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This store has the notebook you didn’t know you needed. “Tiny Feast” is a phrase the owners coined; a metaphor that’s used to “describe a variety of things that feel celebratory, lavish, almost extravagant—yet are intrinsically simple and useful, and therefore justifiably attainable on a personal, everyday level.” Stationery, gifts and other interesting items, shopping here is a feast in which you should indulge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cordova Tapas and Wine&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
93 Albert Street
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cordovatapas.bar&#x2F;&quot;&gt;cordovatapas.bar&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This intimate space has an extensive (and delicious) wine and tapas menu. What could be better than enjoying a glass of wine and a few one-bite dishes with friends?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Natural Cycleworks&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
91 Albert Street
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;naturalcycle.ca&#x2F;cycleworks&#x2F;&quot;&gt;naturalcycle.ca&#x2F;cycleworks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Down the flight of stairs at 91 Albert Street you’ll find one of the best bike shops in the city. This worker co-op (the people who work there also own it) has been around for a long time—and they know bikes. Natural Cycleworks offers full bike service year-round, custom built bikes, and is committed to recycling and resource conservation. With all those fancy new bike lanes in our downtown, this is your place to get geared up for a ride.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living downtown provides you quick access to Winnipeg’s vibrant arts and culture scene. The Exchange District, whether East or West, is brimming with new and fantastic things to taste, see and experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my list—what’s yours? Share your comments on your favourite spots in the Exchange.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
