<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Home - Living at 300Main Downtown Winnipeg - clutter</title>
	<subtitle>We all love 300Main</subtitle>
	<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/clutter/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2019-03-20T20:13:11+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/clutter/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>New Season, New Apartment: Decluttering your Space for Spring</title>
		<published>2019-03-20T20:13:11+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-03-20T20:13:11+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/new-season-new-apartment-decluttering-your-space-for-spring/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/new-season-new-apartment-decluttering-your-space-for-spring/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whether you just finished binging Marie Kondo’s Netflix series or are just looking for a neater home, decluttering is a key part of spring cleaning.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve all been there: Despite your best intentions, what was once a spotless and organized space has now drawn piles of clutter like moths to the flame. Don’t waste time feeling embarrassed; we’ve all been there! Follow these quick tips and you’ll feel like you have a new apartment by spring.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Create a Schedule and Set Aside the Time&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Start off by making a list of all the rooms in your apartment, and don’t forget coat closets or cleaning supplies closets! No two rooms will need the same amount of time; your bathroom might take 30 minutes whereas your bedroom could take half a day.
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve identified the rooms you need to tackle, create a schedule and be specific about what you hope to accomplish in each room. For example, your goal for your kitchen might be to create more countertop room, or you might want to clear more wardrobe space in your bedroom.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Out with the Old&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Winter clothing can truly take a beating in these harsh chilly months. Set aside a couple of hours and inspect your wardrobe. Recycle any hole-infested sweaters and worn-down thermal socks.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_3617&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignnone&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;1024&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-3617&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;03&#x2F;dan-gold-544435-unsplash-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;De-cluttering, Spring Cleaning, 300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Living, Downtown Winnipeg, Downtown Apartments&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; &#x2F;&gt; by Dan Gold from Unsplash[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clothes are one of the easiest things to collect and hoard within your home. Ask yourself, “Have I worn this in the past 6 months?” If you haven’t (be honest!) and there’s no sentimental value to it (like a wedding dress or your grandmother’s hand-knit sweater,) donate it. You’ll thank yourself later when looking for your favourite shirt doesn’t count as an arm workout.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are anything like me, you fear getting rid of stuff because you can’t help but think, “&lt;em&gt;But what if I need this later?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;” Trust me on this: You’re never going to need those hotel toiletries you snagged on your past six vacations, or that one phone charger that works when you place it just right—it’s time to toss ‘em!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Become Friends with your Countertops and Tables Again&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Flat surfaces in your apartment accumulate the most clutter because it’s just so easy to let things pile up. Remove every item from the surface, including decorations, appliances and all the haphazard junk. Lay everything out on a flat surface like another table (or even the floor), so you have a clear view of each item.
&lt;p&gt;An easy place to start is by throwing away all the random flyers, coupons and other non-important loose papers that tend to accumulate. Next, tackle things that spark more annoyance than joy, such as decorations you don’t remember buying.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve picked the items worthy of being on your counter or table, find a permanent home for them in a convenient and logical spot. Be selective of what you keep on your counters; you don’t need to have every single appliance on the counter! If you don’t use it every day, store it in a cabinet or on top of the fridge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Don’t Forget to Tackle the Junk Drawer&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Drawers are the first place you throw miscellaneous stuff into, especially when you’re quickly tidying up. I get it; out of sight, out of mind. But this spring, we’re reversing that mindset! The purpose of a junk drawer is to provide a place to store all the little odds and ends that don&#x27;t quite fit in anywhere else. This is still possible, but it can be done in a more intentional way.
&lt;p&gt;Toss anything that is expired, unnecessary or is just plain garbage. Keep extra batteries, packs of pens and chip clips, but get rid of extra chopsticks, expired coupons, and that stack of random business cards.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ready, Shreddy, Go!&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Paper junk can collect quickly, like old receipts, bank invoices or even more of those random business cards. Shredding these will clear up your office space.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_3623&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignright&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;576&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-3623&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;03&#x2F;felipe-bustillo-1176758-unsplash2-576x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;De-cluttering, Spring Cleaning, 300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Living, Downtown Winnipeg, Downtown Apartments&quot; width=&quot;576&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt; by Felipe Bustillo from Unsplash[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Collections of any Kinds Have to Go&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Items like books, CD’s or DVD’s can really pile up over the years. Ask yourself if these mementos are necessary, or just part of your past that you’re holding onto. It’s a brave, new virtual world, and most of us don’t even have CD&#x2F;DVD players any more thanks to Netflix. So why are you wasting space for stacks of CDs from the early 2000s?
&lt;p&gt;The same thing goes for books. It might be nice to look like a bookworm when your friends pop by, but you know they’re mostly just taking up space. This doesn’t mean you have to give up every book but ask yourself if you’ll really ever read it again. If you won’t, donate it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick Tip: Donate your books to newcomer organizations (such as N.E.E.D.S) or a senior living facility!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Be Ruthless&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Getting rid of stuff in your home is difficult at first because we create connections with items. But, once you get the hang of it, you’ll wonder why you didn’t tackle it sooner!
&lt;h3&gt;Organize the Rest&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Decluttering isn’t just about getting rid of stuff; it’s also about knowing how to manage what you have. From racks, baskets, or under-bed storage, there’s an assortment of storage products for every need on the market.
&lt;h3&gt;Out of Sight, Out of Mind&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
A forgotten place that is one of the most convenient storage spaces is hiding out under your bed. Grab a few thin, narrow bins and you have the perfect place to store out of season clothes, booksyou want to keep but don’t need on your shelf, or any mish-mashed items that don’t seem to have a place but that you know you need.
&lt;p&gt;Shelving units are also a great way to kill two birds with one stone: Grab a few baskets and tuck away all those miscellaneous items such as cords or craft supplies. Your shelves will look neat and aesthetically pleasing, and what they hold is your little secret.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Celebrate!&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Now that your hard work is over, sit back and celebrate Apartment 2.0! Now your mission is to keep your home decluttered. Remember to follow the golden rule: Only bring things into your home that you actually need and will use. Once your apartment is decluttered, it’s easy to follow into old habits and end up buying more stuff you don’t need.
&lt;p&gt;Before bringing something new into your home, ask yourself, “Do I need this? How will this benefit my home?” If you can’t answer both questions, don’t buy it. Another great trick is the one in, one out rule. For every item that comes into your apartment, try to get rid of one item so you don’t end up with a cluttered apartment once again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tips might seem ambitious, but you can do it! And once you see how freeing it can feel to have less &lt;em&gt;stuff&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; around you, you’ll be kicking yourself for not starting sooner. What’s your personal decluttering challenge?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Small Space Design Ideas</title>
		<published>2019-03-05T11:00:22+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-03-05T11:00:22+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/small-space-design-ideas/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/small-space-design-ideas/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After spending two years studying, working, and falling in love in Scotland, in October I moved into a one-bedroom suite in the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theboyceloftsonross.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Boyce Lofts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;exchangedistrict.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Exchange District&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It was the first time I didn’t have to live with roommates, and the first time I didn’t have to move into a furnished apartment. The Boyce Lofts were brand new and no one had lived in the space before me. It was a blank canvas (and not just because of the white walls and white cabinetry), and I was so excited to decorate and furnish it just the way I wanted.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But while my apartment has high ceilings and an open concept, it’s pretty small—at around 500 square feet—and narrow enough that I can’t fit furniture on both sides of the living&#x2F;dining room. So not only did I have to plan out the use of space, but I had to make sure I wasn’t filling the space with too much. I knew my already-small space would feel even smaller with clutter and large furniture. I had to be smart about decorating.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m no design expert, but I like to think I have good taste, and I strongly believe that minimalism is the way forward. Not only does minimalism help reduce consumerism, but it helps you &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.psychologytoday.com&#x2F;ca&#x2F;blog&#x2F;anxiety-zen&#x2F;201612&#x2F;minimalism-when-living-less-means-more-mental-health&quot;&gt;feel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; unburdened in the place that should matter most—home. So here are some tips on designing your small space.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Storage&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
When you have less space to leave things lying around, you can’t afford to have much clutter! Even if you’re not a messy person, it’s hard to keep things clean and tidy if you simply have too much stuff. It’s easy to accumulate Christmas and birthday gifts you didn’t really want, impulse buys you could’ve done without, and clothing and shoes.
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, I understand that sometimes you just don’t want to be looking at your things, especially if it’s miscellaneous stuff you’re unsure where to store. Small-space living is your chance to get creative!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you move into your small space, purge your belongings. Donate or sell them things you don’t want or need (&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.siloam.ca&#x2F;donate&#x2F;donate&#x2F;?utm_source=google&amp;amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;amp;utm_term=siloam%20mission&amp;amp;utm_campaign=paid&amp;amp;gclid=CjwKCAiAqt7jBRAcEiwAof2uK9QVeCxi4pU-My2leJVWHSvKIY9wy_26stHto4zZ_d46JGC9wNY6qBoCMXwQAvD_BwE&quot;&gt;Siloam Mission&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; gratefully accepts new and gently used clothing!). Not only will you feel unburdened from all these nonessential objects, but your small space will feel bigger and you’ll have more room to work with.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For storing your belongings, opt for open shelving. Closed shelving gives the illusion that your walls are closing in and that the room is even smaller. I have an abundance of kitchen cabinet space, so I use it to store some non-kitchen related items as well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the bed is a great place to store items you don’t use very often. You can buy long, slim boxes exactly for this purpose, or you can even get a storage bed that has built-in storage under the mattress.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your building has storage lockers, use yours! They’re handy for storing larger items like suitcases, bicycles, and seasonal clothing. Items that are essential, but seasonal, and too clunky to be keeping in your apartment year-long.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Furniture&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
When &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;hutk.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;choosing furniture&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for your small space, look for pieces that are light and don’t take up a lot of space, or that give the illusion that they don’t. Avoid big, clunky, overstuffed furniture, and choose pieces that are low to the ground and have exposed legs.
&lt;p&gt;Go for &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.interiorillusions.ca&#x2F;product-category&#x2F;furniture&#x2F;living-room&#x2F;accent-chairs&#x2F;&quot;&gt;sleek armless chairs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and try transparent coffee tables, which won’t look like they’re taking any room at all. Think about using two small coffee tables instead of one big one that takes up a lot of space.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_3430&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;940&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-3430&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;03&#x2F;by-interior_illusions-1024x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Interior Illusions, Interior Design, Small Space, Downtown Apartments, 300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments&quot; width=&quot;940&quot; height=&quot;940&quot; &#x2F;&gt; by @interior_illusions on Instagram[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dual or multipurpose pieces are key in a small space. Consider getting an ottoman instead of a coffee table so it can do double duty as extra seating. (Bonus points if it has built-in storage!) Floor cushions also make great emergency seating for when you have guests over, and you can stack them up when you’re not using them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look into getting an expandable or folding dining table. Keep it small when you’re alone and open it up to fit all your friends around the table the next time you’re hosting brunch.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For storing things like books and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;intothemusic.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;records&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, opt for a shelving unit that is vertical, not horizontal. You’ll be able to store more items while taking up less floor space. If you can, install floating shelves to avoid using up precious square footage. They’re sleek, easy to set up, and you can arrange them however you like.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A TV media console can take up a lot of space, so mount your television on the wall to minimize the use of floor space. I took it a step further and got a projector—they’re cheaper, much smaller, easily transportable, and a great alternative to a clunky television if you have white walls.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Decoration&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Plants are the easiest way to decorate and brighten up your space. If you have a history of being bad at keeping plants alive (guilty as charged!), try a cactus or a bonsai; they’re small, cute, and can withstand being over or under watered. Stop by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;verdeplantdesign.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Verde Plant Design&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for a great selection!
&lt;p&gt;Don’t be afraid to decorate your walls with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wag.ca&#x2F;visit&#x2F;shop&quot;&gt;art&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that you love. Mirrors make a space look larger, so go on the hunt for a mirror with a stylish frame. A stylish mirror can function as part of your decor, not just something you check to make sure you look good before heading out the door.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hang your curtains from the ceiling, not at the top of the window frame—it’ll create the illusion of higher ceilings and a larger space.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to creating a colour palette for a small space, use colour sparingly. Use light colours for your walls and furniture, and dark or bold colours as accents only, such as throw pillows, vases, or lamps. Try to create a colour palette that uses only two to three colours.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Getting Started&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Where do you spend the most time? Focus your spending on that area to get the most out of your budget. If you like sleeping, invest in a bed you can’t wait to crawl into; if you like watching TV, invest in a cozy sofa; if you work from home, invest in a good working space, with a comfy chair and a nice desk. Make a plan, and don’t buy everything at once. Get the important things like your bed and your sofa first, live with it for a bit, and feel out what you need to get next; you might surprise yourself!
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Any tips for decorating a small space? Share them below!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Creative Ways to Control Kitchen Clutter</title>
		<published>2018-12-06T11:00:49+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-12-06T11:00:49+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/creative-ways-to-control-kitchen-clutter/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/creative-ways-to-control-kitchen-clutter/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Is your kitchen bursting at the seams? Don’t hide from your culinary creativity because of a mess! Here are five ways to keep your kitchen from looking like a hurricane made landfall in your cupboards.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Learn to love your Tupperware&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
The dreaded Tupperware cupboard: we all have one. Despite the mysterious lids and tumbling bottoms, tackling this beast doesn’t need to be intimidating. For a smooth post-dinner clean-up, invest in a simple file organizer. Yes—the file organizer on your desk can be put to work in your kitchen, too. Slide lids in one organizer and containers in another to make packing up leftovers a cinch.
&lt;h3&gt;2. High rise&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Don’t compromise your charming mug collection just because you’re short on storage. Get the most out of the space you have by thinking vertical! Adding a shelf riser is a quick fix that lets you store more by instantly turning one shelf into two. With all that extra space, why not see what &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.tinyfeast.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Tiny Feast&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has in stock to add to your collection?
&lt;h3&gt;3. Stash away your sprays&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
The cupboard under the sink—also known as the “I’ll just throw it under there” shelf—is an organizing challenge. Finding that one particular kitchen cleaner can be easy with a little creativity: buy a tension rod (the kind you use to hang a shower curtain) and install it under the cupboard. Hook sprays on the rod to create more room on the bottom shelf for “unhangables,” such as garbage bags. For bonus points, pare your collection down to one or two earth-friendly alternatives from &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;generationgreenwpg.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Generation Green&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;h3&gt;4. Double-duty backsplash&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
When it comes to organizing your kitchen, don’t let space goes to waste. Lean a square of pegboard against the back wall of your kitchen counter. Simply insert hooks into the board and hang the tools you use most often to keep them handy. This customizable option can be used for measuring cups, spatulas, and even whisks.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_573&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;682&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-573 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;11&#x2F;calum-lewis-387582-unsplash-682x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hanging Cups, Organizing Kitchen, 300 Main Apartments&quot; width=&quot;682&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt; Photo by Calum Lewis from Unsplash[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5. Stickin’ your spices&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Cooking a meal can feel intimidating when you’re fumbling through your cabinet of toppling jars, bags, and containers of spices. Head to the nearby dollar store to purchase small glass jars and magnets. With a little bit of hot glue, your made-for-the-counter jars can become fridge magnets. Fill them up with your favourite spices for an easy way to grab cinnamon or oregano while minimizing cabinet clutter.
&lt;p&gt;Storage spaces and gadgets don’t need to be used the way they were intended to be; with a bit of imagination, you can make your kitchen a welcoming place to whip up your favourite meals! Feeling inspired to get the rest of your home in shipshape? Gather ideas by browsing &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;hutk.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;HutK&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;’s collection of beautiful furniture that doubles as clever storage.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your favourite ways to make your kitchen an inviting place to cook?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
