<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Home - Living at 300Main Downtown Winnipeg - neighbourhood</title>
	<subtitle>We all love 300Main</subtitle>
	<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/neighbourhood/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2019-11-21T21:41:11+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/post-tag/neighbourhood/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Bigger is Greener: The Environmental Benefits of High-Density Housing</title>
		<published>2019-11-21T21:41:11+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-11-21T21:41:11+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/bigger-is-greener-the-environmental-benefits-of-high-density-housing/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/bigger-is-greener-the-environmental-benefits-of-high-density-housing/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Canadians are increasingly &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.macleans.ca&#x2F;news&#x2F;canada&#x2F;census-2016-a-picture-of-a-bigger-more-urban-canada&#x2F;&quot;&gt;living in cities&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;canadapopulation.org&#x2F;winnipeg-population&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Winnipeg is no exception&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It can sometimes be hard for communities with fast-growing populations to keep up with the infrastructure needs for new residents. That’s why many cities are gravitating towards more high-density housing as part of their “&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.smartcitiesdive.com&#x2F;ex&#x2F;sustainablecitiescollective&#x2F;urban-density-and-sustainability&#x2F;241696&#x2F;&quot;&gt;smart growth&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;” strategies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is High-Density Housing?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
High-density housing simply is housing that packs more people per geographic unit. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;300 Main&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a 40-storey apartment building that will be home to several hundred city dwellers. Communities that are urbanizing sometimes encourage developers to add higher-density complexes to their downtown areas. There are many advantages to these tall multiplexes.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_6065&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;1024&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;300main.ca&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-6065&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;Final_C2-1024x775.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Apartment Buildings, Apartments in Winnipeg&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;775&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; 3D Rendering of 300 Main[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Higher-density neighbourhoods have a strong sense of community and connectedness because people are just in closer contact with each other. High-density housing usually entails high-rise buildings such as 300 Main. Higher population density is essential for &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.huffingtonpost.ca&#x2F;ypnexthome&#x2F;high-density-housing-gta_b_17208346.html&quot;&gt;developing busy, vivacious neighbourhoods&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with lots of features. It allows for beautiful public spaces like downtown Winnipeg to make life convenient, enjoyable and, most importantly, green!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sustainable Design&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
As cities &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;canada.constructconnect.com&#x2F;dcn&#x2F;news&#x2F;economic&#x2F;2019&#x2F;04&#x2F;canadas-major-cities-ride-slipstream-surging-population-growth&quot;&gt;boom in population&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and invest to meet the needs of their new citizens, sustainability has also become a major focus. High-rise apartments are one of the easiest ways to make a community more sustainable. They have a smaller footprint than that of many smaller buildings.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_6069&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;680&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-6069&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;apartment-architectural-design-architecture-bridge-1152849-3-680x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Apartment Buildings, Apartments in Winnipeg, Chicago, High Rise Buildings in Chicago, High Rise Apartments in Chicago&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt; Chicago, United States by Cameron Casey from Pexels[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If neighbourhoods want to continue to grow, all they need to do is look up! Building up, or even on top of, is &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.citylab.com&#x2F;equity&#x2F;2012&#x2F;01&#x2F;why-most-environmental-building-building-weve-already-built&#x2F;1016&#x2F;&quot;&gt;more environmentally-friendly&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; than conventional demolished-site redevelopment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Size Matters (For Energy)&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Denser neighbourhoods that include apartment blocks or condos also use less energy. Residences that are stacked or bunched should &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ottawacitizen.com&#x2F;life&#x2F;homes&#x2F;modern-housing-why-highrises-are-good-for-the-environment&quot;&gt;use less energy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. For example, an apartment suite in 300 Main is more efficient to heat and cool than a detached suburban house. So even on cold winter nights (which us Winnipeggers know sometimes start in October), if every apartment suite were to turn their heat up, they’d be using less energy than the equivalent number of houses. Higher-density neighbourhoods also &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cbsnews.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;trying-to-reduce-your-carbon-footprint-dont-fall-for-these-myths&#x2F;&quot;&gt;create fewer harmful emissions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. As &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.citylab.com&#x2F;life&#x2F;2012&#x2F;04&#x2F;why-bigger-cities-are-greener&#x2F;863&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Richard Florida at CityLab&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; says, “When it comes to greenness, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;martinprosperity.org&#x2F;insights&#x2F;insight&#x2F;cities-and-co2-bigger-is-better&quot;&gt;size matters&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.”
&lt;h3&gt;Encourages more Walking, Cycling and Use of Public Transportation&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Though downtown areas can seem busy, there are major benefits to living and working downtown. Dense downtown neighbourhoods help residents drive less and walk more, without giving up their lifestyles. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.fastcompany.com&#x2F;40492045&#x2F;living-in-a-dense-city-makes-citizens-healthier&quot;&gt;Research&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has shown that lower density promotes sedentary behavior. If your home is far away from the grocery store and your office, you’re going to spend more time in a car and less time being active.
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;getting-around-winnipeg-without-a-car-yes-its-possible&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High-density housing encourages walking and cycling &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cbsnews.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;trying-to-reduce-your-carbon-footprint-dont-fall-for-these-myths&#x2F;&quot;&gt;because everything is closer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; together! Transit is also promoted by high-density housing, as transit connections become more common when neighborhood density increases. Many city dwellers find it more convenient to jump on a transit bus and be at work in a stress-free jiffy, rather than drive to work, deal with traffic, and find parking. Talk about a headache!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individuals who live in suburban areas can also benefit from people taking transit to work. Fewer cars on the road equal fewer harmful emissions, like carbon dioxide.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What’s Big, Green, and Sustainable?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
High-density housing is a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theguardian.com&#x2F;environment&#x2F;georgemonbiot&#x2F;2011&#x2F;jun&#x2F;30&#x2F;sustainable-cities-urban-planning&quot;&gt;sustainable choice&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for growing cities. Tall buildings are more than just towers of concrete and steel; they’re a fundamental part of successful urbanization. They offer a greener, less wasteful, and more energy-efficient way of life.
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_6072&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;954&amp;quot;]&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-6072&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;11&#x2F;vehicles-on-road-between-high-rise-buildings-1525612-954x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;300 Main Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Winnipeg Apartments, Downtown Winnipeg Apartments, Apartment Buildings, Apartments in Winnipeg, New York, New York Apartment Buildings&quot; width=&quot;954&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; &#x2F;&gt; New York, United States by Craig Adderley from Pexels[&#x2F;caption]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Won&#x27;t You Be My Neighbour?</title>
		<published>2018-10-29T20:35:02+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-10-29T20:35:02+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/wont-you-be-my-neighbour/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/wont-you-be-my-neighbour/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Downtown living can be exciting. You’re in the heart of the city with oodles of entertainment choices right outside your door. In your new digs at 300 Main, you will also have new neighbours, maybe more than you’ve ever had before. &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As adults, we sometimes have trouble making new friends and even introducing ourselves to others. Do you want your neighbours to be more than just nameless faces but don’t know where to start? If so, here are five ideas that just may get you started in meeting those sharing your new living environment. &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;Join the Gym&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
At 300 Main, you’ve got some swanky new amenities, including a gym. There are many good reasons to use these facilities, the most obvious of which are exercise and healthy living. Yes, you could work out in your apartment, but you won’t meet anyone new there. The gym will give you an opportunity to politely check out and maybe meet some of your neighbours. &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;plugins&#x2F;post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2F300MainWinnipeg%2Fposts%2F1438523886290140&amp;width=500&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;513&quot; style=&quot;border:none;overflow:hidden&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowTransparency=&quot;true&quot; allow=&quot;encrypted-media&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be easier to introduce yourself to someone in the gym, because you already have something in common: a desire to exercise. This gives you a ready-made topic to discuss. Does your possible new bestie have a favourite piece of equipment or a good workout tip? Starting with this type of safe topic gives you a chance to chat and discover if you might have more in common. If they don’t seem like buddy material, stick to your short exercise chat, then go back to working out. Having exercise to do gives you an easy excuse to extract yourself from a conversation that isn’t going well. (The introverted among us always like having an escape plan from awkward conversation.) Remember, less is more. You don’t want to be the pushy type, so don’t monopolize anyone for too long.&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your first conversation goes well, you can try to catch this person on the regular at the gym for a while. If you both seem receptive to talking outside of the gym, suggest going for drinks or coffee, something comfortable and short.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-184 size-large&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;10&#x2F;Friends-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;940&quot; height=&quot;627&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;Join a Social Event or Start a Social Committee&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;alignright wp-image-225&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;10&#x2F;blue-charity-cheerful-1208694-1024x766.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;374&quot; &#x2F;&gt;Does your building hold any social events onsite or organize any group outings? If yes, consider joining one that interests you. If you don’t see any options for social gatherings, consider starting a social committee yourself. You will likely need to talk to building management first, but group outings are another great way to meet people in low-stress situations and see if you have something in common.&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also join or start a charitable endeavour in your building. There are many non-profit organizations located downtown, such as&lt;i&gt; Siloam Mission&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;&#x2F;i&gt;or&lt;i&gt; Welcome Place&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;, which have volunteer openings.  Alternatively, you could invite your apartment block or floor to raise money as a community. Organizations like the Christmas Cheer Board are always looking for new donors. Any of these options will create an opportunity for you to meet people and help a worthy cause at the same time. &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;Start a Conversation in Common Areas&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Inevitably, you will see some of your new neighbours in the hall, on the elevator or in the mailroom. One of the easiest ways to meet your neighbours is to pipe up and introduce yourself in these situations. If you’re an extrovert, starting conversations with complete strangers is likely an easy task for you. If you’re an introvert, this will take more effort. &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start with a smile and avoid coming on too strong. Remember, you’ve already got something in common: you live in the same building! Ask what they think of the building, the gym or some other amenity. This should lead to an easy conversation. Chances are good you can converse on this topic for a few minutes, which is all you will have (at most) when you randomly run into people in your building. Remember to give your name and, if you feel comfortable, what floor you live on. You won’t hit it off with every neighbour, so don’t fret if the first few conversations don’t work out. &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;Advanced Technique&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;: Throw a Party!&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
If you’re a sociable sort and like to plan events, consider throwing a party. This might be especially welcome if everyone on the invitee list is new to the building, since most of us like to make friends. &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s best to invite a smallish number of people to a party, maybe everyone on your floor. You can knock on doors, leave messages under doors or invite people you’ve met and with whom you have already exchanged numbers.&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep the event low key and don’t try to make people do party games. Be conscientious and keep the volume down. Not everyone will come and you don’t want to tick off the people who share your building. The party could just be an easy brunch (mimosas!) or after work drinks. You don’t have to plan for a six-hour event. If all goes well, you might make a few friends. At least you will have some friendly new acquaintances you can talk to when moving around your building.&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;Think&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Beyond Your Building&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;TextRun SCXW892797&quot; lang=&quot;EN-CA&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-CA&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;NormalTextRun SCXW892797&quot;&gt;It’s great to know people right in your living space, but you don’t have to limit yourself to one spot. Take advantage of your location to meet other downtown denizens. You can try local coffee shops or nightclubs. If you pick a regular time to visit your favourite coffee haunt, you might spot other regulars&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;TextRun SCXW892797&quot; lang=&quot;EN-CA&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-CA&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;NormalTextRun SCXW892797&quot;&gt; and be spotted by them&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;TextRun SCXW892797&quot; lang=&quot;EN-CA&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-CA&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;NormalTextRun SCXW892797&quot;&gt;. It will be less intimidating to start conversations with people who have seen your face a few times.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.meetup.com&#x2F;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-187 size-medium alignleft&quot; src=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2018&#x2F;10&#x2F;meetup.en_-300x158.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;158&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;You can also look for local organizations to join. There are multiple Toastmasters clubs that meet downtown. You can also check out &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.meetup.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;www.meetup.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to find information about groups or events downtown that might interest you. You can visit the Millennium Library or sign up for some volunteer work in your neighbourhood. There are so many options for meeting people downtown. Pick one and take the plunge!&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;Starting Is Often the Hardest Part&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
Meeting people and making new friends can take some work and some intentionality. Choose not to keep your head down over your phone when you’re in your building.  Show your neighbours you are open to connecting by smiling, making eye contact, and saying “hi” when you can. The truth is, many people are shy and just need an invitation to strike up a conversation.  Before long, you’ll discover that “renters” have become “neighbours”, and “neighbours” have become friends. &lt;span data-ccp-props=&quot;{}&quot;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
