<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Home - Living at 300Main Downtown Winnipeg - pets</title>
	<subtitle>We all love 300Main</subtitle>
	<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/category/pets/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-06-06T14:49:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/category/pets/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>To Bark or not To Bark - 5 Basic Steps to Successful Training your Dog</title>
		<published>2022-06-06T14:49:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-06-06T14:49:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/to-bark-or-not-to-bark-5-basic-steps-to-successful-training-your-dog/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/to-bark-or-not-to-bark-5-basic-steps-to-successful-training-your-dog/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems like our dogs will bark for just about anything and everything so the article To Bark or not To Bark - 5 Basic Steps to Successful Training your Dog can help you. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training your dog to stop barking may seem daunting but with a little bit of work from you, anything is possible! In this article, we guide you about training your dog so you have the tools you need to teach your dog when and when not to bark.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:9939,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;bark6-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9939&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until you train your dog otherwise, they basically think they must report everything pretty much they hear, as they hear it. To your dog, anything can be a potential threat, and barking is their only alarm. Especially when you are living in an apartment, one of the main reasons your dog barks is random noises.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To dogs who are sensitive to noise and vibrations, loud neighbors, other animals, kids, and random noises that come with the everyday life of apartment living probably sound a little bit like a purge until you see what is really going on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The 5 Basic Steps to Successful Training&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important not to discipline your dog every time they bark, but teach them when and how to instead. You can use these steps to train your dog for almost anything. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:9940,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;bark3-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9940&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways to have your dog bark trained is by teaching them how to bark properly. Once your dog realizes there is a time and a place for barking, they will start to bark less at seemingly everything. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The 5 Steps to Training Your Dog are:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:list --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Observe (The Reaction)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Introduce (The Sound)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Replace (Reaction with Command)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Reward &amp;amp; Repeat&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:list --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:4} --&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Observe&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start by observing what triggers your dog barking so you can plan what you need to work on. It&#x27;s likely your dog is triggered by the same noises every time so take note of what you need to train your dog on and work on those areas specifically.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:4} --&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Introduce&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next is to introduce your dog to the sound so they can understand where it is coming from. Much of the time, dogs are barking out of curiosity, and you can help them stop barking at the same things in the future by teaching them what the sounds are. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:9941,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;bark1-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9941&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if your dog is triggered by noise in the hall, let your dog watch what is making the noise. If your dog barks at people in the hallway, it is helpful to try and let your dog meet as many of your neighbors as possible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likely your pet barks at your next-door neighbors the most since they&#x27;re the closest, and your dog can&#x27;t always tell if it&#x27;s their door or yours. So, if your neighbor and your dog are both friendly, try a meet and greet as they&#x27;re coming and going so your dog gets familiar with them and stops barking at them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Training Exercise&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that your dog is familiar with the white noise and people of your building, start training them on the sound of your next-door neighbors if that&#x27;s a problem area for your dog.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have your neighbor leave and come back and work on how your dog reacts. When your dog starts to react to the noise of your neighbor, start by getting your dog to sit and work up to add in your own &#x27;no barking command&#x27;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:9942,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;pexels-leah-kelley-776373-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9942&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your dog hears them and starts to react, get them to sit and stay. Open your door, so your dog can associate the sound with the person. Now that your dog knows that the sound of the keys in the lock next door is just your friendly neighbor who isn&#x27;t a threat, they will start barking less.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repeat the exercise; this time, don&#x27;t open the door right away. Ask your dog to sit and use your no-barking command to get the dog to sit and try to be quiet before opening the door. Your dog probably knows who is on the other side of the door if you do this a few times in a row, so it is important to do this outside of your training exercise as well. As your dog starts to change his reactions, keep refreshing the training and rewarding their efforts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Barking at Your Door&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next situation you want to train your dog in is when there is a knock on your door. Since your dog thinks he is doing his job by reporting every noise to you, it is important to teach him which noises to look out for and how to react to them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:9946,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;bark7-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9946&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have observed how they are reacting and you have decided how you want them trained, it&#x27;s time to work on replacing their barking with that reaction instead. Training is most effective if you can dedicate time out each day for your dog where you are going to work on the specific things, rather than just trying to correct the behavior as it pops up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing you want to do is get their attention by having them sit. Once they&#x27;re sitting, work on getting them to stop barking using your designated command. Reward them for sitting and for any efforts made to stop barking at your word.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have them trained to stop barking on command try to repeat the situation a&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.petsmart.ca&#x2F;dog&#x2F;treats&#x2F;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;nd reward them for stopping a few times in a row&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Try to avoid calling your dog badly, focus on rewarding for changed behavior instead. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:9948,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;bark5-1-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9948&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In time, your dog will learn to ignore the noises entirely. Once your dog is more used to everything and you start training, you can begin to train them on how they are barking at your company and at you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Knock Training&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing you want to train them on is knocks on the door. A big reason why dogs bark is they think you or someone else is at the door. So, you want to teach them how to tell the differences and how you want them to act. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way of doing this is with knock training for when the company is at the door and for when you are coming home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When It&#x27;s Company&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a friend stand on the other side of the closed door with you and your dog inside. Have them knock on the door, and you train your dog on how you want them to react to someone knocking on the door. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, you want to start with training them to sit and get them to stop barking using their newly taught word.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:9947,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;bark8-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9947&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:list --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Observe&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:list --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get your friend to knock, and you observe your dog&#x27;s reaction, try to resist intervening or saying a command, and wait out until they are done, if possible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:list --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Introduce&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:list --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduce your dog to what is making the sound. Show your dog that it is actually someone at your door that they are responding to. Don&#x27;t open the door but acknowledge that your dog is alerting you about someone. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, you want to get them to sit and if you can, stop barking using your word before you open the door. If they still are barking, continue training.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:list --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Replace&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:list --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, you want to do is replace the reaction with what you are teaching them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repeat your friend knocking and your dog sitting with rewards a few times in a row. Once they are sitting for you, as a reaction, you can teach them a command to go with it that tells them to stop or not to bark when there is a knock at the door.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:9945,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;bark9-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9945&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have your friend knock again, and when your dog barks, have them sit and tell them the command. Encourage them to stop barking with that command and once your dog stops barking, say the command and praise them, so they associate the word with being quiet and being quiet with praise and reward.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:list --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Repeat &amp;amp; Reward&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:list --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some dogs pick it up right away; others may need a few more training days or weeks. It is important to keep training consistent until your dog does get it before they start to go back to their old behavior. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;7-fun-ways-to-celebrate-halloween-with-your-dog&#x2F;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Dogs respond much better to praise and reward&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Make sure you mix up the rewards for your dog with treats, pets, and getting to play with a toy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When It&#x27;s You&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to training your dog to not bark when you are at the door, you want to do a similar exercise.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Practice walking up, knocking, putting the keys in, whatever makes your dog bark when you come home, and start with teaching them to replace the behavior with sitting and the quiet command.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You want to avoid punishing your dog for barking,&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; especially while you are training them. If your dog feels like you are getting angry at them for barking, this may make your dog&#x27;s barking or other reactions worse and harder to train.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:9944,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;bark2-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9944&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continue to praise them for the following days to a couple of weeks while they are still fresh with it. Remember, when it comes to changing behavior like barking with your dog, consistency, praise, and patience are key.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your dog is only as smart as you make them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training your dog how to react when it is you helps them tell the difference between strangers and you when they are home alone. This will help your dog be more relaxed towards people in the hallway passing by and your neighbors coming and going while you are out as it teaches your dog to recognize when you are home and when it&#x27;s just someone passing by.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to remember that your dog is only as trained as you let them be. Every dog is different. There is no magic number of times or amount of time until your dog is totally trained in this way. Usually, a behavior like barking can take a few weeks. Just remember to be persistent and patient!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Preparing Your Cat To Move Into a New Home</title>
		<published>2022-05-21T19:10:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-21T19:10:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/preparing-your-cat-to-move-into-a-new-home/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://chet-cloud.github.io/zola_livingat300main/preparing-your-cat-to-move-into-a-new-home/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving is an exciting time for many people but preparing your cat to move into a new home can be tricky. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The joys of a new environment, fresh scenery, and best of all, a new beginning in a new place! &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;finding-the-one-choosing-an-apartment-in-winnipeg&#x2F;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Moving may be exciting&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but you can&#x27;t talk about moving without admitting that it can be just as stressful as it is fun.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:9900,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;pexels-helena-lopes-7980485-1-1024x682.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9900&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt; As fun as unpacking, organizing, finding a new home for everything, and getting to use out the old in with the new as an excuse and a fresh start is, getting there isn&#x27;t always such a smooth transition. Moving can be hard on everyone in your household, not just us, but our pets are much more affected by moving than we may be. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Animals do have a harder time with moving than us since they don&#x27;t get the luxury of being able to mentally prepare as we do for something as big as moving to a new home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Think Ahead&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to try and make a move as easy as possible for your feline friend, who can be particularly sensitive when it comes to moving. The best thing you can do is start by thinking ahead. Sometimes we don&#x27;t always get to plan everything, but moving with animals, when possible, the earlier you get yourself and your pets ready, the easier it will be on everyone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to try and keep our pets in mind a couple of weeks before the moving day if that&#x27;s possible in your situation. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:9901,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;full&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;pexels-arina-krasnikova-7725637.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cat inside a box&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9901&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Packing up your house can be hard on your cat, so you want to get them used to the process early. Luckily, this can also be fun for your pet with your help. We all know that as soon as there&#x27;s an empty box, cats will be in it or trying to be. After all, the saying goes, &quot;if I fit, I sit, right&quot;? &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let them have some fun by leaving a couple of empty boxes around where you are packing, so it gets them used to the action and it gives them something to play with. You get bonus points if you want to cut holes in the sides of the boxes to really provide them with something to have fun with.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something that you can do to get your cat ready for moving out is to have a dedicated kitty-corner set up for them a couple of weeks in advance, so they already have a safe space when moving day comes. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:9902,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;pexels-joao-jesus-4198369-2-1024x682.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cat sleeping in a box&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9902&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key thing to remember is that the transition can only go as smoothly as you help make it. With a bit of preparation and thinking ahead, you can help make this transition as smooth as possible for your cat.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Getting The Old Place Ready&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it is possible, it&#x27;s best to have an area or a room set up for your cat that is comfortable and will be packed last. Set this area up with stuff for your cat to help make moving easier on them. This should include their kennel, bed, food, water, litter box, cat furniture, and toys. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gives them a safe and comfortable spot to be away from the stress of moving. You want to set this room up a few weeks in advance and keep it accessible to your cat, so when you must keep them in there on moving day, they will be able to be comfortable and hopefully happy to spend some time in there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:9903,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;pexels-александар-цветановић-1560424-2-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cat sleeping on a cozy bed&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9903&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things to include in the room:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:list --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Toys&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Blankets &amp;amp; Bed&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Kennel&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.petvalu.ca&#x2F;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Food, Water &amp;amp; Treats&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Litter box&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:list --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a cozy cat room isn&#x27;t an option, then you can still prepare by getting the carrier you&#x27;re going to be moving them in, setting up a couple of weeks ahead of time, and giving them a little section of the house with their kennel, toys, food, and litter. This gives your cat a safe spot to go to when things around them are being packed and moved and gets them comfortable with the idea of being in their carrier when it comes time for them to be in it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Getting The New Place Ready&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving out is one thing to consider, but it&#x27;s important to make sure you take just as much care with making your kitty comfortable with the new place as it is moving out of the old one. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:9904,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;pexels-cats-coming-674570-3-1024x617.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cat chilling on a furniture&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9904&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new environment can be a lot for anyone to take in, especially our animals. You want to make sure that they will feel comfortable in their new home. If you can, it&#x27;s best to set up a safe area at the new place, too, and take your cat over there to explore the empty house first. This makes it a little less stressful having to spend some time in there while you do the heavy lifting and unpacking.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would preferably be a room or section of the house or apartment that you can move your cat into with its comfort items and will be set up for its actual use last. Keep your kitty comfy in this area while you set up the house. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Let them Explore&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are ready to let your cat explore their newly set up environment, make sure you hold off on taking apart the moving room and try to keep their safe space available for the first little while until they are more comfortable in the new place.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:9905,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;pexels-tranmautritam-948049-1-1024x682.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cat exploring a new room&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9905&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things to include in the room:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You pretty much want to include whatever you had set up at the old place or to include the same kind of items that you have set up at the old place. You can move the stuff you already have set up if you are moving the cat there for good and just re-set that up in the kitty corner at the new place until you&#x27;re done moving in.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:list --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Food, Treats &amp;amp; Water&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Toys&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Litter Box&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Familiar Toys&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Blankets&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Kennel&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bed&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cat Furniture&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:list --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If new toys and furniture are in your cat&#x27;s future to go along with the new house, it always provides a good distraction to throw some new things in the safe space to let them get used to everything, and it helps keep them excited and distracted, along with some of their old stuff, so they still feel familiar and safe.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pets ID and Registration&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important thing to remember to do before or soon after moving in is to make sure you update your &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.winnipeg.ca&#x2F;cms&#x2F;animal&#x2F;licenses&#x2F;pet_licensing.stm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;pet&#x27;s ID tags and registration&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:9906,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;pexels-breanne-sartori-65006-1-1024x689.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cat looking from a step&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9906&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even indoor cats can get out, and even in an apartment or condo, it&#x27;s essential to have your up-to-date address and phone number on their ID tag on their collar in case they ever do get out and lost, even if it is most likely they just walk down the hall. If they do get out, you&#x27;ll want whoever they might meet to be able to bring them back to the right place.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that moving is a lot on your cat, so don&#x27;t be surprised if your cat is more vocal during the moving process until they are settled in the new place. They also will probably spend a lot of time testing out new hiding spots until they feel at home. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:heading {&quot;level&quot;:3} --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Encourage Them&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:heading --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try to be encouraging of your cat to come out and explore if it seems like they have been hiding a lot but be careful not to make them feel like they are being pulled out of their new hiding spots, especially while they are still trusting the new place.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {&quot;id&quot;:9907,&quot;sizeSlug&quot;:&quot;large&quot;,&quot;linkDestination&quot;:&quot;none&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;livingat300main.ca&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2022&#x2F;05&#x2F;pexels-tomas-ryant-2870489-1-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cat sleeping on a mat&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9907&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:image --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you noticed they don&#x27;t seem to be coming out very much, try persuading them with some play and treats, and they should start warming up to the new place in no time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving can be stressful, but it doesn&#x27;t have to be. With a little bit of planning, you will feel ready when the day comes, and the transition will go as easy as you make it for you and your cat. It may take your fur friend time to warm up, come out and get back to normal, but don&#x27;t worry, your cat will feel right at home, which probably means acting like &lt;em&gt;they&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; own the place in no time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#x2F;wp:paragraph --&gt;</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
